//DIABLO II

//Act III: The Infernal Gate

//SECTION:GREETINGS

//Ormus Greetings
//act3\ormus\orm_hello.wav
//"Hello."
//act3\ormus\orm_greetings.wav
//"Greetings."
//act3\ormus\orm_yes.wav
//"Yes?"
//act3\ormus\orm_goodmorning.wav
//"Good morning."
//act3\ormus\orm_goodday.wav
//"Good day."
//act3\ormus\orm_goodevening.wav
//"Good evening."
//act3\ormus\orm_goodtoseeyouagain.wav
//"Good to see you again."

//Asheara Greetings
//act3\asheara\ash_hello.wav
//"Hello."
//act3\asheara\ash_greetings.wav
//"Greetings."
//act3\asheara\ash_whatdoyouneed.wav
//"What do you need?"
//act3\asheara\ash_whatcanidoforyou.wav
//"What can I do for you?"
//act3\asheara\ash_goodmorning.wav
//"Good morning."
//act3\asheara\ash_goodday.wav
//"Good day."
//act3\asheara\ash_goodevening.wav
//"Good evening."
//act3\asheara\ash_imsurprised.wav
//"I'm surprised you made it back all in one piece. Most mortals who come back from Hell are usually dead...
//or undead as it turns out."

//Hratli Greetings
//act3\hratli\hra_hello.wav
//"Hello."
//act3\hratli\hra_greetings.wav
//"Greetings."
//act3\hratli\hra_yes.wav
//"Yes?"
//act3\hratli\hra_goodmorning.wav
//"Good morning."
//act3\hratli\hra_goodday.wav
//"Good day."
//act3\hratli\hra_goodevening.wav
//"Good evening."
//act3\hratli\hra_returngreeting.wav
//"Truth be told, I didn't expect to see you again. Did you happen to see any magical weapons in Hell?"

//Alkor Greetings
//act3\alkor\alk_hello.wav
//"Hello."
//act3\alkor\alk_greetings.wav
//"Greetings."
//act3\alkor\alk_whatdoyouneed.wav
//"What do you need?"
//act3\alkor\alk_whatcanidoforyou.wav
//"What can I do for you?"
//act3\alkor\alk_goodmorning.wav
//"Good morning."
//act3\alkor\alk_goodday.wav
//"Good day."
//act3\alkor\alk_goodevening.wav
//"Good evening."
//act3\alkor\alk_goodtoseeyouagain.wav
//"Good to see you again."

//Meshif Greetings
//common\meshif\mes_hello.wav
//"Hello."
//common\meshif\mes_ahoymate.wav
//"Ahoy, mate."
//common\meshif\mes_myshipyourship.wav
//"My ship is your ship."
//common\meshif\mes_goodtoseeyou.wav
//"Yes?"
//common\meshif\mes_goodmorning.wav
//"Good morning."
//common\meshif\mes_goodday.wav
//"Good day."
//common\meshif\mes_goodevening.wav
//"Good evening."
//common\meshif\mes_thankfuldontcharge.wav
//"You should be thankful that I don't charge you for ferrying you across the sea."

//Natalya Greetings
//act3\natalya\nat_hello.wav
//"Hello."
//act3\natalya\nat_greetings.wav
//"Greetings."
//act3\natalya\nat_yes.wav
//"Yes?"
//act3\natalya\nat_goodmorning.wav
//"Good morning."
//act3\natalya\nat_goodday.wav
//"Good day."
//act3\natalya\nat_goodevening.wav
//"Good evening."
//act3\natalya\nat_goodtoseeyouagain.wav
//"Good to see you again."
//Unneeded! She has departed to Act V!

//Iron Wolf Hireable Acknowledgements
//act3\ironwolf\iron_asyoucommand1.wav
//"As you command!"
//act3\ironwolf\iron_asyoucommand2.wav
//"As you command!"
//act3\ironwolf\iron_immediately.wav
//"Immediately."
//act3\ironwolf\iron_yes.wav
//"Yes!"
//act3\ironwolf\iron_yes2.wav
//"Yes!"
//act3\ironwolf\iron_willdo1.wav
//"Will do."
//act3\ironwolf\iron_willdo2.wav
//"Will do."
//act3\ironwolf\iron_done.wav
//"Done."

//Iron Wolf Hireable Get Hits and Death sfx
//"Uhnn!"
//"Arrrghh.."

//Mephisto's taunts for Quest 3.6
//act3\monster\mephistotaunt1.wav
//"My brothers have escaped you."
//act3\monster\mephistotaunt2.wav 
//"You're too late, ha ha ha ha ha ha"

//Mephisto Attacks, Get Hits, and Death
//"Uhnn!"
//"Arrrghh.."


SECTION:GOSSIP

//Natalya is 'waiting' to receive orders to go after Baal in the beginning. She (or her superiors) won't know that Baal (Tal Rasha ) is still in the world until the end of this Act.

NAME:NatalyaIntro
SPEED:48
wave:act3\natalya\nat_act3_intro.wav
"Greetings, hero. I've heard of your exploits and… I'm quite impressed. Very few mortals are capable of dealing with the Three and their minions as you have.
 
My name is Natalya. I am a hunter of Evil, part of an ancient Order sworn to hunt down corrupted sorcerers.
 
If I could, I would gladly join your quest to stop the Three. But I must wait here for further news. I can't predict what will happen, but the danger is greater than we can know.
 
Until I receive my orders, I'll assist you with the information I have."

NAME:Natalya
SPEED:74
wave:act3\natalya\nat_act3_gossip01.wav 
"Asheara…? Oh, she's is a tough-talking mage, but I'd wager she's never faced true Evil.
 
Pampering drunken mercenaries is one thing, but standing face to face with a hell-spawned demon is another."

SPEED:69
wave:act3\natalya\nat_act3_gossip02.wav 
"I've heard the name of Deckard Cain many times. He's the last of the Horadrim, and thus, I must honor him. You must be powerful, indeed, if one such as he accompanies you."

SPEED:100
wave:act3\natalya\nat_act3_gossip03.wav 
"Hratli is a master craftsman. My Order could make use of one with his unique skills."

SPEED:67
wave:act3\natalya\nat_act3_gossip04.wav 
"My Order has been keeping watch over Ormus for many years, now. He seems to champion the cause of good, but who knows what shadow lurks within his soul?"

NAME:CainAct3Intro
SPEED:45
wave:act3\cain\cain_act3_intro.wav 
"I've not set foot in glorious Kurast for many years. But I never would have imagined it could be so corrupted.
 
Certainly, this must be Mephisto's work! You'd best get going, my friend. Diablo and Baal are still out there and you must find them."

NAME:CainAct3
SPEED:62
wave:act3\cain\cain_act3_gossip_01.wav 
"Seeing his homeland in such a state must be horrifying to Meshif. I'm surprised he's willing to remain here in order to help you."

SPEED:82
wave:act3\cain\cain_act3_gossip_02.wav 
"Asheara seems like a very tough woman. I'd be careful around her if I were you."

SPEED:53
wave:act3\cain\cain_act3_gossip_03.wav 
"Drognan told me of Hratli when we were in Lut Gholein. He said that he weaves magic into his forge and produces mystical weapons and armor.
 
His skills could be quite useful to you. "

SPEED:44
wave:act3\cain\cain_act3_gossip_04.wav 
"Judging from his dress and strange markings, I would guess that Ormus is from the ancient Taan mage-clan. Yet none of the others here seem to know that he is a sorcerer.
 
The Taan were once as powerful as the Vizjerei clan, but their studies were even more secretive. I wonder what he's hiding." 

SPEED:49
wave:act3\cain\cain_act3_gossip_05.wav 
"Have you met, Natalya? She appears to be a member of the Khral-Harzhek, a secret order that has been around for centuries… almost as long as the Horadrim, itself.
 
Her presence here makes me uneasy, for they are traditionally sworn to hunt down Magi who have betrayed the trust of their order.
 
I wonder why she is here."

SPEED:73
wave:act3\cain\cain_act3_gossip_06.wav
"Ormus would like you to think him mad. Better to watch his actions than listen to his words."

NAME:HratliActIntro
//changed 2/23/00
SPEED:33
wave:act3\hratli\hra_act3_intro.wav
"Welcome to Kurast, traveler. Few come willingly to this ancient city anymore. I hope you brought your wits with you, for sanity is in short supply here.
 
My name is Hratli. I am a sorcerer skilled in metal work. It'd be a pleasure to help you… I don't have many customers these days.
 
As you can see, the populace has been brutally decimated by the forces of Mephisto. The canals run red with blood and demons roam the land.
 
The wretched jungle-hell has already reclaimed much of Kurast. The only safety you'll find is here at the dockside, where a magical warding holds the jungle evils at bay… but I don't know how long it will last.
 
To make matters worse, the Children of Zakarum are in league with the forces of Mephisto. The Zakarum have concentrated their power in the Temple City of Travincal, located within Kurast deep in the jungle wilderness.
 
It's true… Their zeal is unmatched. But I say the so-called 'Warriors of Light' are nothing more than the twisted puppets of a hidden hand."

NAME:HratliActIntroSor
//changed 2/23/00
SPEED:33
wave:act3\hratli\hra_act3_intro_sor.wav 
"Welcome to Kurast, young Sorceress. Few come willingly to this ancient city anymore. I hope you brought your wits with you, for sanity is in short supply here.
 
My name is Hratli. I am a sorcerer skilled in metal work. It'd be a pleasure to help you… I don't have many customers these days.
 
Though my own magic is only useful for making enchanted weapons, I'll bet yours will put an end to this terrible evil once and for all. May the spirits of Skatsim watch over and protect you.
 
As you can see, the populace has been brutally decimated by the forces of Mephisto. The canals run red with blood and demons roam the land.
 
The wretched jungle-hell has already reclaimed much of Kurast. The only safety you'll find is here at the dockside, where a magical warding holds the jungle evils at bay… but I don't know how long it will last.
 
To make matters worse, the Children of Zakarum are in league with the forces of Mephisto. The Zakarum have concentrated their power in the Temple City of Travincal, located within Kurast deep in the jungle wilderness.
 
It's true… Their zeal is unmatched. But I say the so-called 'Warriors of Light' are nothing more than the twisted puppets of a hidden hand."

NAME:Hratli
//The next gossip is only for a Sorceress.
SPEED:48
wave:act3\hratli\hra_act3_gossip_sor.wav 
"You're very brave to have come here. In the old days, mages who didn't belong to one of the great Mage Clans were hunted down as renegades. But now, the Mage Clans have little authority."

<Q5
SPEED:53
wave:act3\hratli\hra_act3_gossip_01.wav 
"Within the Temple City stands a tower built long ago by the Horadrim to imprison the… Well, you'll discover more about it soon enough."

SPEED:60
wave:act3\hratli\hra_act3_gossip_02.wav 
"If you are another follower of Zakarum, I've told you people before I don't want your Towering Spire or anything else you have to sell!"

SPEED:74
wave:act3\hratli\hra_act3_gossip_03.wav 
"Some find my prices unreasonable. That is because I am unreasonable." 

SPEED:76
wave:act3\hratli\hra_act3_gossip_04.wav 
"You'll find that the Zakarumites have the persistence of zombies, but without the charisma."
 
SPEED:60
wave:act3\hratli\hra_act3_gossip_05.wav 
"Asheara leads the mercenary company known as the Iron Wolves. You can hire some of them, but many are occupied securing the dockside."
 
SPEED:74
wave:act3\hratli\hra_act3_gossip_06.wav 
"Alkor is a potion dealer given over to a life steeped in ceaseless study and dissipation."

SPEED:58
wave:act3\hratli\hra_act3_gossip_07.wav 
"Ormus is a man of many mysteries. I sense strong magic about him, but he's never spoken of it to me."

SPEED:49
wave:act3\hratli\hra_act3_gossip_08.wav 
"I trust you already know Meshif. But did you know that he was born and raised here?
 
I suspect that like many of us his spirit is near broken at the sight of Kurast's decline. Only our brand of gallows humor saves us from utter despair."
 
SPEED:55
wave:act3\hratli\hra_act3_gossip_09.wav 
"This, Cain, whom you brought with you. He has the bearing of great power, yet I sense no magic about him. He is an enigma to me."

SPEED:49
wave:act3\hratli\hra_act3_gossip_10.wav
"Natalya is a quiet one. She arrived here about a week ago and has pretty much kept to herself. She's inquired about my weapons a few times, so I assume that she's a warrior of some sort."

NAME:MeshifAct3Intro
SPEED:51
wave:act3\meshif\mes_act3_intro.wav 
"Well, I gave you my word, and brought you here as promised.
 
But by all that's still holy, I wish I'd never returned to this accursed place. This fetid jungle can't be the fair Kurast I left behind.
 
I don't know what all this evil is, my friend, but it's obvious that you must stop it. I only pray that you can before the jungle consumes the last vestiges of my beloved homeland."

NAME:MeshifAct3IntroBar
//changed 2/23/00
SPEED:47
wave:act3\meshif\mes_act3_intro_bar.wav 
"Being a Barbarian, I'm sure you've seen many strange sights in the northlands.
 
But by all that's still holy, I wish I'd never returned to this accursed place. This fetid jungle can't be the fair Kurast I left behind!
 
I don't know what all this evil is, my friend, but it's obvious that you must stop it. I only pray that you can before the jungle consumes the last vestiges of my beloved homeland.
 
If this evil isn't contained, it could spread north to your homeland, too. Then the whole world would fall under the shadow of the Three."

NAME:MeshifAct3
//The next gossip is only for a Barbarian.
SPEED:63
wave:act3\meshif\mes_act3_gossip_bar.wav 
"It takes great courage and generosity to defend a land and a people that are not your own. Perhaps, when this curse is lifted, my people can do something for yours in return." 

SPEED:72
wave:act3\meshif\mes_act3_gossip_01.wav 
"I shouldn't have boasted so much about Kurast on the journey here. Oh… Much has changed since I left."

SPEED:99
wave:act3\meshif\mes_act3_gossip_02.wav 
"The dockside is apparently the only civilized area left in Kurast."

SPEED:88
wave:act3\meshif\mes_act3_gossip_03.wav 
"If you are planning to carry on your wild ways here, you may need the assistance of Asheara's Iron Wolf mercenaries."

SPEED:75
wave:act3\meshif\mes_act3_gossip_04.wav 
"Your companion, Cain, must have known that he would be in grave danger here. You are great, indeed, to elicit such loyalty." 

SPEED:81
wave:act3\meshif\mes_act3_gossip_05.wav
"Hratli seems to be the only one left here with any common sense. Yet how sensible is it to remain here?"

SPEED:80
wave:act3\meshif\mes_act3_gossip_06.wav 
"I went to speak with old Alkor, but I disturbed his studies. He doesn't seem to like visitors."

SPEED:73
wave:act3\meshif\mes_act3_gossip_07.wav 
"Trying to get information out of Ormus is like straining water from a rock. His damned riddles are almost as confusing as our current state of affairs."

SPEED:75
wave:act3\meshif\mes_act3_gossip_08.wav 
"That woman, Natalya, seems to be waiting for something important to happen. She's a strange one, I think."

SPEED:68
wave:act3\meshif\mes_act3_gossip_09.wav 
"All through my childhood, Kurast was a paradise. The once perfumed air now reeks of putrefaction."

NAME:AshearaIntro
SPEED:54
wave:act3\asheara\ash_act3_intro.wav 
"Hello, there. You must be a great adventurer to risk coming here.
 
My name's Asheara, and I lead the mercenary band of mages known as the Iron Wolves. We've been hunting down demons in the jungle for months, but no matter how many of them we kill, they just keep comin'. Seems this whole place has been overrun by evil.
 
Rumor has it that you've come here to help. If that's true, then I'll let you hire some of my mercenaries.
 
But be careful… If you piss them off, they can be worse than those monsters out in the jungle."

NAME:AshearaIntroAma
SPEED:50
wave:act3\asheara\ash_act3_intro_ama.wav 
"Hello, there. You must be an Amazon. I've heard about your people… nomadic warriors without peer.
 
My name's Asheara, and I lead the mercenary band of mages known as the Iron Wolves. We've been hunting down demons in the jungle for months, but no matter how many of them we kill, they just keep comin'. Seems this whole place has been overrun by evil.
 
Rumor has it that you've come here to help. If that's true, then I'll let you hire some of my mercenaries.
 
But be careful… If you piss them off, they can be worse than those monsters out in the jungle."

NAME:Asheara
//The next gossip is only for an Amazon.
SPEED:66
wave:act3\asheara\ash_act3_gossip_ama.wav 
"Your skills are unique indeed. They are neither sorcery, nor physical, but seem to be a harmonious blend of the two. The Iron Wolves could learn much from your kind."

SPEED:160
wave:act3\asheara\ash_act3_gossip_01.wav
"Why fight fair, when you can hire some of us?"

SPEED:107
wave:act3\asheara\ash_act3_gossip_02.wav
"No one comes to Kurast anymore without good reason.  You must be seeking fame and fortune."

SPEED:137
wave:act3\asheara\ash_act3_gossip_03.wav
"The Iron Wolves and I have made a good living around here lately."

SPEED:110
wave:act3\asheara\ash_act3_gossip_04.wav
"The jungle can take you down fast. Try to avoid getting trapped out there if you can."

SPEED:90
wave:act3\asheara\ash_act3_gossip_05.wav
"Hratli may be a bit too clever for his own good. Still, I'd trust his work anytime."

SPEED:77
wave:act3\asheara\ash_act3_gossip_06.wav
"Hratli thinks he's so funny. The other day he said, 'Asheara, I don't recognize you without that big gash on your face.'"

SPEED:97
wave:act3\asheara\ash_act3_gossip_07.wav 
"Meshif says he used to live here. I'm surprised he came back. I'll bet he wishes he hadn't."

SPEED:78
wave:act3\asheara\ash_act3_gossip_08.wav 
"I invited Natalya to join the Iron Wolves and she began lecturing me about the 'dangers of magic'. Who the hell does she think she is, anyway?"

NAME:AlkorIntro
SPEED:61
wave:act3\alkor\alk_act3_intro.wav 
"Damn it, I wish you people would just leave me alone! I…
 
Oh, you're new here, aren't you?
 
I am Alkor, the Alchemist. I dabble in potions and salves, and I can sell you some if you really need them.
 
But don't make a habit of coming here. I don't like to be disturbed while I'm studying!"

NAME:AlkorIntroNec
SPEED:48
wave:act3\alkor\alk_act3_intro_nec.wav 
"Damn it, I wish you people would just leave me alone! I…
 
Oh, you're a Necromancer, aren't you? I've heard that your kind use powerful potions and such to wake the dead and control spirits. I'd love to discuss what components you use some time.
 
I am Alkor, the Alchemist. I dabble in potions and salves, myself, and I can sell you some if you really need them.
 
…Feel free to drop by anytime."

NAME:Alkor
//The next gossip is only for a Necromancer.
SPEED:55
wave:act3\alkor\alk_act3_gossip_nec.wav 
"Even I can tell that the evil in the jungle is growing. I hope you survive out there, my pasty friend. I'd still like to discuss what components are best used in necromantic potions." 

SPEED:151
wave:act3\alkor\alk_act3_gossip_01.wav
"Care to take a gander at my Grimoire?"

SPEED:90
wave:act3\alkor\alk_act3_gossip_02.wav
"I've never claimed that you'd live forever after trying one of my potions! Merely that you might look as though you had."

SPEED:105
wave:act3\alkor\alk_act3_gossip_03.wav
"I keep a library of tomes - heretical, exegetical, hermeneutical and pharmaceutical."

//Removed from game
SPEED:50
wave:act3\alkor\alk_act3_gossip_04.wav
"There was a very fat man here recently asking after the Golden Bird of Ku Y'Leh. Have you heard of it? He kept muttering about ashes. I would imagine one Golden Bird's ash-hole to be about the same as another, wouldn't you?"

SPEED:150
wave:act3\alkor\alk_act3_gossip_05.wav
"I hope you don't object to my badgering the witless."

SPEED:115
wave:act3\alkor\alk_act3_gossip_06.wav 
"You came here with Meshif? That old 'tour-guide to the stupid'!
 
I'm surprised you made it here in one piece."

SPEED:98
wave:act3\alkor\alk_act3_gossip_07.wav 
 "Oh, Asheara's a good customer. She buys a potion of manliness from me every week."

SPEED:82
wave:act3\alkor\alk_act3_gossip_08.wav 
"Hratli's only good for making his silly magic weapons. It's not like he's got the stones to actually go out and use them on anything."

SPEED:88
wave:act3\alkor\alk_act3_gossip_09.wav 
"Oh, Ormus has been talking in riddles for years. I think he does it to cover up the fact that he's got nothing intelligent to say." 

SPEED:52
wave:act3\alkor\alk_act3_gossip_10.wav 
"Yes, Natalya is a cute girl. However, I think she could use a special potion.
 
Let me see here, 'Radiant Beauty'… No. 'Ray of Sunshine'… No, that's not it.
 
Ah, here it is: 'Relax Frosty Bitch'. This should help her out."

NAME:OrmusIntro
SPEED:38
wave:act3\ormus\orm_act3_intro.wav 
"You now speak to Ormus.
 
He was once a great mage, but now lives like a rat in a sinking vessel. You have questions for Ormus and doubt in yourself. Ormus sees a strange dichotomy in you… as he does in all would-be heroes.
 
Speak to him and he may grant you wisdom in turn. Or turn from him and seek wisdom in thyself."

NAME:OrmusIntroPal
SPEED:37
wave:act3\ormus\orm_act3_intro_pal.wav 
"You now speak to Ormus, good Paladin.
 
He was once a great mage, but now lives like a rat in a sinking vessel. You have questions for Ormus and doubt in yourself. Ormus sees a strange dichotomy in you… as he does in all would-be heroes.
 
Speak to him and he may grant you wisdom in turn. Or turn from him and seek wisdom in thyself."

NAME:Ormus
//The next gossip is only for a Paladin.
SPEED:68
wave:act3\ormus\orm_act3_gossip_pal.wav 
"The Church which you serve is corrupted by evil. Yet the holy disciplines it taught you may yet save us all.
 
This is a strange time for heroes, Ormus thinks." 

SPEED:65
wave:act3\ormus\orm_act3_gossip_01.wav 
"Your salvation can only be reached through Hatred. A strange fate, but a true one."

SPEED:52
wave:act3\ormus\orm_act3_gossip_02.wav 
"How does one destroy Destruction? How does one force Terror to flee in fear? You have great tasks ahead of you, Ormus thinks."

SPEED:72
wave:act3\ormus\orm_act3_gossip_03.wav 
"The Church of Light harbors the darkest shadow of all. Tread lightly."  

SPEED:89
wave:act3\ormus\orm_act3_gossip_04.wav
"When speaking of the dead, it is best to remain cryptic."

SPEED:84
wave:act3\ormus\orm_act3_gossip_05.wav
"The Travincal can be breached by the loss of one's wits, not by the use of them."

SPEED:95
wave:act3\ormus\orm_act3_gossip_06.wav
"Alkor is able to explain things much more clearly than Ormus."

SPEED:58
wave:act3\ormus\orm_act3_gossip_07.wav 
"For one who spends so much time away from home, Meshif has taken Kurast's corruption the hardest."

SPEED:91
wave:act3\ormus\orm_act3_gossip_08.wav 
"Asheara is both proud and self-conscious of her womanhood."

SPEED:65
wave:act3\ormus\orm_act3_gossip_09.wav 
"Deckard Cain… Ormus has no time for the last son of the Horadrim. Pride led that holy Order to failure."

SPEED:63
wave:act3\ormus\orm_act3_gossip_10.wav 
"Hratli suspects that Ormus is a mage. He can suspect whatever he wants, Ormus will not show him the true magic."


SECTION:QUEST

//Quest 3.4 The Golden Bird
QUEST:A3Q4

// Initialized by picking up the Jade Figurine. Quest Log says "Ask Cain about the Jade Figurine."
STATE:Init1
NAME:CainAct3
SPEED:53
wave:act3\cain\cain_act3_q1_early_act3.wav
"Back in Lut Gholein Meshif told me he had a fondness for jade figurines. On his trading voyages he collected an odd assortment of such small statues.
 
I would show him your figurine. "

NAME:Asheara
SPEED:160
wave:act3\asheara\ash_act3_q1_early.wav 
"Only Deckard Cain can make sense of this."

//Quest Log says "Show Meshif the Figurine."
STATE:Init2
SPEED:73
NAME:MeshifAct3
wave:act3\meshif\mes_act3_q1_early.wav
"Praise you! That jade figurine will complete the set I was collecting.
 
Here! I've had this statuette of a golden bird for years, but I consider it a fair exchange."

NAME:Natalya
SPEED:89
wave:act3\natalya\nat_act3_q1_early.wav 
"I'm having fun just watching you run from place to place searching for a Golden Bird. Some hero you are."

//Quest Log says "Give the Golden Bird to Alkor."
STATE:Init3
NAME:CainAct3
SPEED:47
wave:act3\cain\cain_act3_q1_after.wav 
"I've read legends about a sage named Ku Y'leh, who studied the mysteries of life beyond death.
 
If I remember correctly, his ashes were ensconced within a golden statuette. It was a very strange tale."

NAME:Hratli
SPEED:134
wave:act3\hratli\hra_act3_q1_successful.wav 
"You will have to take Ku Y'leh's ashes to Alkor."

NAME:Asheara
SPEED:96
wave:act3\asheara\ash_act3_q1_successful.wav 
"Such a beautiful statuette… But, you'd think it would've been better cared for. There's a compartment here that's full o' dust."

STATE:AfterInit
NAME:Alkor
SPEED:73
wave:act3\alkor\alk_act3_q1_successful.wav 
"Ah, the Golden Bird of Ku Y'leh.  Thank you, my friend. 
 
Busy yourself while I experiment with the ashes within it. Then, return and see what I have made for you."

NAME:Ormus
SPEED:51
wave:act3\ormus\orm_act3_q1_after.wav 
"Ku Y'leh, in searching for immortal youth, found only an early death. His apprentices, seeking to live forever, burned his body in order to derive benefit from his ashes."

NAME:Hratli
SPEED:50
wave:act3\hratli\hra_act3_q1_after.wav
"Ku Y'leh was a powerful sage who was rumored to have brewed a potion of immortality. In an ironic twist of fate, he was murdered before his potent elixir could take effect."

NAME:Natalya
SPEED:78
wave:act3\natalya\nat_act3_q1_after.wav 
"Don't tell me you believe in all of that 'life after death' nonsense. You should be more concerned with avoiding death than making plans for after it finds you."  

STATE:Successful

NAME:Alkor
SPEED:120
wave:act3\alkor\alk_act3_q1_successful_reward.wav
"From the ashes of Ku Y'leh I have mixed for you a potion."

NAME:MeshifAct3
SPEED:94
wave:act3\meshif\mes_act3_q1_after.wav
"Immortality is definitely not for me.
 
Can you imagine having to wake up every night just to piss for the next thousand years?"

NAME:CainAct3
SPEED:63
wave:act3\cain\cain_act3_q1_successful.wav
"So, Meshif had the Golden Bird all along. I wonder if he knows what he gave up for that jade figurine."

NAME:Ormus
SPEED:54
wave:act3\ormus\orm_act3_q1_early.wav 
"Ormus remembers the tale of Ku Y'leh. That venerable sage forgot that there is no life beyond death. There is only life.
 
Once prolonged unnaturally, it can become a living hell."

NAME:Natalya
SPEED:67
wave:act3\natalya\nat_act3_q1_successful.wav 
"I must admit, your foolish quest made little sense to me. But now I see the value of your actions. I believe you do possess great wisdom."

//changed 2/24/00
//the following quest lines were added to replace the quese "Beneath the City"
//QUEST 3.2 Khalim's Will
QUEST:A3Q2
//enabled by completing "The Golden Bird" or by finding one of Khalim's relics.

STATE:Init 
NAME:Cain
SPEED:33
wave:act3\cain\cain_act3_q2A_init.wav 
"Never forget that your ultimate purpose here in Kurast is to destroy Mephisto. The ancient Horadrim imprisoned the Lord of Hatred inside the Guardian Tower that is located within the Temple City of Travincal.
 
Know this, friend. The only way to gain entry to Mephisto's prison is to destroy the artifact known as the Compelling Orb.
 
Mephisto used this device to control the Zakarum Priests and their followers. The Orb can only be destroyed with an ancient flail imbued with the spirit of the one incorruptible priest.
 
Soon after his imprisonment, Mephisto worked his evil corruption on the Zakarum priesthood. All were turned to his dark ways, save one - Khalim, the Que-Hegan of the High Council.
 
Mephisto directed the other Council priests to slay and dismember Khalim and then scatter his remains across the Kingdom. The Priest Sankekur succeeded Khalim as Que-Hegan, eventually becoming the embodiment of Mephisto here on the mortal plane.
 
The corrupted High Council fashioned an Orb to control the rest of the Zakarum faithful and used their powers to hide the lair of their master from mortals.
 
Your task is to collect the scattered relics of Khalim - his Heart, his Brain, and his Eye. Then, using the Horadric Cube, transmute Khalim's Flail with his relics.
 
Once this is accomplished, you must destroy the Compelling Orb with Khalim's Will to open the way into the corrupt sanctum of Mephisto."

//STATE:AfterInit

STATE:EarlyReturnHeart
NAME:Cain
SPEED:61
wave:act3\cain\cain_act3_q2A_earlyheart.wav 
"You have found Khalim's Heart, and it still bears the courage to face Mephisto!
 
Place it in the Horadric Cube along with Khalim's other relics - the Eye, the Brain, and the Flail."

STATE:EarlyReturnEye
NAME:Cain 
SPEED:52
wave:act3\cain\cain_act3_q2A_earlyeye.wav 
"Ahh… Khalim's Eye! Only it can reveal the true path to Mephisto.
 
Place the Eye in the Horadric Cube along with Khalim's other relics - the Heart, the Brain, and the Flail."

STATE:EarlyReturnBrain
NAME:Cain
SPEED:58
wave:act3\cain\cain_act3_q2A_earlybrain.wav 
"This is most fortunate! Khalim's Brain knows Mephisto's weakness.
 
Place it in the Horadric Cube along with Khalim's other relics - the Eye, the Heart, and the Flail."

STATE:EarlyReturnFlail
NAME:Cain
SPEED:46
wave:act3\cain\cain_act3_q2A_earlyflail.wav 
"Once properly imbued, Khalim's Flail can destroy the Compelling Orb and reveal the way to Mephisto.
 
Place it into the Horadric Cube along with Khalim's relics - his Heart, his Brain, and his Eye. Then, transmute them to carry out Khalim's Will."

STATE:Successful
NAME:Cain
SPEED:54
wave:act3\cain\cain_act3_q2A_successful.wav 
"Masterfully done, hero! You have crafted Khalim's Will. Employ it to destroy the Compelling Orb and open the way to Mephisto. 
 
May the true Light guide your way."

//NOTE: The lines in quests 3.5 and 3.6 marked …VA are Vague Alternatives that are used until Quest 3.1 is satisfied.

//Quest 3.1 Lam Esen's Tome
QUEST:A3Q1
STATE:Init

NAME:Alkor
SPEED:56
wave:act3\alkor\alk_act3_q3_init.wav 
"It pains me to waste time with you, so I'll get right to the point.
 
There is a very special book which you must find for me. It was written long ago by a sage known as Lam Esen, who studied Skatsimi magic and the effects of the Prime Evils on the mortal world. The Black Book was lost when the Children of Zakarum took over this land.
 
Now, you must reclaim it without delay! Its knowledge may aid us in this dark time ahead." 

STATE:AfterInit

NAME:Alkor
SPEED:73
wave:act3\alkor\alk_act3_q3_after.wav 
"The Black Book contains powerful secrets of Skatsim, the Old Religion, long eclipsed by Zakarum.
 
I should warn you. The Black Book is much sought after by both good and evil. Be wary."

NAME:Ormus
SPEED:62
wave:act3\ormus\orm_act3_q3_after.wav 
"The Children of Zakarum believe that the Black Book is filled with blasphemous heresy. In truth, the book may contain the secrets to our ultimate redemption."

NAME:MeshifAct3
SPEED:73
wave:act3\meshif\mes_act3_q3_after.wav 
"Oh. No one really believes that the Black Book exists. It's just a symbol of Zakarum's anti-Skatsim propaganda."

NAME:Asheara
SPEED:102
wave:act3\asheara\ash_act3_q3_after.wav 
"Many things can be found in the city of Kurast. The book may be there."

NAME:Hratli
SPEED:54
wave:act3\hratli\hra_act3_q3_after.wav
"We have long sought the Black Book of Lam Esen. Rumors of its whereabouts spread as fast as jungle plagues. If you find it, take it to Alkor."

NAME:CainAct3
SPEED:72
wave:act3\cain\cain_act3_q3_after.wav 
"The Black Book is a powerful source of information. The Zakarum will do everything in their power to stop you from obtaining it."

NAME:Natalya
SPEED:81
wave:act3\natalya\nat_act3_q3_after.wav 
"I've heard of the Black Book. My Order's code is based on many of its passages. If you find it, I will be greatly impressed."

STATE:EarlyReturn

NAME:Alkor
SPEED:104
wave:act3\alkor\alk_act3_q3_early.wav 
"Did I neglect to mention that the book contains useful information about the Prime Evils?"

NAME:Ormus
SPEED:55
wave:act3\ormus\orm_act3_q3_early.wav 
"Even if you find the sacred Book, you must still traverse the jungle of meaning within it. That journey could prove to be far more perilous."

NAME:MeshifAct3
SPEED:56
wave:act3\meshif\mes_act3_q3_early.wav
"Kurast was once the greatest city in the world. Now it is hard to tell where the jungle stops and the city begins. The jungle grows rampant on the soil enriched by the blood of my fellow citizens."

NAME:Asheara
SPEED:68
wave:act3\asheara\ash_act3_q3_early.wav 
"I believe I can trust you now.
 
When you first arrived, I suspected you a spy for the Zakarum, the false religion whose faithful are now under the sway of a mysterious power. They've made a mockery of the Old Religion of Skatsim."
 
NAME:Hratli
SPEED:62
wave:act3\hratli\hra_act3_q3_early.wav
"Not getting much help?
 
You know, people are like rugs. Hang them out a window and shake 'em a couple times. You'll be surprised how much dirt comes out."

NAME:CainAct3
SPEED:81
wave:act3\cain\cain_act3_q3_early.wav 
"I heard that there are ruined temples in Kurast. Perhaps you will find the Black Book in one of them."

NAME:Natalya
SPEED:105
wave:act3\natalya\nat_act3_q3_early.wav
"I hope you find the Black Book soon. I could use something to read while I wait for my orders."

STATE:Successful

NAME:Alkor
//changed 2/23/00
SPEED:83
wave:act3\alkor\alk_act3_q3_successful.wav 
"You have found the Book! It should give all of us here some insight into the nature of the Prime Evils…
 
Ah, but as for you…"

NAME:Ormus
SPEED:70
wave:act3\ormus\orm_act3_q3_successful.wav 
"Why is the Black Book of Lam Esen like a coffin? Simple. Each holds the shape of our future."

NAME:MeshifAct3
SPEED:75
wave:act3\meshif\mes_act3_q3_successful.wav 
"Thank all that's holy. You've returned with the Black Book! Maybe now you can put an end to the Evil that has destroyed my homeland."

NAME:Asheara
SPEED:135
wave:act3\asheara\ash_act3_q3_successful.wav 
"The Iron Wolves are very impressed by your skills."

NAME:Hratli
SPEED:74
wave:act3\hratli\hra_act3_q3_successful.wav
"We have the Book. Now we must see if we can bear its revelations."

NAME:CainAct3
SPEED:86
wave:act3\cain\cain_act3_q3_successful.wav 
"You have found a source of information powerful enough to turn the tide against the Zakarum."

NAME:Natalya
SPEED:89
wave:act3\natalya\nat_act3_q3_successful.wav 
"So, you've returned with the Book. You surprise me. You must be very resourceful." 

//Quest 3.3 Blade of the Old Religion
QUEST:A3Q3
STATE:Init

NAME:Hratli
SPEED:45
wave:act3\hratli\hra_act3_q4_init.wav 
"As I told you before, I placed an enchantment upon the dockside in order to keep the demons at bay. But lately, the enchantment seems to be weakening.
 
If memory serves me correctly, there is a holy Skatsimi blade that could revitalize the enchantment. The blade is called the Gidbinn.
 
Find it, and our sanctuary here will remain safe."

STATE:AfterInit

NAME:Alkor
SPEED:66
wave:act3\alkor\alk_act3_q4_after.wav 
"Have you not heard of the Gidbinn? Well, allow me to reduce your ignorance on the subject.
 
The Gidbinn is an enchanted dagger - a religious artifact greatly valued by the Old Religion, Skatsim."

NAME:Ormus
SPEED:64
wave:act3\ormus\orm_act3_q4_after.wav 
"Ormus is familiar with the Gidbinn. But how would a powerful Skatsimi artifact aid an unbeliever like you?"

NAME:MeshifAct3
SPEED:66
wave:act3\meshif\mes_act3_q4_after.wav
"The Gidbinn is one of the few remaining relics of Skatsim, the Old Religion. It is reputed to have great powers."

NAME:Asheara
SPEED:107
wave:act3\asheara\ash_act3_q4_after.wav 
"The Gidbinn will reinforce the enchantments that protect the dockside from the evil that infests Kurast."

NAME:Hratli
SPEED:54
wave:act3\hratli\hra_act3_q4_after.wav
"As far as we know, the Gidbinn is in the possession of the Children of Light. They do not wish it to fall into the hands of those who can restore its powers.
 
You may not believe it, but Ormus is the one who can use the Gidbinn to protect us."

NAME:CainAct3
SPEED:55
wave:act3\cain\cain_act3_q4_after.wav 
"I've done some research on the Taan mage-clan, and it seems that most of their magical studies were focused on Skatsimi rites.
 
If anyone is qualified to use the powers of the Gidbinn, it would be Ormus."

NAME:Natalya
SPEED:73
wave:act3\natalya\nat_act3_q4_after.wav 
"Don't let the Gidbinn's size fool you. Though it is only a small dagger, it holds tremendous power when in the hands of a true Skatsimi mage." 

STATE:EarlyReturn

NAME:Alkor
SPEED:70
wave:act3\alkor\alk_act3_q4_early.wav 
"Legend has it that the Skatsimi priests placed great power within the small blade. Power enough to repel this terrible jungle-curse which encroaches on our sanctuary."

NAME:Ormus
SPEED:83
wave:act3\ormus\orm_act3_q4_early.wav 
"If we are to have peace from the shadow, you must find the weapon which will destroy the Light."

NAME:MeshifAct3
SPEED:67
wave:act3\meshif\mes_act3_q4_early.wav
"The jungle is like nothing you've ever seen before. Imagine Paradise festering like a wound… then bursting!"

NAME:Asheara
SPEED:145
wave:act3\asheara\ash_act3_q4_early.wav 
"I'm certain that the Gidbinn is very closely guarded."

NAME:Hratli
SPEED:70
wave:act3\hratli\hra_act3_q4_early.wav 
"Once the Gidbinn is found, Ormus will use it to strengthen the protective barrier around the dockside."

NAME:CainAct3
SPEED:75
wave:act3\cain\cain_act3_q4_early.wav 
"Since you haven't come across the Gidbinn yet, the dagger must be deeper in the jungle nearer Kurast."

NAME:Natalya
SPEED:97
wave:act3\natalya\nat_act3_q4_early.wav 
"You'd best get back out there and find that blade. The jungle creeps further into this camp by the hour."

STATE:Successful

NAME:Alkor
SPEED:77
wave:act3\alkor\alk_act3_q4_successful.wav 
"Hah! You have stolen the fabled blade from right under Zakarum's nose! This is a great day, indeed!"

NAME:Ormus
//changed 2/24/00
SPEED:41
wave:act3\ormus\orm_act3_q4_successful.wav 
"You have done well, noble hero. Ormus congratulates you. The old spirits of Skatsim will watch over you for returning their sacred blade.
 
Now, after all these years, Ormus will once again use his powers to protect the innocent from the shadow. The spell that protects the dockside shall now be reinforced."
 
NAME:MeshifAct3
SPEED:79
wave:act3\meshif\mes_act3_q4_successful.wav 
"With any luck, the spirits of Skatsim will grant us revenge upon the powers that ravaged this land."

NAME:Asheara
SPEED:99
wave:act3\asheara\ash_act3_q4_successful.wav 
"Now that fewer of the Iron Wolves are needed to guard the dockside, some of them have volunteered to accompany you free of charge."

NAME:Hratli
SPEED:80
wave:act3\hratli\hra_act3_q4_successful.wav
"The Gidbinn's magic can only be channeled through Ormus.
 
Take it to him. He has the necessary knowledge about the ancient Skatsimi magics."

NAME:CainAct3
SPEED:62
wave:act3\cain\cain_act3_q4_successful.wav 
"Who could have foreseen that the Old Religion would play such an effective role in our war against the Three? Again, your efforts amaze me, my friend." 

NAME:Natalya
SPEED:67
wave:act3\natalya\nat_act3_q4_successful.wav 
"You are truly amazing, stranger. There are precious few items in the world that would tempt me to go up against the Children of Zakarum and their midget minions."

STATE:Reward
NAME:Ormus
//changed 2/24/00
SPEED:101
wave:act3\ormus\orm_act3_q4_successful_reward.wav
"This magic ring does me no good.
 
Here… Wear it proudly!"


//Quest 3.5 The Blackened Temple
QUEST:A3Q5
STATE:Init

NAME:Ormus
SPEED:36
wave:act3\ormus\orm_act3_q5_init.wav 
"You have done well, my friend. Your courage and valor are an inspiration to us all.
 
But now the time has come to face those responsible for the evil that has stifled our land. You must destroy the High Council of Zakarum!
 
Long ago, these elders were charged with the stewardship of Mephisto, the Lord of Hatred, who was imprisoned within the Guardian Tower.
 
Through the generations, these pious men slowly fell more and more under the sway of Mephisto's malevolent power and the Council became an evil mockery of its former glory. 
 
It is Mephisto's Hatred that has corrupted Zakarum and turned its devout followers into paranoid fanatics. That is why you must travel to the Temple City of Travincal and slay the Council.
 
Once they are gone, Mephisto's hold over this land and its people will be broken!"

STATE:AfterInit

NAME:Alkor
SPEED:84
wave:act3\alkor\alk_act3_q5_after.wav 
"The Black Book contains some vague prophecies regarding this undertaking. I'm not so sure it will turn out well for you."

NAME:AlkorVA
SPEED:90
wave:act3\alkor\alk_act3_q5_after_va.wav 
"I am but a potion dealer and an avid reader of occult books. What do I know of the Travincal?"

NAME:Ormus
SPEED:54
wave:act3\ormus\orm_act3_q5_after.wav 
"You must know that the Guardian Tower in the Temple City was built by the Horadrim for one purpose - to hold Mephisto. Once the Council is dead, you may enter the Tower."

NAME:OrmusVA
SPEED:54
wave:act3\ormus\orm_act3_q5_after.wav 
"You must know that the Guardian Tower in the Temple City was built by the Horadrim for one purpose -  to hold Mephisto. Once the Council is dead, you may enter the Tower."

NAME:MeshifAct3
SPEED:68
wave:act3\meshif\mes_act3_q5_after.wav
"There is only one way to the Temple City. You will have to cross many rivers and streams, but you'll find it. A great tower stands at its center."

NAME:MeshifAct3VA
SPEED:113
wave:act3\meshif\mes_act3_q5_after_va.wav
"It has been said that Ormus speaks most clearly when his ideas are utterly mad."

NAME:Asheara
SPEED:89
wave:act3\asheara\ash_act3_q5_after.wav 
"The Children of Zakarum who guard the Tower square can be killed, but their numbers are vast. You must destroy their Council."

NAME:AshearaVA
SPEED:105
wave:act3\asheara\ash_act3_q5_after_va.wav 
"There are many zealots among the followers of Zakarum. It will be difficult to get past them."

NAME:Hratli
SPEED:104
wave:act3\hratli\hra_act3_q5_after.wav 
"Remember. You can always find sanctuary here with us."

NAME:HratliVA
SPEED:75
wave:act3\hratli\hra_act3_q5_afterva.wav 
"This has been a trying time for all of us, but I sense this nightmare is coming to an end."

NAME:CainAct3
SPEED:63
wave:act3\cain\cain_act3_q5_after.wav 
"Ormus tells me that the Council is comprised of tremendously powerful priests. It will be difficult to best them."

NAME:CainAct3VA
SPEED:93
wave:act3\cain\cain_act3_q5_after_va.wav 
"The Temple City is well guarded. You'd best keep your wits about you."

NAME:Natalya
SPEED:100
wave:act3\natalya\nat_act3_q5_after.wav 
"You are incredibly brave to venture into the lion's den. I wish you luck."

NAME:NatalyaVA
SPEED:95
wave:act3\natalya\nat_act3_q5_after_va.wav 
"Beware the followers of Zakarum. Their fanaticism is their greatest weapon."

STATE:EarlyReturn
 
NAME:Alkor
SPEED:111
wave:act3\alkor\alk_act3_q5_early.wav 
"Kill as many as you can. I have a morbid love of excess."

NAME:AlkorVA
SPEED:91
wave:act3\alkor\alk_act3_q5_early_va.wav 
"If only we could have found the Black Book. I feel as though a malevolent hand has led us away from it."

NAME:Ormus
SPEED:49
wave:act3\ormus\orm_act3_q5_early.wav 
"If you die on this quest, I will commemorate your sacrifice in an epic poem. You will not need a potion to achieve immortality. Ormus' words will do that."

NAME:MeshifAct3
SPEED:110
wave:act3\meshif\mes_act3_q5_early.wav
"Within the Temple City is a courtyard. The Council resides there."

NAME:MeshifAct3VA
SPEED:107
wave:act3\meshif\mes_act3_q5_early_va.wav
"I have heard rumors that the Prime Evils are here seeking their Brother."

NAME:Asheara
SPEED:161
wave:act3\asheara\ash_act3_q5_early.wav 
"The Iron Wolves and I are at the ready to aid you."

NAME:AshearaVA
SPEED:139
wave:act3\asheara\ash_act3_q5_early_va.wav 
"Things are getting wilder than Ladies Night at the Slippery Fist."

NAME:Hratli
SPEED:65
wave:act3\hratli\hra_act3_q5_early.wav
"The followers of Zakarum demand complete allegiance to their creed. They have slaughtered many of their own for minor grievances.
 
They will not hesitate to kill you."

NAME:HratliVA
SPEED:75
wave:act3\hratli\hra_act3_q5_earlyva.wav 
"After having served Mephisto all these years, the Council must be twisted by hatred and evil."

NAME:CainAct3
SPEED:81
wave:act3\cain\cain_act3_q5_early.wav 
"Sankekur may be using a Compelling Orb to control the minds of the Children of Zakarum."

NAME:Natalya
SPEED:80
wave:act3\natalya\nat_act3_q5_early.wav 
"I respect your need to do this. Honor demands that you see this through. Yet your chances are so slim…"

NAME:NatalyaVA
SPEED:80
wave:act3\natalya\nat_act3_q5_early.wav 
"I respect your need to do this. Honor demands that you see this through. Yet your chances are so slim…"

STATE:Successful

//Changed "over Zakarum" to "of Zakarum" 3/28/00
NAME:Alkor
SPEED:91
wave:act3\alkor\alk_act3_q5_successful.wav 
"You've accomplished the impossible! By killing the Council, the curse of Zakarum will be lifted and our land will be free!
 
Oh. Thank you!"

NAME:Ormus 
wave:act3\ormus\orm_act3_q5_successful.wav 
SPEED:40
"Ormus is grateful to you, stranger. You have broken the long, dark reign of Zakarum and delivered the first paralyzing blow against the Three.
 
Yet still, the true test lies ahead. For he whom the Council guarded still lives within the Blackened Tower."

NAME:MeshifAct3
SPEED:76
wave:act3\meshif\mes_act3_q5_successful.wav 
"It seems the jungle is already dying back. You've broken the curse, my friend! May the Light bless you!"

NAME:Asheara
SPEED:125
wave:act3\asheara\ash_act3_q5_successful.wav 
"The sun has set on the Religion of Light."

NAME:Hratli
SPEED:68
wave:act3\hratli\hra_act3_q5_successful.wav
"The followers of Zakarum lacked all sense of moderation. The collapse of their tainted religion gives me hope."

NAME:CainAct3
SPEED:48
wave:act3\cain\cain_act3_q5_successful.wav 
"Ridding Kurast of the Council of Zakarum was essential. Still, there is more you must do. The Compelling Orb, too, must be destroyed.
 
Diablo and Baal must be close to finding their brother, Mephisto, by now. You've no time to waste."

NAME:Natalya
SPEED:88
wave:act3\natalya\nat_act3_q5_successful.wav 
"I can hardly believe you did it. Your power blankets you like a shining aura."


//Quest 3.6 The Lord of Hatred
QUEST:A3Q6
STATE:Init

NAME:Ormus
SPEED:53
wave:act3\ormus\orm_act3_q6_init.wav
"Diablo and Baal have surely found the Temple City by now. They seek to free their Brother, Mephisto, who was imprisoned by the Horadrim in the Temple's Guardian Tower.
 
You must reach him before his Brothers do and prevent them from releasing Hatred upon the world."

STATE:AfterInit

NAME:Alkor
SPEED:90
wave:act3\alkor\alk_act3_q6_after.wav 
"The hidden ways of the Tower are long forgotten. Though… it is rumored to have been built as far below the ground as above it."

NAME:AlkorVA
SPEED:114
wave:act3\alkor\alk_act3_q6_after_va.wav 
"We have seen Diablo, but remain unsure of his Brothers' whereabouts."

NAME:Ormus
SPEED:52
wave:act3\ormus\orm_act3_q6_after.wav
"Make haste! Though the Three are sure to reunite, it is uncertain as to what they have planned once they do.
 
Be cautious, my friend. Though you are mighty, no mortal can stand alone against the power of the Prime Evils."

NAME:OrmusVA
SPEED:52
wave:act3\ormus\orm_act3_q6_after.wav 
"Make haste! Though the Three are sure to reunite, it is uncertain as to what they have planned once they do.
 
Be cautious, my friend. Though you are mighty, no mortal can stand alone against the power of the Prime Evils."

NAME:MeshifAct3
SPEED:66
wave:act3\meshif\mes_act3_q6_after.wav
"Be careful when you return to the Tower. Though many of the followers of Zakarum have fled, there's no telling what horrors still lurk inside it."

NAME:MeshifAct3VA
SPEED:116
wave:act3\meshif\mes_act3_q6_after_va.wav 
"Move quickly, my friend, and end this curse once and for all!"

NAME:Asheara
SPEED:60
wave:act3\asheara\ash_act3_q6_after.wav 
"I sent a few of my Iron Wolves on a scouting mission into the jungle near the Temple City… They encountered two cloaked men who attacked them with horrifying powers.
 
My men barely survived. I have to assume that the two strangers are Diablo and Baal.
 
You'd better hurry. They're close to finding their brother."

NAME:AshearaVA
SPEED:93
wave:act3\asheara\ash_act3_q6_after_va.wav 
"Many Iron Wolves have disappeared in Travincal. The Evil is still strong there."

NAME:Hratli
SPEED:43
wave:act3\hratli\hra_act3_q6_after.wav
"Mephisto, along with Baal, was originally captured in the desert near Lut Gholein. But imprisoning two of the Brothers together was far too dangerous.
 
The Horadrim built the Guardian Tower to hold Mephisto. When Zakarum came to power in this land, it took over the Temple City without paying any heed to what was locked within the Tower.
 
And it became their doom." 

NAME:HratliVA
SPEED:73
wave:act3\hratli\hra_act3_q6_afterva.wav
"I hear there is a little family reunion about to take place in Kurast. The Three brothers draw close."

NAME:CainAct3
SPEED:116
wave:act3\cain\cain_act3_q6_after.wav 
"You must reach Mephisto before his brothers do."

NAME:CainAct3VA
SPEED:50
wave:act3\cain\cain_act3_q6_after_va.wav 
"The ancient Horadrim always feared that the Three would escape their prisons and unite. I can't believe that I, the last of their Order, have seen it come to pass.
 
You are the only one who can prevent this, my friend. The final hour draws near."

NAME:Natalya
SPEED:75
wave:act3\natalya\nat_act3_q6_after.wav 
"Now you rush to face Mephisto. Don't give in to your hatred. That is his greatest weapon against you."

NAME:NatalyaVA
SPEED:75
wave:act3\natalya\nat_act3_q6_after.wav 
"Now you rush to face Mephisto. Don't give in to your hatred. That is his greatest weapon against you."

STATE:EarlyReturn

NAME:Alkor
SPEED:68
wave:act3\alkor\alk_act3_q6_early.wav 
"Well, the good news is that events are unfolding just as Lam Esen foretold. The bad news is that the story ends in our utter ruin!"

NAME:AlkorVA
SPEED:80
wave:act3\alkor\alk_act3_q6_early_va.wav 
"I'm afraid both fear and a large dose of elixir preclude me from answering."

NAME:Ormus
SPEED:59
wave:act3\ormus\orm_act3_q6_early.wav 
"I understand that the great Patriarch of Zakarum, Sankekur, now embodies Mephisto.
 
You must overcome Hatred lest Terror and Destruction claim us all!"

NAME:OrmusVA
SPEED:77
wave:act3\ormus\orm_act3_q6_early_va.wav 
"I am loath to describe what will happen if Diablo and Baal release Mephisto."

NAME:MeshifAct3
SPEED:110
wave:act3\meshif\mes_act3_q6_early.wav
"I ought to return to the ship. We may have to sail from here very quickly."

NAME:MeshifAct3VA
SPEED:110
wave:act3\meshif\mes_act3_q6_early.wav
"I ought to return to the ship. We may have to sail from here very quickly."

NAME:Asheara
SPEED:80
wave:act3\asheara\ash_act3_q6_early.wav 
"The sudden reduction in our ranks makes us eager to destroy Diablo and his brothers. Vengeance for the Iron Wolves!"

NAME:AshearaVA
SPEED:200
wave:act3\asheara\ash_act3_q6_early_va.wav 
"We will fight to the death."

NAME:Hratli
SPEED:58
wave:act3\hratli\hra_act3_q6_early.wav
"Why build a Tower to place the beast below ground? At times I believe the Horadrim lacked common sense."

NAME:HratliVA
SPEED:106
wave:act3\hratli\hra_act3_q6_earlyva.wav
"Shouldn't you be running frantically up and down stairs about now?"

NAME:CainAct3
SPEED:96
wave:act3\cain\cain_act3_q6_early.wav 
"Search the Tower thoroughly. Mephisto must not escape."

NAME:CainAct3VA
SPEED:96
wave:act3\cain\cain_act3_q6_early.wav 
"Search the Tower thoroughly. Mephisto must not escape."

NAME:Natalya
SPEED:55
wave:act3\natalya\nat_act3_q6_early.wav 
"Beware, my friend. Sankekur may be the most powerful mortal in the world. He controls thousands of fanatical worshippers and embodies the Lord of Hatred, himself. His death will be no easy task."

NAME:NatalyaVA
SPEED:55
wave:act3\natalya\nat_act3_q6_early.wav 
"Beware, my friend. Sankekur may be the most powerful mortal in the world. He controls thousands of fanatical worshippers and embodies the Lord of Hatred himself. His death will be no easy task."

STATE:Successful

NAME:Alkor
SPEED:71
wave:act3\alkor\alk_act3_q6_successful.wav 
"Your news is great indeed. You have saved us all. I would smile, but I'm afraid my face might collapse."

NAME:Ormus
SPEED:48
wave:act3\ormus\orm_act3_q6_successful.wav 
"You have defeated a Prime Evil in combat. Ormus is impressed beyond words. But staying here will not end this conflict.
 
You must enter the Infernal Gate and stop Diablo once and for all." 

NAME:MeshifAct3
SPEED:70
wave:act3\meshif\mes_act3_q6_successful.wav
"Ahh… Now, Kurast can begin the task of rekindling its former glory… I thank you."

NAME:Asheara
SPEED:65
wave:act3\asheara\ash_act3_q6_successful.wav 
"Well done, my friend. You are a great champion of Order. Please, consider yourself an honorary Iron Wolf."

NAME:Hratli
SPEED:121
wave:act3\hratli\hra_act3_q6_successful.wav
"It looks like you're going to Hell before me.
 
Put in a good word."

NAME:CainAct3
SPEED:42
wave:act3\cain\cain_act3_q6_successful.wav 
"Our faith in you was well deserved. But Diablo has made his way to Hell; and it is likely that Baal followed him there.
 
Enter the Infernal Gate and kill the Lord of Terror before all is lost. Only then will our world be saved!"

NAME:Natalya
SPEED:55
wave:act3\natalya\nat_act3_q6_successful.wav
"Word is spreading fast that you killed Mephisto. I'd be honored to fight beside you in Hell, but I've just received my mission orders.
 
I'll be travelling to the Barbarian lands of the North, but I can't tell you why. With luck, our paths will cross again. Farewell."
//end

