//DIABLO II

//Act IV: The Harrowing

//SECTION:GREETINGS

//Halbu Greetings  -- Male warrior shopkeeper.
//act4\halbu\hal_hello.wav
//"Hello."
//act4\halbu\hal_hailtoyou.wav
//"Hail to you, Champion."
//act4\halbu\hal_whatdoyouneed.wav
//"What do you need?"

//Jamella Greetings  -- Female warrior shopkeeper
//act4\jamella\old\jam_greetings.wav
//"Greetings."
//act4\jamella\old\jam_hailtoyou.wav
//"Hail to you, Champion."
//act4\jamella\old\jam_whatdoyouneed.wav
//"What do you need?"

//Tyrael Greetings
//act4\tyreal\tyr_hello.wav
//"Hello."
//act4\tyreal\tyr_greetings.wav
//"Greetings."
//act4\tyreal\tyr_yes.wav
//"Yes?"

//Cain Greetings
//act4\cain\cain_act4_hellomyfriend.wav
//"Hello, my friend. I was hoping you'd return. It gets very unnerving here… 
//especially when I'm alone."

//Izual taunts
//act4\monster\izualtaunt1.wav
//"Save yourself!"
//act4\monster\izualtaunt2.wav 
//"Leave me!"
//act4\monster\izualtaunt3.wav 
//"You cannot help me!"
//Attacks, Get hits, and Death sfx

//changed 3/6/00
//Diablo's taunts for Quest 4.2
//act4\monster\diablotaunt1.wav
//"Not even death can save you from me…"
//act4\monster\diablotaunt2.wav
//"Aggh… The smell of life surrounds me."
//Howls, screeches, and demonic laughter
//Attacks, Get Hits, and Death sfx
//"Uhnn!"
//"Arrrghh.."

SECTION:GOSSIP
NAME:TyraelActIntro
SPEED:43
//act4\tyreal\tyr_act4_intro.wav
"It is good to see you again, hero.
 
Mephisto's defeat is a great victory for the Light. I knew that you would eventually find your way here. The Pandemonium Fortress is the last bastion of Heaven's power before the Gates of the Burning Hells.
 
This place has been hallowed by the blood of thousands of champions of the Light, many of whom were mortal, like yourself. Now the final battle against the Prime Evils draws near… and you must face it alone. 
 
I have been forbidden to aid you directly, save for a few bits of wisdom. For this is the hour of mortal Man's triumph…your triumph.
 
May the Light protect you and the powers of Heaven shine upon your path..."

NAME:TyraelAct4
SPEED:62
//act4\tyreal\tyr_act4_gossip_01.wav 
"Long ago, I swore an oath to watch over the Horadrim and their descendants.
 
As Deckard Cain is the last of their esteemed Order, I will not allow him to perish here so far from the lands of his birth.
 
Be at ease, hero, I know that he is your friend. He shall come to no harm."

NAME:CainAct4Intro
SPEED:41
//act4\cain\cain_act4_intro.wav
"Can you believe this place? Did you ever dare to dream that you'd one day stand upon the crossroads between Heaven and Hell? This Pandemonium Fortress is truly miraculous.
 
However, your journey is not yet over. Diablo still roams free in Hell, marshalling his demonic forces. Only when he is beaten will our world finally have peace.
 
Hurry now… the sands of time slow for no one! "

NAME:CainAct4
SPEED:48
//act4\cain\cain_act4_gossip_01.wav 
"I have read much about the enigmatic Archangel Tyrael. He was revered in Horadrim lore 
both for his compassion for mortals and his unquenchable spirit.
 
It was rumored that he went against the wishes of Heaven and gave the Horadrim the original Soulstones in order to trap Diablo and his Brothers."

NAME:HellsAngel
SPEED:72
//act4\angel\angel_mephistone.wav
"Halt! Before venturing into Diablo's lair, go to the Hellforge with Mephisto's Soulstone.
 
Place the stone on the Hellforge and use the Hellforge Hammer to destroy it."

NAME:HellsAngel
SPEED:66
//act4\angel\angel_mephistonesmashed.wav
"Proceed, hero, into Terror's lair.
 
Know that Diablo's innermost sanctum is hidden by five seals.
 
Only by opening each of these seals can you clear your way to the final battle."

SECTION:QUEST

//Quest 4.1: The Fallen Angel
QUEST:A4Q1
STATE:Init
NAME:Tyrael
SPEED:42
//act4\tyreal\tyr_act4_q1_init.wav 
"There is a dark, tortured soul who was trapped within this forsaken realm long ago. He was called Izual by mortal men, and in ages past he was my most trusted Lieutenant.
 
Yet, against my wishes he led an ill-fated assault upon the fiery Hellforge, itself.
 
Despite his valor and strength, Izual was captured by the Prime Evils and twisted by their perverse power. They forced him to betray his own kind and give up Heaven's most guarded secrets.
 
He became a corrupt shadow of his former self - a fallen angel trusted neither by Heaven nor Hell.
 
For his transgressions, Izual's spirit was bound within the form of a terrible creature which was summoned from the Abyss. His maddened spirit has resided within that tortured husk for many ages now.
 
It seems to me that he has suffered long enough. I implore you, hero, find Izual and release him from his cruel imprisonment.
 
Put an end to his guilt and suffering."

STATE:AfterInit 
NAME:Tyrael
SPEED:59
//act4\tyreal\tyr_act4_q1_after.wav 
"Though Izual no longer carries the Angelic Runeblade, Azurewrath, he may still possess great strength and power within his new form.
 
Also, he may not be able to tell friend from foe while in his present state. If you find him, he will almost certainly be hostile.
 
Proceed with the utmost caution."

NAME:Cain
SPEED:54
//act4\cain\cain_act4_q1_after.wav 
"Tyrael has asked you to confront Izual the Fallen? He must have great faith in your abilities!
 
I trust you know what you're doing… Be careful. You're our last hope."

STATE:EarlyReturn
NAME:Tyrael
SPEED:75
//act4\tyreal\tyr_act4_q1_early.wav 
"You mustn't delay, mortal hero. Izual must be put to rest, but Diablo still lurks within this realm.
 
Go now… Hurry!"

NAME:Cain
SPEED:83
//act4\cain\cain_act4_q1_early.wav 
"Having trouble finding the Fallen Angel, eh?
 
You'd better hurry. It's beginning to feel like some great evil is permeating the air around here."

STATE:Successful
//Said after killing the unique monster that held the spirit of Izual.
NAME:Izual
//changed 2/28/00
SPEED:47
//act4\monster\Izu_act4_q1_successful.wav
"Tyrael was a fool to have trusted me!
 
You see, it was I who told Diablo and his Brothers about the Soulstones and how to corrupt them. It was I who helped the Prime Evils mastermind their own exile to your world.
 
The plan we set in motion so long ago cannot be stopped by any mortal agency.  Hell, itself, is poised to spill forth into your world like a tidal wave of blood and nightmares.
 
You and all your kind… are doomed."

NAME:Tyrael
//changed 4/28/00 MSH
SPEED:53
//act4\tyreal\tyr_act4_q1_successful.wav 
"Thank you, hero, for putting Izual's tortured spirit to rest. May the Light protect you and the powers of Heaven shine upon your path.
 
But, if what you tell me is true, then I fear that we have been played for fools all along.
 
Izual helped Diablo and his Brothers trick me into using the Soulstones against them… Now the Stones' powers are corrupted.
 
With the combined powers of the Soulstones under their control, the Prime Evils will be able to turn the mortal world into a permanent outpost of Hell!"

NAME:Cain
SPEED:68
//act4\cain\cain_act4_q1_successful.wav 
"You're lucky to be alive, my friend! It is imperative that you find and stop Diablo!
 
You should speak of this with Tyrael. He will know what to make of this."


//Quest 4.3: The Hellforge
QUEST:A4Q3
// Initialized by killing the SuperUnique Smith near the Hellforge who drops the Hammer.

STATE:InitHasStone
NAME:Cain
//changed 2/25/00
SPEED:53
//act4\cain\cain_act4_q3_inithasstone.wav 
"The time has come for you to destroy Mephisto's Soulstone!
 
Take the Stone to the Hellforge. Place it upon the forge and strike it soundly with the Hammer.
 
Only by doing this can you prevent Mephisto from manifesting in this world ever again."

STATE:InitNoStone
NAME:Cain
//changed 2/25/00
SPEED:50
//act4\cain\cain_act4_q3_initnostone.wav 
"The time has come to destroy Mephisto's Soulstone! 
 
Although I picked it up before entering the Infernal Gate, I believe you should carry out this crucial mission.
 
Take the Stone to the Hellforge.  Place it upon the forge and strike it soundly with the Hammer.
 
Only by doing this can you prevent Mephisto from manifesting in this world ever again."

STATE:Successful
NAME:Cain
SPEED:70
//act4\cain\cain_act4_q3_successful.wav 
"Congratulations, hero!
 
Surely, even Diablo, himself, sensed the fury unleashed when you smashed his Brother's Soulstone."


//Quest 4.2: Terror's End
QUEST:A4Q2
STATE:Init
NAME:Tyrael
SPEED:48
//act4\tyreal\tyr_act4_q2_init.wav
"The time has come to hunt down and destroy Diablo, himself.
 
But beware, the Lord of Terror is not to be underestimated. He single-handedly destroyed the town of Tristram and corrupted the last noble hero who tried to stop him.
 
This time, you must defeat him for good. Only by destroying the Soulstone which he carries will his spirit be banished forever.
 
Good luck! Though this be our darkest hour, it may yet be your greatest moment."

STATE:AfterInit
NAME:Cain
SPEED:54
//act4\cain\cain_act4_q2_after.wav 
"You don't have time to dally about here!
 
Diablo awaits you in Hell. Remember… Diablo's greatest weapon against you is Terror.
 
Don't give in to your fears. Resist his power and put an end to him for good!"

NAME:Tyrael
SPEED:48
//act4\tyreal\tyr_act4_q2_init.wav 
"The time has come to hunt down and destroy Diablo, himself.
 
But beware, the Lord of Terror is not to be underestimated. He single-handedly destroyed the town of Tristram and corrupted the last noble hero who tried to stop him.
 
This time, you must defeat him for good. Only by destroying the Soulstone which he carries will his spirit be banished forever.
 
Good luck! Though this be our darkest hour, it may yet be your greatest moment."

//added 4/27/00 MSH
STATE:Successful
//When the player(s) kill(s) Diablo, the countdown begins, and then the final (Act V) cinematic plays. Players who don't have the Expansion set are sent to b.net chat. Players with the Expansion set installed return to the Pandemonium Fortress.

//During the countdown the NPCs are in active mode and say the following:

//added 4/27/00 MSH
NAME:Tyrael
SPEED:62
//act4\tyreal\tyr_act4_q2_successful.wav
"Praise be to the Light! You have accomplished the impossible!
 
Diablo and Mephisto have been banished back into the Black Abyss that spawned them and the corrupted Soulstones are no more.
 
You've done well, hero. For now, you should rejoice."

//added 4/27/00 MSH
NAME:Cain
SPEED:42
//act4\cain\cain_act4_q2_ successful.wav 
"I knew there was great potential in you, my friend. You've done a fantastic job.
 
Though my ancestors often struggled against the Three Evils and their minions, I've always lived a shut-in, scholarly life. I'm glad that my wisdom aided you.
 
Now, I wish to leave this place. Though Heaven's Gates are a marvel to behold, I hope I won't have to see them again for many, many years."

//end

02/25/00	All contents copyright © 1997 by BLIZZARD NORTH	Page 6

