//DIABLO II
//ACT 4: The Harrowing (updated)
Section:Quest
QUEST:A4Q2
State:ExpansionSuccess
//Following are new lines for Cain and Tyrael at the end of Act IV, after the player has killed Diablo. The timer does not count down in the Expansion, allowing the player to talk to Tyrael, who gives the scoop on Baal back in the mortal realm. Tyrael then pops open a portal. When the player steps into it, the final Act IV cinematic plays followed by the Act V intro. Finally, the player appears in Act V town, Harrogath.

NAME:Tyrael
SPEED:40
wave:act4\tyreal\tyr_act4_q2_successfulExp.wav
"Praise be to the Light! You have accomplished the impossible!
 
Diablo and Mephisto have been banished back into the Black Abyss that spawned them, and the corrupted Soulstones are no more.
 
However, while you were fighting here, Baal remained behind in the mortal realm, building an army of hellish minions. Now, Baal's army is searching for the Worldstone, the ancient source of all the Soulstones and their power, while leaving behind a wake of destruction. They have forged deeply into the Barbarian homelands, heading directly for the summit of Mount Arreat!
 
Baal knows, mortal hero! That is the very site of the blessed Worldstone!
 
Now, enter the portal I have opened for you. It will take you to the Barbarian city of Harrogath, the last bastion of Order on the slopes of Arreat."

NAME:Cain
SPEED:40
wave:act4\cain\cain_act4_q2_successfulExp.wav 
"I knew there was great potential in you, my friend. You've done a fantastic job.
 
Though my ancestors often struggled against the Three Evils and their minions, I've always lived a shut-in, scholarly life. I'm glad that my wisdom aided you.
 
Now, I wish to leave this place. Though Heaven's Gates are a marvel to behold, I hope I won't have to see them again for many, many years.
 
Please talk to Tyrael about leaving this place now!"



//ACT 5: Lord of Destruction

//SECTION: GREETINGS
//Cain Greetings
//Cain's greetings have already been recorded.

//common\cain\cain_hello.wav
//"Hello."
//common\cain\cain_greetings.wav
//"Greetings."
//common\cain\cain_yes.wav
//"Yes?"
//common\cain\cain_goodmorning.wav
//"Good morning."
//common\cain\cain_goodday.wav
//"Good day."
//common\cain\cain_goodevening.wav
//"Good evening."
//common\cain\cain_havenews.wav
//"I have news for you."
//common\cain\cain_havequest.wav
//"I have a quest for you."
//common\cain\cain_havereward.wav
//"I have a reward for you!"
//common\cain\cain_goodtoseeyou.wav
//"Good to see you!"
//common\cain\cain_stayandlisten.wav
//"Stay a while and listen."
//common\cain\cain_youreturned.wav
//"You have returned!"
//common\cain\cain_goodafternoon.wav
//"Good afternoon."


//Anya Greetings
//act5\Anya\any_yes.wav
//"Yes?"
//act5\Anya\any_whatareneeds.wav
//"What are your needs?"
//act5\Anya\any_hellowarrior.wav
//"Hello, warrior."
//act5\Anya\any_canihelpyou.wav
//"Can I help you?
//act5\Anya\any_hello.wav
//"Hello."
//act5\Anya\any_goodmorning.wav
//"Good morning."
//act5\Anya\any_goodafternoonwarrior.wav
//"Good morning, warrior."
//act5\Anya\any_goodevening.wav
//"Good evening."



//Larzuk Greetings
//act5\larzuk\lar_yeah.wav
//"Yeah?"
//act5\larzuk\lar_whatyouneed.wav
//"What do you need?"
//act5\larzuk\lar_atyourservice.wav
//"At your service."
//act5\larzuk\lar_goodday.wav
//"Good day."
//act5\larzuk\lar_morning.wav
//"Morning."
//act5\larzuk\lar_afternoon.wav
//"Afternoon."
//act5\larzuk\lar_evening.wav
//"Evening."
//act5\larzuk\lar_canihelpyou.wav
//"Can I help you?"
//act5\larzuk\lar_yourback.wav
//"You're back."


//Malah Greetings
//act5\malah\mal_salutations.wav
//"Salutations."
//act5\malah\mal_ howmayibeofhelp.wav
//"How may I be of help?"
//act5\malah\mal_yourpresenceiswelcome.wav
//"Your presence is welcome."
//act5\malah\mal_greetingshero.wav
//"Greetings hero."
//act5\malah\mal_hello.wav
//"Hello."
//act5\malah\mal_morningcomes.wav
//"The morning comes."
//act5\malah\mal_goodafternoon.wav
//"Good afternoon."
//act5\malah\mal_goodevening.wav
//"Good evening."


//Nihlathak Greetings
//act5\nihlathak\nih_whatisit.wav
//"What is it?"
//act5\nihlathak\nih_what.wav
//"What!"
//act5\nihlathak\nih_hmm.wav
//"Hmm?"
//act5\nihlathak\nih_yes.wav
//"Yes?"
//act5\nihlathak\nih_surprisedtoseeyou.wav
//"Surprised to see you."
//act5\nihlathak\nih_bequickaboutit.wav
//"Be quick about it!"


//Qual-Kehk Greetings
//act5\qual-kehk\qua_yeswarrior.wav
//"Yes, warrior?"
//act5\qual-kehk\qua_whatisit.wav
//"What is it?"
//act5\qual-kehk\qua_quicklytraveller.wav
//"Quickly, traveler."
//act5\qaul-kehk\qau_morning.wav
//"Morning."
//act5\qual-kehk\qua_afternoon.wav
//"Afternoon."
//act5\qual-kehk\qua_evening.wav
//"Evening."
//act5\qual-kehk\qua_canihelpyou.wav
//"Can I help you?"

//Soldiers' Cries for help
//act5\soldier\sol_overhere.wav
//"Over here!"
//act5\soldier\sol_helpus.wav
//"Help us!"
//act5\soldier\sol_letmeout.wav
//"Let us out!"

//Soldiers' Cheers and Acknowledgments 
//act5\soldier\sol_cheer1.wav
//"For the homeland!"
//act5\soldier\sol_cheer2.wav
//"Let's go!"
//act5\soldier\sol_cheer3.wav
//"Come on!"

//The following lines are to acknowledge items dropped on the hirables' portraits (in the upper left corner of the screen).
//NOTE: These lines must be recorded for the hirables in Acts I, II, and III as well.
//act5\soldier\thanks1.wav
//"Thank you."
//act5\soldier\thanks2.wav
//"I'll put that to good use."
//act5\soldier\nothanks1.wav
//"I can't use that."
//act5\soldier\nothanks2.wav
//"I can't use that…yet."


//Shenk's Taunts
//act5\overlord\ove_haha.wav
//(Menacing laughter)

//act5\overlord\ove_taunt.wav
//(gibberish in the native tongue of the Overlords)

//AncientsAct5Unworthy
//This is to be played after the player has been defeated by the Ancients or if anyone leaves or enters the Summit by Town Portal during the fight.
//NAME:Ancients
//wave:act5\ancient\anc_act5_unworthy.wav
//"Unworthy!"
//wave:act5\ancient\anc_act5_coward.wav
//"Coward!"
//wave:act5\ancient\anc_act5_haha.wav
//(mocking laughter)

//Anya's Exclamation 
//NAME:Anya
//wave:act5\Anya\any_act5_q3_rescue.wav
//"Meet me in town! Hurry!"

//Nihlathak's Taunts
//NAME:Nihlathak
//wave:act5\nihlathak\nih_act5_q4_taunt1.wav
//"You have no idea of the power you face!"
//wave:act5\nihlathak\nih_act5_q4_taunt2.wav
//"I shall keep my end of Baal's bargain!"
//wave:act5\nihlathak\nih_act5_q4_taunt3.wav
//"For my homeland!"
//wave:act5\nihlathak\nih_act5_q4_taunt4.wav
//"I will kill you!"

//Baal's Taunts
//NAME:Baal
//wave:act5\monster\baaltaunt.wav
//"My brothers will not have died in vain!"

//Baal's Death Taunt
//This is what Baal says when you kill him the first time.
//wave:act5\monster\baallaugh1.wav
//wave:act5\monster\baallaugh2.wav
//"(Maniacal Laughter)."

//Baal's Resurrection 
//This is what Baal says when he reforms into his true form.
//REMOVED 4/3/01

//Baal's Death
//wave:d2\data\global\sfx\monster\baal\death.wav
//"Aaaaggghhh…"

SECTION: GOSSIP

NAME:AncientsAct5Intro
SPEED: 35
wave:act5\ancients\anc_act5_intro.wav
"We are the spirits of the Nephalem, the Ancient Ones. We have been chosen to guard sacred Mount Arreat, wherein the Worldstone rests. Few are worthy to stand in its presence; fewer still can comprehend its true purpose.
 
Before you enter, you must defeat us." 

NAME:CainAct5Intro
SPEED: 39
wave:act5\cain\cain_act5_intro.wav
"I am amazed to find this place so untouched. Everything else in the path of Baal the Lord of Destruction lies in ruin. 
 
These Barbarians must indeed be the legendary guardians of Mount Arreat. They are a proud, hardy people. Don't expect to be greeted warmly -- strangers here rarely are.
 
Perhaps I can gain their trust. I'll spend some time with the townsfolk and try to understand them better. I'll let you know what I discover."
 
NAME:CainAct5
SPEED: 52
//The following gossips are for any player class.
wave:act5\cain\cain_act5_01.wav
"With hellspawn, size is no measure of their threat. Demons half the size of men can kill with a gesture, while hellish pack animals trample any who stand in their way."

SPEED: 55
wave:act5\cain\cain_act5_02.wav
"Though these Barbarians are known throughout the kingdoms as ferocious fighters, they are also capable of great compassion.
 
They have trained throughout history for a battle their legends foretell will decide the fate of the world."

SPEED: 55
//The following gossip should only be active after Quest five is active. (Q5)
wave:act5\cain\cain_act5_03.wav
"The angel Tyrael has watched over the guardians of Arreat throughout history. I do not believe that Baal and Tyrael have come to fight over a paltry few souls.
 
They are here to settle a conflict as old as time itself."

SPEED: 44
//The following gossip should only be active after Quest five is active. (Q5)
wave:act5\cain\cain_act5_04.wav
"During my time with the Horadrim, we often debated the nature of Mount Arreat.
 
We knew that the Barbarian clans zealously guarded the mountain as their sacred duty. However, many dismissed their zeal as simple superstition…combined with an inborn hostility toward outsiders.
 
Those Horadrim who trekked up Arreat were never heard from again…Still, I do not believe they died at the hands of Barbarians."


SPEED: 41
wave:act5\cain\cain_act5_05.wav
"All users of the magical arts know of Mount Arreat, but few understand its true nature. It is the nexus of an unfathomable magic.
 
It bodes ill that the Lord of Destruction races to its summit with such purpose. I fear for the whole world should Baal gain what he seeks."

SPEED: 59
wave:act5\cain\cain_act5_06.wav
"I have spent decades trying to understand the forces at work in this world. But in the face of all that is transpiring, I realize how meager my knowledge is.
 
I will be of assistance where I can, my friend."
 
SPEED: 54
//The following gossip must be active only after the completion of Quest 3. >Q3.
wave:act5\cain\cain_act5_07.wav
"Though the Elder Council of Harrogath is gone, there are many capable young leaders to take their place.
 
Anya certainly has enough courage and intelligence to lead them all, if they can survive this catastrophe."

SPEED: 53
//The following gossip must be active only after the completion of Quest 3. >Q3.
wave:act5\cain\cain_act5_08.wav
"Ah, Anya. Such a fine example of feminine strength…
 
She reminds me of the Zakarum priestesses I knew in my youth. They don't take vows of chastity, you know."

SPEED: 65
wave:act5\cain\cain_act5_09.wav
"It is fortunate that this town has such a talented smith.
 
The quality of Larzuk's work surely complements your skills. In fact, he would have been quite welcome amongst the Horadrim." 

SPEED: 54
wave:act5\cain\cain_act5_10.wav
"It is my belief that the Soulstones are at the center of this conflict. If only that fool Marius had not intervened, Baal would still be imprisoned within Tal Rasha." 


NAME:AnyaAct5Intro
SPEED: 54
wave:act5\Anya\any_act5_intro.wav
"You have proven yourself a true hero to me and my people.
 
These are dark times, warrior. I hope you can bring an end to Baal's reign of destruction. 
 
Our Council of Elders is gone -- my father, Aust, among them. The one thing that keeps us from total despair is the promise of vengeance against Baal." 

NAME:Anya
//The following gossips are for any player class.

//The next gossip is only active after quest 4 is complete (>Q4)
SPEED: 45
wave:act5\Anya\any_act5_gossip_01.wav
"Now that the Elders are all dead, I don't know who will guide our people through this dark time. I was to be next in line after my father, but this burden is too great for me to shoulder alone. 
 
We are a people of strong blood. I shall do what I can and let fate do the rest."

SPEED: 82
wave:act5\Anya\any_act5_gossip_02.wav
"Baal's minions are not to be trifled with. In their bloodlust they will sacrifice themselves to destroy you."

SPEED: 60
wave:act5\Anya\any_act5_gossip_03.wav
"Many outsiders believe that the fantastic stories about our ancestors, the Ancients, are but fables. However, I believe that the Ancients were more than human -- that mankind has fallen from what it once was."

SPEED: 58
wave:act5\Anya\any_act5_gossip_04.wav
"When I was a child, the Elders told us stories about the mountain and its power…and how the Barbarian people are bound to it as protectors.
 
Baal is not just taking our land -- with every step he takes up the mountain, he takes a part of who we are as a people."

SPEED: 72
wave:act5\Anya\any_act5_gossip_05.wav
"I am truly glad you are here, warrior. Perhaps things would be different now if we had asked for assistance from the neighboring kingdoms.
 
Our foolish, foolish pride…" 

SPEED: 54
wave:act5\Anya\any_act5_gossip_06.wav
"My father, Aust, was among those Elders wise enough to see that we would need outside help to deal with Baal's legions. He believed that this conflict would affect the entire world, not just our homeland. He said that Mount Arreat is as necessary to the world's survival as food and water is to our own.
 
I believe this to be true."


SPEED: 50
wave:act5\Anya\any_act5_gossip_07.wav
"Qual-Kehk's confidence in his abilities once bordered on arrogance, but in the early days of the siege, he was humbled by Baal. While he saved us from immediate destruction, a third of our warriors were lost.
 
None felt those losses more than he. Though he may not admit it, your presence gives him hope, warrior."

SPEED: 78
wave:act5\Anya\any_act5_gossip_08.wav
"If Larzuk could sing or dance half as well as he smiths, he'd be married by now.
 
…Just look at those shoulders."

SPEED: 57
wave:act5\Anya\any_act5_gossip_09.wav
"Nihlathak was the last of our Elders, whose charge it was to safeguard the mountain. He alone tried to guide us through the most desperate time in our history -- but he was just as helpless as the rest of us.
 
I cannot forgive his betrayal, but I can learn from it."

SPEED: 60
wave:act5\Anya\any_act5_gossip_10.wav
"Our people believe that the Ancients protecting Mount Arreat have the power to stop Baal. Unfortunately, the Lord of Destruction has shown great power to undermine our faith."



NAME:LarzukAct5Intro
SPEED: 55
wave:act5\larzuk\lar_act5_intro.wav
"I am Larzuk, the armorer. My ancestors were some of the finest craftsmen in Harrogath. 
 
Regretfully, my supplies run lower with every passing day, yet the demons beyond the walls have not weakened. 
 
I fear the time is near when I must put down my hammer and take up a sword, instead." 

NAME:LarzukAct5IntroAma
SPEED: 42
wave:act5\larzuk\lar_act5_intro_ama.wav
"So, you're an Amazon. I have heard rumors about your kind. Your unusual weapons could prove a challenge to my skills, but I'm prepared to meet it.
 
I am Larzuk, the armorer. My ancestors were some of the finest craftsmen in Harrogath. 

Regretfully, my supplies run lower with every passing day, yet the demons beyond the walls have not weakened. 

I fear the time is near when I must put down my hammer and take up a sword, instead."

NAME:Larzuk
SPEED: 65
//The next 2 gossips are only for the Amazon.
wave:act5\larzuk\lar_act5_gossip_ama_01.wav
"I've heard that you Amazons excel at killing from a distance. From what I've seen, that's the best way to deal with Hell's minions. 
 
Are all of your kind so…big?"

SPEED: 65
wave:act5\larzuk\lar_act5_gossip_ama_02.wav
"Why did you ever leave your beautiful islands to come to this frozen battleground? Perhaps if we both survive this, we'll travel back there together."

//The following gossips are for any player class.
SPEED: 75
wave:act5\larzuk\lar_act5_01.wav
"Has that infernal howling been keeping you awake at night, too? Some think it's the howling of animals, but those sounds don't come from any beast I've ever known."

SPEED: 69
wave:act5\larzuk\lar_act5_02.wav
"Demonic forces have been using our own towers and barricades against us. You know, it would be wise to cut the demons down in the open before they can mount those fortifications."

SPEED: 70
//The following quest should not be active after the completion of Quest 3. <Q4
wave:act5\larzuk\lar_act5_03.wav
"Nihlathak's despair is infectious -- and his behavior does not befit an Elder of his stature. I think we'd be better off without him."


SPEED: 63
wave:act5\larzuk\lar_act5_04.wav
"I've offered Qual-Kehk my ideas on how to break the siege, but he dismisses them. Is it because I lack scars of battle, or does he think I'm a couple arrows short of a quiver?"

SPEED: 64
wave:act5\larzuk\lar_act5_06.wav
"Legend has it that the top of Mount Arreat is guarded by the spirits of our ancestors. Though our people are forbidden to climb to the mountain's summit, some foreign travelers have made the attempt.
 
None have ever returned."

SPEED: 66
wave:act5\larzuk\lar_act5_07.wav
"This is a lively town during our victory celebrations. We Barbarians train long and hard from childhood to become warriors, and we celebrate with equal fervor.
 
You didn't happen to bring along any ale to trade?"

SPEED: 54
wave:act5\larzuk\lar_act5_08.wav
"Every day, one of my friends dies fighting outside the town walls, while I tend my anvil here unscathed. If only we didn't need weapons so badly, I could be out doing my share of the fighting. 
 
Good luck to you, warrior."

SPEED: 56
wave:act5\larzuk\lar_act5_09.wav
"Just so you know…The gold you pay me doesn't line my pockets. Much of it goes to buy the raw metal I need to melt down for weapons and armor. The rest -- well, all I can spare -- goes to Malah and Qual-Kehk for other supplies."



NAME:MalahAct5Intro
//MALAH INTRO SPEECH (Player starts new game near this character…she is in Active Mode.)
SPEED: 35
wave:act5\malah\mal_act5_intro.wav
"I, Malah, welcome you to Harrogath, the last stronghold of Order on Mount Arreat. You have come to the right place if you intend to defeat Baal the Lord of Destruction.
 
Baal has laid waste to our mountain and its denizens. His minions continue to attack our town, while Qual-Kehk and his men have proven helpless to stop them. Baal is still out on the mountain looking for something -- but I know not what. 
 
All of the Elders, save Nihlathak, sacrificed themselves to place a protective ward around Harrogath.
 
Some of us here, certainly Nihlathak, do not appreciate your presence. We are a proud people, and it is not easy for us to accept aid. I, however, am glad you are here.
 
If you need healing or a potion, please come to me. See Larzuk for weapons, armor, and repairs. Nihlathak, despite his disposition, may be of some assistance with other wares. Finally, Qual-Kehk, our Man-At-Arms, leads Harrogath's remaining forces against Baal." 

NAME:MalahAct5IntroSor
SPEED: 36
wave:act5\malah\mal_act5_intro_sor.wav
"A Sorceress…Here in Harrogath?
 
There was a time, child, when I thought I was destined to follow your kind's path. However, my powers never developed beyond the simplest of spells. Although I can heal almost any wound with time and energy, there is little I can do to help against Baal.
 
But enough of that…I spend too much time in reflection and have forgotten my manners.
 
I, Malah, welcome you to Harrogath, the last stronghold of Order on Mount Arreat. You have come to the right place, if you intend to defeat Baal the Lord of Destruction.
 
Baal has laid waste to our mountain and its denizens. His minions continue to attack our town, while Qual-Kehk and his men have proven helpless to stop them. Baal is still out on the mountain looking for something -- but I know not what. 
 
All of the Elders, save Nihlathak, sacrificed themselves to place a protective ward around Harrogath.
 
Some of us here, certainly Nihlathak, do not appreciate your presence. We are a proud people, and it is not easy for us to accept aid. I, however, am glad you are here.
 
If you need healing or a potion, please come to me. See Larzuk for weapons, armor, and repairs. Nihlathak, despite his disposition, may be of some assistance with other wares. Finally, Qual-Kehk, our Man-At-Arms, leads Harrogath's remaining forces against Baal."
 

NAME:MalahAct5IntroBar
SPEED: 34
wave:act5\malah\mal_act5_intro_bar.wav
"You have traveled far only to return home to us, Barbarian. Ohh…Much has happened in Harrogath since you left. Our homeland is hardly recognizable with so much evil about.
 
Yet, I've managed to survive so far. You've seen your share of suffering as well, I'm sure. Seeing you again -- alive -- does my heart good. I shall pray that you can help us out of this hell.
 
Baal has laid waste to our mountain and its denizens. His minions continue to attack our town, while Qual-Kehk and his men have proven helpless to stop them. Baal is still out on the mountain looking for something -- but I know not what.
 
Nihlathak is the last survivor of the Council of Elders, but I'm afraid he has not been himself lately. The other Elders sacrificed themselves to place a protective ward around Harrogath. If Nihlathak is curt with you, it is because he feels responsible for our situation. He does not relish sending more of our people out to die.
 
So much has changed since you left that I see little hope for us in this life.
 
If you need healing or a potion, please come to me. See Larzuk for weapons, armor, and repairs. Nihlathak, despite his disposition, may be of some assistance with other wares. Finally, Qual-Kehk, our Man-At-Arms, leads Harrogath's remaining forces against Baal."

NAME:Malah
SPEED: 53
//The next gossip is only for the Sorceress.
wave:act5\malah\mal_act5_gossip_sor.wav
"I'm aware of the amazing magical powers a Sorceress can channel. If we survive Baal's wrath, I would be most honored if you could demonstrate and perhaps teach me something of what you know. 
 
I may be old, but I'm not dead."

SPEED: 42
//The next gossip is only for the Barbarian.
wave:act5\malah\mal_act5_gossip_bar.wav
"I know you and my son, Bannuk, did not part on the best of terms. He did not understand the wanderlust that drove you to leave your homeland. However, even though Bannuk could never admit it to me, as he grew older I could see that same desire in his eyes.
 
Oh…It's a pity I didn't encourage him to go with you. He might still be alive today."

//The following gossips are for any player class.
SPEED: 57
wave:act5\malah\mal_act5_01.wav
"Though once considered shelter by our people, the Ice Caves offer no refuge from the dark horde. There are creatures there that will freeze your heart before feasting upon it."

SPEED: 107
wave:act5\malah\mal_act5_02.wav
"On the battlefield, turning your back on even the dead is unwise."


SPEED: 60
wave:act5\malah\mal_act5_03.wav
"This battle plays mind tricks on our warriors. Those fortunate enough to have returned from the mountainside claim to have seen angels in flight.
 
Fly they might, but that certainly does not make them angels."

SPEED: 53
wave:act5\malah\mal_act5_04.wav
"Perhaps you have heard the accounts of my son's horrible death at the hands of Baal's minions. 
He was my last living child…
 
The oath of compassion I have taken as a healer extends only to humankind.
 
Cut them down, warrior. All of them!"

SPEED: 78
wave:act5\malah\mal_act5_05.wav
"The catapults are infernal machines made of demon flesh fused with steel.
 
Be wary of them."

//The next gossip must be active only before quest 2 is complete. (<Q2)
SPEED: 60
wave:act5\malah\mal_act5_06.wav
"Qual-Kehk is a worthy leader, but the losses have borne heavily upon him. He is only impatient because he judges the worth of a warrior by action, not words.
 
You must prove yourself worthy of his trust."

SPEED: 52
wave:act5\malah\mal_act5_07.wav
"Larzuk possesses a good soul, but at times his mind seems quite unsound. 
 
He once asked me for twenty of my finest sheepskins. He said he would fill them with hot air and float like a cloud above the battlefield to spy on Baal's legions! 
 
I worry the siege has driven him mad."

SPEED: 90
wave:act5\malah\mal_act5_08.wav
"Be cautious, warrior.
 
Though I am an experienced healer, resurrection is beyond my powers."

SPEED: 53
wave:act5\malah\mal_act5_09.wav
"I pray for the day when the fields are covered in snow unstained by the blood of our own. Perhaps that day will come soon…Perhaps never…
 
Oh…But I forget myself. How may I aid your quest?"

SPEED: 64
wave:act5\malah\mal_act5_10.wav
"Your gold is most helpful. Medical supplies for our wounded are scarce and very expensive.
 
When we can find a supplier, oh, we must pay dearly for what we need."

SPEED: 44
wave:act5\Malah\mal_act5_11.wav
"With the exception of Qual-Kehk, the townspeople do not see what I see -- the massacre we face.
 
Our bravest, strongest heroes hobble back to me begging for help. I do what I can -- healing and bandaging some, preparing the others for what lies beyond."


NAME:NihlathakAct5Intro
SPEED: 43
wave:act5\nihlathak\nih_act5_intro.wav
"Well, well. The siege has everything in short supply…except fools. 
 
Why would you seek this place, stranger? Are you a vulture come to loot the bodies of our fallen warriors? 
 
Regardless, this is no place to make a name for yourself. The mountain is ours to protect. It is only a matter of time before Hell's legions are routed."

NAME:NihlathakAct5IntroAss
SPEED: 54
wave:act5\nihlathak\nih_act5_intro_ass.wav
"Well, well…An Assassin!
 
Heh, heh…While I am sure we are all grateful for your presence in our troubled town, you need not have made the journey.
 
I can personally say that your skills are not required here. You would serve your clan better elsewhere."
 
NAME:NihlathakAct5IntroNec
SPEED: 45
wave:act5\nihlathak\nih_intro_nec.wav
"Ahhh, a Necromancer.
 
While I admire your courage in seeking out the darker side of magic, we really have little need of your skills. The battle will turn soon enough without your meddling. 
 
Yet, I should have expected to see your kind here. You are like a moth to the flame -- drawn to all this death. It feeds you in more ways than one, does it not?"
 

NAME:Nihlathak
SPEED: 49
//The next gossip is only for the Assassin.
wave:act5\nihlathak\nih_act5_gossip_ass.wav
"If you're looking for cases of treacherous magic, Assassin, take a hard look at Larzuk. He was the only one in town who escaped the Red Fever last spring. He claimed his good fortune was due to 'hand washing' before meals.
 
Hmmm…Very suspicious…"

SPEED: 48
//The next gossip is only for the Necromancer.
wave:act5\nihlathak\nih_act5_gossip_nec.wav
"Why would you seek this place, stranger? Are you a vulture come to loot the bodies of our fallen warriors? 
 
Regardless, this is no place to make a name for yourself. The mountain is ours to protect. It is only a matter of time before Hell's legions are routed."

//The following gossips are for any player class.
SPEED: 67
wave:act5\nihlathak\nih_act5_01.wav
"Qual-Kehk is useless. He has blindly sent our warriors to their deaths, assuming Baal's legions would fight as men do. Of course, everyone knows they do not."

SPEED: 57
wave:act5\nihlathak\nih_act5_02.wav
"The demon hordes have grown powerful beyond measure, aided by our foolish mistakes. But I may have found a way to correct those mistakes…"

SPEED: 37
wave:act5\nihlathak\nih_act5_03.wav
//(small, quiet, melancholy)
"Oh yes…I remember our warriors as children. Malah would set their broken bones and give them powders for their fevers. Now, they return to her with wounds that will never heal.
 
I am tired…Please…leave me."

SPEED: 133
wave:act5\nihlathak\nih_act5_04.wav
"If you have nothing useful for me, be on your way!"

//The next gossip must be active only after quest 3 is completed. (>Q3)
SPEED: 81
wave:act5\nihlathak\nih_act5_05.wav
"Anya's father was my good friend. There are so many to mourn…I have no time for you!"

SPEED: 53
wave:act5\nihlathak\nih_act5_06.wav
"I have long been criticized, but especially of late -- since the deaths of my fellow Elders. Through it all, I have learned one thing. Each man must do what's right, no matter what others may think."

SPEED: 65
wave:act5\nihlathak\nih_act5_07.wav
"The Council of Elders always believed itself prepared for the coming of the Three. Obviously, we were not prepared enough."

NAME:QualKehkAct5Intro
SPEED: 45
wave:act5\Qual-Kehk\qua_act5_intro.wav
"I am Qual-Kehk, the Senior Man-At-Arms of Harrogath.
 
You have the look of a warrior…An extra soldier will be useful. But don't expect anyone to mourn if you get yourself killed. 
 
Baal is true to his namesake. He has ravaged through our lands like a merciless plague.
 
The protective ward laid down by our lost Elders helps hold the evil at bay, but Baal's siege has taken its toll all the same.
 
Most of my men are now dead. Others are trapped in the mountain passes.
 
But I swear we are not beaten yet! We will fight to the end to protect this mountain!" 

NAME:QualKehkAct5IntroPal
SPEED: 42
wave:act5\qual-kehk\qua_act5_intro_pal.wav
"A Paladin! I have long heard of your people.
 
As a young warrior I even considered the pilgrimage to Kurast. But I was younger then and foolish. My place has always been here -- protecting Harrogath, and Mount Arreat with it.
 
I am Qual-Kehk, the Senior Man-At-Arms of Harrogath.
 
You have the look of a warrior…An extra soldier will be useful. But don't expect anyone to mourn if you get yourself killed. 
 
Baal is true to his namesake. He has ravaged through our lands like a merciless plague.
 
The protective ward laid down by our lost Elders helps hold the evil at bay, but Baal's siege has taken its toll all the same.
 
Most of my men are now dead. Others are trapped in the mountain passes.
 
But I swear we are not beaten yet! We will fight to the end to protect this mountain!" 


NAME:QualKehkAct5IntroDru
SPEED: 42
wave:act5\qual-kehk\qua_act5_intro_dru.wav
"A Druid in Harrogath! Have things truly come to this?
 
After the Mage Wars, I assumed Druids would never be seen in Harrogath again. You take a big chance coming here! 
 
To be honest, I have never been comfortable with your shape-shifting kind, but I do respect your search for balance and peace. So, if you trust us enough to enter our gates, I trust you enough to let you stay.
 
I am Qual-Kehk, the Senior Man-At-Arms of Harrogath.
 
You have the look of a warrior…An extra soldier will be useful. But don't expect anyone to mourn if you get yourself killed. 
 
Baal is true to his namesake. He has ravaged through our lands like a merciless plague.
 
The protective ward laid down by our lost Elders helps hold the evil at bay, but Baal's siege has taken its toll all the same.
 
Most of my men are now dead. Others are trapped in the mountain passes.
 
But I swear we are not beaten yet! We will fight to the end to protect this mountain!" 


NAME:QualKehk
SPEED: 67
//The next gossip is only for the Paladin.
wave:act5\qual-kehk\qua_act5_gossip_pal.wav
"It would be an honor to have a warrior of the Light fighting side-by-side with my men.
 
I can see your faith gives you great strength, Paladin, but don't expect it to keep you out of harm's way."

SPEED: 61
//The next gossip is only for the Druid.
wave:act5\qual-kehk\qua_act5_gossip_dru.wav
"Harrogath has great need of your powers, noble Druid. However, in the face of this supernatural onslaught, are your natural powers up to the task?"

//The following gossips are for any player class.
SPEED: 44
wave:act5\qual-kehk\qua_act5_01.wav
"The death of Malah's son was a great tragedy. He was our finest archer.
 
While leading a successful campaign against Baal's forces, he was impaled on a demon's spear. The wound was such that…Well, even Malah herself acknowledges that quick death was a blessing."

SPEED: 57
wave:act5\qual-kehk\qua_act5_02.wav
"We have lost many well-trained warriors to Baal's siege machines. Their range is great. Though, they are vulnerable if you close the distance quickly enough."

SPEED: 96
wave:act5\qual-kehk\qua_act5_03.wav
"Baal's legions seem countless, but slaying their commanders takes some of the fight out of them."

SPEED: 58
wave:act5\qual-kehk\qua_act5_04.wav
"Early on, parties of our best scouts were ambushed by demons that spawned from the very air around them. Survivors often mentioned a strange creature floating in the distance.
 
Perhaps taking it down could prevent some nasty surprises."


SPEED: 57
wave:act5\qual-kehk\qua_act5_05.wav
"This is unlike any battle I have ever fought. While we ration food and water, the demon hordes feast nightly on the flesh and blood of our dead."

SPEED: 48
wave:act5\qual-kehk\qua_act5_06.wav
"Larzuk is a talented blacksmith, but his head is full of some strange ideas. 
 
Just the other day he came to me with a plan to break the siege. He wanted to fill large pipes with exploding powders and steel balls, then…Well, like I said, strange."

SPEED: 46
wave:act5\qual-kehk\qua_act5_07.wav
"Our Elders were wise leaders in more peaceful times, but now the survival of our people has fallen to me. My men and I will fight to the death, but there's no way to ensure the outcome.
 
I used to believe that nothing could break through our guard and assault the holy mountain. I know now that I was horribly mistaken."


SECTION:QUEST

//Quest 5.1: Siege on Harrogath
QUEST:A5Q1

STATE:Init

NAME:Larzuk
SPEED: 45
wave:act5\larzuk\lar_act5_q1_init.wav
// changed 3/6/2001 msh
"If you're here to defeat Baal, you must prove it!
 
As we speak, Harrogath is under siege by Baal's demons. Catapults rain death just outside the town walls.
 
Baal himself travels up the sacred mountain, having left in charge here one of his most vicious generals, Shenk the Overseer. A ruthless taskmaster, he lashes his own minions into suicidal frenzies on the battlefield.
 
If you wish to prove yourself to us, destroy the monster, Shenk, that commands those infernal catapults outside Harrogath.
  
If you manage to do this, return to me."

STATE:AfterInit

NAME:Larzuk
SPEED: 150
wave:act5\larzuk\lar_act5_q1_after.wav
"Uh…Did I mention there were catapults?"

NAME:Cain
SPEED: 83
wave:act5\cain\cain_act5_q1_after.wav
"I believe that stopping the siege on Harrogath is the only way for you to earn the trust of these people."

NAME:Anya
SPEED: 84
wave:act5\Anya\any_act5_q1_after.wav
"You've proven your skill at rescuing fair maidens…but how are you at killing vicious beasts?"

NAME:Malah
SPEED: 77
wave:act5\malah\mal_act5_q1_after.wav
"Qual-Kehk and his men have been fighting to break the siege for some time. Where many have failed, you may succeed."

NAME:Nihlathak
SPEED: 70
wave:act5\nihlathak\nih_act5_q1_after.wav
"After so many have died, who are you to think you can accomplish what our proud warriors could not?"

NAME:QualKehk
SPEED: 66
wave:act5\qual-kehk\qua_act5_q1_after.wav
"About to face Shenk the Overseer and stop the siege, are you? You should ask Malah to perform your last rites before you go, stranger."
 
STATE:EarlyReturn

NAME:Larzuk
SPEED: 90
wave:act5\larzuk\lar_act5_q1_early.wav
"What's the matter, hero? Questioning your fortitude? I know we are."

NAME:Cain
SPEED: 105
wave:act5\cain\cain_act5_q1_early.wav
"I understand your reluctance, but now is the time to strike."

NAME:Anya
SPEED: 66
wave:act5\Anya\any_act5_q1_early.wav
"Those demons have been out there since before your arrival. Can you do nothing to stop them?
 
Your task is a simple one, warrior. Find Shenk and destroy him."

NAME:Malah
SPEED: 64
wave:act5\malah\mal_act5_q1_early.wav
"This may not be very encouraging, but you have fared better than the others who passed through those gates.
 
In regards to Shenk the Overseer, remember: a general is nothing without his men."

NAME:Nihlathak
SPEED: 78
wave:act5\nihlathak\nih_act5_q1_early.wav
"What are you still doing here? I thought you were going off to die.
 
Go…Be quick about it."

NAME:QualKehk
SPEED: 93
wave:act5\qual-kehk\qua_act5_q1_early.wav
"So, you still live. You're either quick or a coward." 


STATE:Successful

NAME:Larzuk
SPEED: 63
wave:act5\larzuk\lar_act5_q1_successful.wav
"You're an even greater warrior than I expected…Sorry for underestimating you.
 
As a token of my appreciation, I will craft sockets into an item of your choosing, and from now on, you'll get the best price for all my wares."

NAME:Cain
SPEED: 60
wave:act5\cain\cain_act5_q1_successful.wav
"Those catapults were like nothing I have ever seen before. You have prevailed against Shenk, my friend, but Baal is still far ahead of you."

NAME:Anya
SPEED: 108
wave:act5\Anya\any_act5_q1_successful.wav
"I was starting to wonder how long it would take you to stop those beasts.
 
Good job."

NAME:Malah
SPEED: 94
wave:act5\malah\mal_act5_q1_successful.wav
"Oh…At last, the siege is ended. You truly are an angel.
 
I thank you."

NAME:Nihlathak
SPEED: 65
wave:act5\nihlathak\nih_act5_q1_successful.wav
"Ending the siege does not earn immediate respect, outsider.
 
Respect only comes with sacrifice -- something I'm sure you know nothing of."

NAME:QualKehk
SPEED: 68
wave:act5\qual-kehk\qua_act5_q1_successful.wav
"So…You managed to stop the siege.
 
You are more powerful than I gave you credit for. You have rightfully earned my respect." 



//Quest 5.2: Rescue on Mount Arreat
QUEST:A5Q2

STATE:Init

NAME:QualKehk
SPEED: 58
wave:act5\qual-kehk\qua_act5_q2_init.wav
"My concerns have turned to my men taken prisoner on the battlefield by Baal's demons. I hate to think what's happened to them.
 
As you journey up the mountain, keep your eyes open for my soldiers and bring them back to me if you can."

STATE:AfterInit

NAME:QualKehk
SPEED: 85
wave:act5\Qual-Kehk\qua_act5_q2_after.wav
"Those of my men fortunate enough to escape on their own told me that they were held captive in the highlands and plateaus."

NAME:Cain
SPEED: 74
wave:act5\cain\cain_act5_q2_after.wav
"I know firsthand that captivity is a sad fate for a man. Find them quickly."

NAME:Anya
SPEED: 85
wave:act5\Anya\any_act5_q2_after.wav
"If those men are being treated like I was, you must find them. They won't survive much longer."

NAME:Larzuk
SPEED: 73
wave:act5\larzuk\lar_act5_q2_after.wav
"I crafted the swords and armor for Qual-Kehk's men. They were like brothers to me. I can't imagine the pain they must be suffering.
 
Save them if you can!"

NAME:Malah
SPEED: 84
wave:act5\malah\mal_act5_q2_after.wav
"Qual-Kehk's men have been imprisoned for some time. They are certain to be tired and weak.
 
You must protect them once you free them."

NAME:Nihlathak
SPEED: 94
wave:act5\nihlathak\nih_act5_q2_after.wav
"You have proven you can take life, warrior, but can you save it as well?"



STATE:EarlyReturn
NAME:QualKehk
SPEED: 95
wave:act5\qual-kehk\qua_act5_q2_early.wav
"They say that discretion, not procrastination, is the better part of valor."

NAME:QualKehkMan
SPEED: 78
wave:act5\qual-kehk\qua_act5_q2_nthman.wav
"More of my men are still alive out there. I am certain of it!
 
Find them. Free them from their cages and bring them back to me."

NAME:Cain
SPEED: 63
wave:act5\cain\cain_act5_q2_early.wav
"If you are having trouble finding Qual-Kehk's soldiers, you should talk to Malah. She healed those who made it back before. Perhaps she would have some advice."

NAME:Anya
SPEED: 115
wave:act5\Anya\any_act5_q2_early.wav
"Well, you found me on the mountain; I'm sure you'll find them too."

NAME:Larzuk
SPEED: 76
wave:act5\larzuk\lar_act5_q2_early.wav
"As a kid, I used to play soldier among the barricades on the mountain. There's no easy way through that maze of walls."

NAME:Malah
SPEED: 67
wave:act5\malah\mal_act5_q2_early.wav
"Soldiers who made it back told of a system of barricades placed among the mountain passes. They said that is where the prisoners are held."

NAME:Nihlathak
SPEED: 52
wave:act5\nihlathak\nih_act5_q2_early.wav
"Did you ever stop to think why these demons are capturing Qual-Kehk's men? Why they are attacking us? Have you considered what Baal wants with the mountain?
 
No. You've not. You have no idea what you are dealing with."



STATE:Successful

NAME:QualKehk
SPEED: 51
wave:act5\qual-kehk\qua_act5_q2_successful.wav
"Thank you for rescuing my men. They have spoken well of your bravery in battle. Perhaps there is hope for us after all. 
 
If you wish, you may hire some of my mercenaries that you saved. And please…take this set of runes. I had been saving them for a socketed shield, but I think you'll make better use of them.
 
Be sure to set them in the right order for their fullest effect." 

NAME:Cain
SPEED: 80
wave:act5\cain\cain_act5_q2_successful.wav
"You've become a hero to this town, my friend. The shadows have lifted ever since you brought the Light to Harrogath."

NAME:Anya
SPEED: 107
wave:act5\Anya\any_act5_q2_successful.wav
"I'm sure those men appreciate the freedom you gave them…as much as I do."

NAME:Larzuk
SPEED: 55
wave:act5\larzuk\lar_act5_q2_successful.wav
"Since your arrival, Cain has spoken of your deeds in the Southern Kingdoms, defeating both Mephisto and Diablo. At first, I scoffed at his tales, but I'm finding them more believable with every passing day."

NAME:Malah
SPEED: 73
wave:act5\malah\mal_act5_q2_successful.wav
"You have inspired the people in this town -- not only those you rescued, but those you've helped in other ways as well."

NAME:Nihlathak
SPEED: 72
//sarcastically
wave:act5\nihlathak\nih_act5_q2_successful.wav
"So. You brought the lost sheep home to the shepherd. Well done."


//Quest 5.3: Prison of Ice
QUEST:A5Q3

STATE:Init

NAME:Malah
SPEED: 43
wave:act5\malah\mal_act5_q3_init.wav

"There is a matter which I hesitate to share, but I believe you are the only one who can help me now.
 
Anya, the young alchemist and daughter to one of our slain Elders, has been missing for some time. She is a strong, crafty woman with a spirit like no other.
 
One night, just before your arrival, I overheard her and Nihlathak arguing about her father's death. The next morning she was gone.
 
Nihlathak has his own tale as to where she went and why. Don't believe him! I fear he is at the root of her disappearance.
 
Please, if you can, search for Anya and bring her back to us. She'll know what to do about Nihlathak."



STATE:AfterInit

NAME:Malah
SPEED: 94
wave:act5\Malah\mal_act5_q3_after.wav
"When you talk to Nihlathak, be careful. There is no telling what he will say or do."

NAME:Cain
SPEED: 59
wave:act5\cain\cain_act5_q3_after.wav
"I would listen to Malah. Nihlathak speaks with a venomous tongue and acts as if the entire weight of this town rests upon his shoulders.
 
Perhaps there is more going on here than we know."

NAME:Larzuk
SPEED: 57
wave:act5\larzuk\lar_act5_q3_after.wav
"Anya is an amazing alchemist, especially for her young age. As long as I've known her, she's never let anything stop her from pursuing what she believed in. 
 
I wouldn't doubt that Nihlathak is involved. Ever since her father died, they haven't gotten along." 

NAME:Nihlathak
SPEED: 41
wave:act5\nihlathak\nih_act5_q3_after.wav
"Anya! Who have you been talking to? Likely it was that meddling Malah. 
 
Well, I'll tell you what really happened. Anya came to me for guidance, after receiving a vision that her mother and younger brother were trapped in the lands beyond the Ice Caves. She had decided to go rescue them. 
 
I told her that her quest was a foolish one and that she would be safer staying within the city walls. However, she is a willful girl and would not listen to me. 
 
The next morning, she was gone. No one is more distraught than I over losing her. 
 
However, if you feel the need to be Malah's errand child, I won't try to stop you."

NAME:QualKehk
SPEED: 43
wave:act5\qual-kehk\qua_act5_q3_after.wav
"Anya's father, Aust, was our wisest Elder. He was killed along with the other Elders who erected the ward that protects this city. The ward has kept Baal's demons out of Harrogath, but at a costly sacrifice. 
 
Nihlathak, on the other hand, was the only Elder to escape the demons. Somehow, he alone managed to find sanctuary, while the others died around him.
 
Ever since that day, Nihlathak and Anya have been at odds."



STATE:EarlyReturn

NAME:Malah
SPEED: 52
wave:act5\malah\mal_act5_q3_early.wav
"If it were anyone else, I would assume her dead. However, Anya is not so easily beaten. I know she must be alive."

NAME:Cain
SPEED: 60
wave:act5\cain\cain_act5_q3_early.wav
"Nihlathak's story does sound reasonable, considering what I've heard about Anya. However, the best lies are often hidden within truth."

NAME:Larzuk
SPEED: 56
wave:act5\larzuk\lar_act5_q3_early.wav
"As the daughter of Elder Aust, Anya is the only person, besides Nihlathak, who has any real knowledge of Mount Arreat's secrets. I'd hate to see our fate in the hands of Nihlathak alone."

NAME:Nihlathak
SPEED: 46
wave:act5\nihlathak\nih_act5_q3_early.wav
"Look, I've told you! She's dead! If you knew what was good for you, you'd concentrate your efforts on saving Harrogath -- not on lost causes like Anya."

NAME:QualKehk
SPEED: 81
wave:act5\qual-kehk\qua_act5_q3_early.wav
"It seems like everyone feels Nihlathak played a part in Anya's disappearance.
 
Why would he do such a thing?"


STATE:FoundAnya

NAME:Malah
SPEED: 56
wave:act5\malah\mal_act5_q3_found.wav
"So! That snake Nihlathak was behind Anya's disappearance…and he trapped her with a freezing curse.
 
Here. Take this potion to Anya and give it to her. That should release her."

NAME:Cain
SPEED: 54
wave:act5\cain\cain_act5_q3_found.wav
"Goodness! Anya frozen by that fallen Barbarian, Nihlathak…Perhaps Malah can help you where I cannot."

NAME:Larzuk
SPEED: 80
wave:act5\larzuk\lar_act5_q3_found.wav
"Poor Anya! I should've known Nihlathak was a traitor…
 
If you find him alive, kill him for me!"

NAME:QualKehk
SPEED: 70
wave:act5\qual-kehk\qua_act5_q3_found.wav 
"The snake has slipped our grasp! While you were gone, Nihlathak disappeared.
 
I'll bet Anya knows how to track him down."

NAME:Anya
SPEED: 50
wave:act5\Anya\any_act5_q3_found.wav 
"Hero. Nihlathak did this to me!
 
If you've come to help me, my only hope lies with Malah.
 
Please…Tell her you've found me…"


STATE:Successful

NAME:Malah
SPEED: 48
wave:act5\malah\mal_act5_q3_successful.wav
"Thank you so much for bringing Anya back to us. I have devised this spell to increase your resistances as a token of my thanks. I know it isn't much, but I hope you find it helpful.
 
Please go talk to Anya. She has urgent news concerning Nihlathak."

NAME:Cain
SPEED: 62
wave:act5\cain\cain_act5_q3_successful.wav
"For one so young, Anya commands great respect. Now that she is here, I will make it a point to talk to her about Mount Arreat.
 
You should do the same."

NAME:Larzuk
SPEED: 67
wave:act5\larzuk\lar_act5_q3_successful.wav
"I never liked Nihlathak, but I never suspected that he'd betray us! I just can't understand how an Elder could do such a thing."

NAME:QualKehk
SPEED: 140
wave:act5\qual-kehk\qua_act5_q3_successful.wav
"Your rescue of Anya was quite an accomplishment."

NAME:Anya
SPEED: 80
wave:act5\Anya\any_act5_q3_successful.wav
"Thank you, hero, for rescuing me.
 
To show my personal gratitude, I give you this. I had it custom-made for you by Larzuk."



//Quest 5.4: The Betrayal of Harrogath
QUEST:A5Q4

STATE:Init
NAME:Anya
SPEED: 43
wave:act5\Anya\any_act5_intro.wav
"Nihlathak told me he struck a deal with Baal to protect Harrogath. In exchange for the demon's mercy, the misguided fool plans to give Baal the Relic of the Ancients, our most holy totem!
 
Doing so will allow Baal to enter Mount Arreat unchallenged by the Ancients. I tried to stop Nihlathak, but he imprisoned me in that icy tomb.
 
Nihlathak must be stopped before he dooms the whole world. As much as I would love to strangle the life out of him, I'm afraid I haven't the strength.
 
You must go to his lair through this portal I've opened, kill him, and then bring back the Relic of the Ancients.
 
Stop Nihlathak from destroying what we have striven for eons to protect."


STATE:AfterInit

NAME:Anya
SPEED: 90
wave:act5\Anya\any_act5_q4_after.wav
"As noble as Nihlathak's intentions are, nothing can excuse his actions."

NAME:Cain
SPEED: 50
wave:act5\cain\cain_act5_q4_after.wav
"Regretfully, I know very little about this Relic. However, if what the others say is true, then Baal must not gain possession of it.
 
Stop Nihlathak…before all is lost."

NAME:Malah
SPEED: 65
wave:act5\Malah\mal_act5_q4_after.wav
"My worst fear has come true. Nihlathak has gone mad.
 
You must stop him, before he gives the Relic to the Lord of Destruction!"

NAME:Larzuk
SPEED: 56
wave:act5\larzuk\lar_act5_q4_after.wav
"Now, rescuing Anya -- that's good. Talking to me while Nihlathak hands over the Relic to Baal -- uh…that's bad!" 

NAME:QualKehk
SPEED: 60
wave:act5\qual-kehk\qua_act5_q4_after.wav
"I saw Nihlathak leave town just before you found Anya. He must be held accountable for his criminal deeds.
 
Find him and bring him back, if you can. Likely, he won't come willingly, and you'll be forced to kill him.
 
So be it."

STATE:EarlyReturn

NAME:Anya
SPEED: 55
wave:act5\Anya\any_act5_q4_early.wav
"Nihlathak is a traitor! If Baal gets the Relic, he shall enter the mountain and wreak havoc there!
 
I cannot believe that Nihlathak would give the Relic to Baal in any kind of trade. He's truly insane if he believes that he can deal with the Lord of Destruction."

NAME:Cain
SPEED: 58
wave:act5\cain\cain_act5_q4_early.wav
"Ohh…This is a truly horrible turn of events.
 
I know it seems you have always been one step behind, my friend. But look at it this way…You have evil on the run."

NAME:Larzuk
SPEED: 160
wave:act5\larzuk\lar_act5_q4_early.wav
"…What's there to talk about?
 
Kill Nihlathak!"

NAME:Malah
SPEED: 63
wave:act5\malah\mal_act5_q4_early.wav
"Nihlathak was never the kindest man. But for him to betray the whole world…
 
Ahh…Where shall his soul finally rest?"

NAME:QualKehk
SPEED: 65
wave:act5\qual-kehk\qua_act5_q4_early.wav
"My advice is to go in quick and hit hard. Nihlathak can't be half as tough as the beasts you've faced out there." 



STATE: Successful

NAME:Anya
SPEED: 55
wave:act5\Anya\any_act5_q4_successful.wav
"You have stopped Nihlathak, but he didn't have the Relic! He must have already given it to Baal. Now, Baal will not be tested when he reaches Arreat's summit.
 
…Damn Nihlathak!
 
I do thank you for trying, though. Please, allow me to honor your courage by magically inscribing your name onto an item of your choosing. It's the least I can do."

NAME:Cain
SPEED: 90
wave:act5\cain\cain_act5_q4_successful.wav
"Beware! Baal grows stronger with every passing moment."

NAME:Larzuk
SPEED: 93
wave:act5\larzuk\lar_act5_q4_successful.wav
"Hmmm…What does Baal plan to do inside Mount Arreat?"

NAME:Malah
SPEED: 65
wave:act5\malah\mal_act5_q4_successful.wav
"So, the Relic is lost. Do not dwell on failures past. It is your future that matters more."

NAME:QualKehk
SPEED: 57
wave:act5\qual-kehk\qua_act5_q4_successful.wav
"Nihlathak was a vile demon that shall find his home among the tortured minions of Hell!
 
You battled the Darkness without fear. I laud your skill and courage." 


//Quest 5.5: Rite of Passage
QUEST:A5Q5

STATE:Init

NAME:QualKehk
SPEED: 37
wave:act5\qual-kehk\qua_act5_q5_init.wav
"Every time I hear of you, warrior, your deeds become more legendary.
 
But take heed. You are approaching the very summit of Mount Arreat. I have never dared venture there. It is sacred -- our most holy place. The legends say it is guarded by the Ancient Ones, who block the path of all who are unworthy.
 
Your reputation here does not matter…It will be the Ancients who determine your worthiness.
 
Good luck."

STATE:AfterInit

NAME:QualKehk
SPEED: 63
wave:act5\Qual-Kehk\qua_act5_q5_after.wav
"The Ancients are not our enemies. Remember that! They are our ancestors -- our gods."

NAME:Cain
SPEED: 90
wave:act5\cain\cain_act5_q5_after.wav
"A test of mettle is a fitting rite of passage for a Barbarian hero."

NAME:Anya
SPEED: 72
wave:act5\Anya\any_act5_q5_after.wav
"You wouldn't have to test yourself against the Ancients if it weren't for Nihlathak's treachery. He was a fool and deserves to suffer for eternity."

NAME:Larzuk
SPEED: 75
wave:act5\larzuk\lar_act5_q5_after.wav
"Every night, I've prayed to the Ancients to bring us peace…and now you must fight them.
 
Huh…Who shall I pray to now, warrior?" 

NAME:Malah
SPEED: 65
wave:act5\malah\mal_act5_q5_after.wav
"By reaching the summit, you cease being just a simple warrior. When you come back, you will be far more."



STATE:EarlyReturn

NAME:QualKehk
SPEED: 114
wave:act5\qual-kehk\qua_act5_q5_early.wav
"I warned you!
 
The Ancients are not like the demons you're accustomed to fighting." 

NAME:Cain
SPEED: 52
wave:act5\cain\cain_act5_q5_early.wav
"We have come too far to be defeated now, my friend. I have seen you complete many difficult quests. Though this may be your greatest trial, it is not beyond your reach."

NAME:Anya
SPEED: 71
wave:act5\Anya\any_act5_q5_early.wav
"Look. I must apologize.
 
I feel responsible for your current struggle. If I had only stopped Nihlathak from giving Baal the Relic, you would not have to fight those ghosts."

NAME:Larzuk
SPEED: 70
wave:act5\larzuk\lar_act5_q5_early.wav
"You've walked on the burial grounds of our greatest ancestors. I'm not sure whether I should bow before you or revile you for committing sacrilege.
 
Tread lightly when you walk with gods."

NAME:Malah
SPEED: 68
wave:act5\malah\mal_act5_q5_early.wav
"Do not doubt yourself. I believe you are worthy to pass through the Ancients' gates, but you must believe, as well."


STATE:Successful

NAME:QualKehk
SPEED: 75
wave:act5\qual-kehk\qua_act5_q5_successful.wav
"Besting the Ancients in battle is a mighty feat indeed. I hope this means you're ready to battle Baal."

NAME:Cain
SPEED: 67
wave:act5\cain\cain_act5_q5_successful.wav
"You have proven yourself to these people. They look to you as their warrior, their champion."

NAME:Anya
SPEED: 82
wave:act5\Anya\any_act5_q5_successful.wav
"You stand before me a worthy hero -- and on you rests the last hope of our people.
 
Bear it well, warrior."

NAME:Larzuk
SPEED: 82
wave:act5\larzuk\lar_act5_q5_successful.wav
// changed 3/6/2001 msh
"The Ancients have honored you, and in turn, so do we. I have no remaining doubts about you, now."

NAME:Malah
wave:act5\malah\mal_act5_q5_successful.wav
SPEED: 60
"I knew the Ancients would find you worthy of Mount Arreat's secrets. Now, stop Baal before he destroys all that is sacred."

//Quest 5.6: Eve of Destruction
QUEST:A5Q6

STATE:Init

NAME:Ancients
SPEED: 31
wave:act5\ancients\anc_act5_q6_init.wav
"You are a worthy hero! We augment your skill and grant you entry to the interior of Mount Arreat, wherein lies the Worldstone.
 
Beware. You will not be alone. Baal the Lord of Destruction is already inside. 
 
The Archangel Tyrael has always been our benefactor, but even he cannot help us now. For Baal blocks Tyrael's spiritual presence from entering the chamber of the Worldstone. Only you, mortal, have the power to defeat Baal now.
 
Baal threatens the Worldstone -- and through it, the mortal realm, itself. You must stop him before he gains full control of the sacred stone. With it under his control, Baal could shatter the boundaries between this world and the Burning Hells, thus allowing the hordes of the Prime Evils to pour forth into the mortal realm like an unstoppable tide!
 
If you are weak, the world as you know it could be lost forever. You must NOT fail!"


STATE:EarlyReturn

NAME:Cain
SPEED: 51
wave:act5\cain\cain_act5_q6_early.wav
"Remember this. Baal once possessed Tal Rasha, one of the most powerful of the ancient Horadrim.
 
Your battles with Mephisto and Diablo will pale in comparison to your battle with Baal.
 
The Lord of Destruction aided by Tal Rasha's knowledge…The mountain itself will tremble when you clash."

NAME:Larzuk
SPEED: 59
wave:act5\larzuk\lar_act5_q6_early.wav
"I may be just an armorer, but I know this…Baal plans to destroy the world with the secrets contained in that mountain. It doesn't take a genius to know he has to be stopped."

NAME:Malah
SPEED: 70
wave:act5\malah\mal_act5_q6_early.wav
"You knew it would eventually come down to this. Kill Baal! Finish the game!"

NAME:Anya
SPEED: 60
wave:act5\Anya\any_act5_q6_early.wav
"Baal has blocked Tyrael from entering the Worldstone Chamber? This truly has become a battle against Hell.
 
Whether or not it was the Heavens' decree, this is your fight now -- your destiny."

NAME:QualKehk
SPEED: 63
wave:act5\qual-kehk\qua_act5_q6_early.wav
"You have ventured to a place beyond legend. You rush to face an evil few can even imagine.
 
Be careful, my friend, and may the Light watch over you."


STATE: Successful

NAME:Tyrael
SPEED: 40
wave:act5\Tyrael\tyr_act5_quest6_successful.wav
"I am impressed, mortal. You have overcome the greatest challenge this world has ever faced and defeated the last of the Prime Evils. However, we are too late to save the Worldstone. Baal's destructive touch has corrupted it completely.
 
Given enough time, the Worldstone's energies will drain away and the barriers between the worlds will shatter -- the powers of Hell will flood into this…Sanctuary…and eradicate your people and everything you've labored to build.
 
Therefore, I must destroy the corrupted Worldstone before the powers of Hell take root. This act will change your world forever -- with consequences even I cannot foresee. However, it is the only way to ensure mankind's survival.
 
Go now, mortal. I have opened a portal that will lead you to safety.
 
May the Eternal Light shine upon you and your descendants for what you've done this day. The continued survival of mankind is your legacy! Above all else, you have earned a rest from this endless battle."

NAME:Anya
SPEED: 53
wave:act5\Anya\any_act5_q6_successful.wav
"You have done the impossible, hero. Your defeat of the last of the three Prime Evils is a great victory for the Light. 
 
Strange that you say that the Worldstone must be destroyed. The prophecies said nothing about that.
 
Perhaps all we have fought for will be lost…or perhaps we'll never need fight again!"

NAME:Cain
SPEED: 40
wave:act5\cain\cain_act5_q6_successful.wav
"I knew in time you would defeat Baal. You have done everything you set out to do, my friend.
 
Ever since you rescued me from Tristram, I have believed in you. It has been a supreme honor to aid you along the way. 
 
So…The Worldstone was corrupted by Baal. And now Tyrael must destroy it. Worry not. Through whatever lies ahead I have faith that the Light will guide us both.
 
Go, now, back to the Worldstone chamber, and enter the portal Tyrael has opened for you."

NAME:Larzuk
SPEED: 74
wave:act5\larzuk\lar_act5_q6_successful.wav
"The Ancients themselves will envy our songs about you.
 
Please, don't forget about us! Farewell, my friend."


NAME:Malah
SPEED: 48
wave:act5\malah\mal_act5_q6_successful.wav
"If Tyrael says the Worldstone must be destroyed, then it must. We cannot let Baal's corruption prevail!
 
The world will change, true -- but who is to say it isn't for the better?"

NAME:QualKehk
SPEED: 60
wave:act5\qual-kehk\qua_act5_q6_successful.wav
"The destruction of the Worldstone does not bode well for our world. But I'll try not to worry…
 
After all, we have warriors like you fighting for us and for the Light.
 
Farewell!"

//end
Diablo II		NPC Script

02/08/01	All contents copyright © 2000 by BLIZZARD NORTH	Page 44

