D2bnetHelp50, strD2bnetHelp50, "CHAT HELP"
D2bnetHelp, strD2bnetHelp, "CHAT COMMANDS"
D2bnetHelp2a, strD2bnetHelp2a, "To select a Character, left-click on the Character portrait to highlight it with an aura. To deselect any highlighted character, left-click on their portrait."

D2bnetHelpa, strD2bnetHelpa, "The buttons located under the Chat Window on the left side of the screen have the following functions:"

D2bnetHelp1, strD2bnetHelp1, "SEND displays your message to everyone in your chat Channel, regardless of what character portrait is currently selected. This button is activated as soon as you start typing in the Text Box."

D2bnetHelp2, strD2bnetHelp2, "WHISPER sends your message only to the character that you have selected. This button is activated as soon as you start typing in the Text Box and have another character selected."

D2bnetHelp3, strD2bnetHelp3, "SQUELCH filters out incoming messages from the character that you have selected. Characters that you have squelched are marked with a red X graphic. This button is activated as soon as you select another character."

D2bnetHelp4, strD2bnetHelp4, "UNSQUELCH allows you to again receive incoming messages from a character that has been squelched." 

D2bnetHelp5, strD2bnetHelp5, "EMOTE lets you perform an action that the whole room can <see> as represented through text." 
D2bnetHelp5a, strD2bnetHelp5a, "For example, if Doomhammer wants to greet all the players in the chat Channel, he could type, <waves hello.> and then click the EMOTE button. Everyone in the Channel will then receive the message, <Doomhammer waves hello.> This button is activated as soon as you start typing in the Text Box."

D2bnetHelp6, strD2bnetHelp6, "ÿc5Gray Textÿc4 indicates when someone Joins or Leaves the chat Channel."
D2bnetHelp7, strD2bnetHelp7, "ÿc7Gold Textÿc4 indicates the name of the player speaking."
D2bnetHelp8, strD2bnetHelp8, "ÿc0White Textÿc4 indicates what you or others have said out loud to the entire chat Channel."
D2bnetHelp9, strD2bnetHelp9, "ÿc2Green Textÿc4 indicates what you have <whispered> to a specific person, or any message that has been <whispered> to you, in the chat Channel." 
D2bnetHelp10, strD2bnetHelp10, "ÿc3Blue Textÿc4 represents actions that have been taken by people in the chat Channel or special messages sent directly from battle.net."
D2bnetHelp11, strD2bnetHelp11, "ÿc1Red Textÿc4 represents error messages sent directly from battle.net."

D2bnetHelp36, strD2bnetHelp36, "THE DIALOGUE WINDOW"
D2bnetHelp36a, strD2bnetHelp36a, "This window on the right side of the screen is used to display and enter both game and profile information. Unlike the Chat Window, this area changes depending on what function you have activated. The buttons for these functions are discussed in detail in the following section:"
 
D2bnetHelp37, strD2bnetHelp37, "CREATE"
D2bnetHelp37a, strD2bnetHelp37a, "Lets you form a new game for other players to join. There are several choices listed below that you need to make when creating a new game, although many of them are optional."

D2bnetHelp38, strD2bnetHelp38, "Game Name is how you want your game to be displayed in the Join Game screen. It can be cryptic or descriptive, although certain words and names are restricted."

D2bnetHelp39, strD2bnetHelp39, "Password gives you the option to make your game Private. Other players who wish to join your game will need to know the password you have selected." 

D2bnetHelp40, strD2bnetHelp40, "Game Description lets you say something about the game you are forming. This is a good way to advertise for the kind of player or character you want to join your game."

D2bnetHelp41, strD2bnetHelp41, "Maximum Number of Players sets a limit as to how many characters can be in your game at any one time. The default setting is 4. You can change the number of players, up to a maximum of 8, by clicking the Up or Down arrows next to the box."

D2bnetHelp42, strD2bnetHelp42, "Character Difference sets a range above and below the level of your character that other characters joining your game must fall into. The default setting is set at 4 to determine who can join your game."
 
D2bnetHelp42a, strD2bnetHelp42a, "To set no level restrictions, click the check box next to this option. The displayed number 4 means that any character joining your game must be within 4 levels of your character. You can change the level difference by clicking the Up or Down arrows next to the box."

D2bnetHelp43, strD2bnetHelp43, "Normal, Nightmare and Hell sets the difficulty levels at which you can play. The default setting is Normal. Characters must meet certain requirements to start games with the Nightmare and Hell difficulties. Until those requirements are met, these options will be non-selectable."

D2bnetHelp44, strD2bnetHelp44, "JOIN"
D2bnetHelp44ab, strD2bnetHelp44b, "Lets you enter an existing game. Games that are listed in this screen are considered Public and can be can be joined any time they have space for a player within them." 
D2bnetHelp44a, strD2bnetHelp44a, "Selecting a game from this list will display information on the game, including the characters and the elapsed time of the game. To join a Private game, you will be required to enter the name of the game and its assigned password."

D2bnetHelp45, strD2bnetHelp45, "CHANNEL" 
D2bnetHelp45b, strD2bnetHelp45b, "Lets you join an existing chat Channel or gives you the opportunity to create a Channel of your own. To enter an established Public Channel, select one from the Channels list and click the OK button. To enter a Private Channel, you will need to enter the name of the Channel that you wish to enter." 
D2bnetHelp45a, strD2bnetHelp45a, "If you wish to start your own Channel, enter the name of the Channel that you wish to create in the Channel Name Field. If this channel does not exist, you will automatically create that Channel."

D2bnetHel46, strD2bnetHelp46, "LADDER"
D2bnetHelp46a, strD2bnetHelp46a, "Allows you to view your character's ranking in the Diablo II Ladders for your Realm."

D2bnetHelp47, strD2bnetHelp47, "The STANDARD LADDER displays the top characters, ranked by experience. The default setting displays overall rankings, but you can view sorted lists after selecting the By Class option."

D2bnetHelp48, strD2bnetHelp48, "The HARDCORE LADDER displays the top Hardcore characters, ranked by experience. The default setting displays overall rankings, but you can view sorted lists after selecting By Class option."

D2bnetHelp49, strD2bnetHelp49, "QUIT closes the Battle.net chat interface and returns you to the Character Selection screen. Although you are still connected to Battle.net, you cannot chat or start games until you have selected a character."

D2bnetHelp12, strD2bnetHelp12, "ADVANCED COMMANDS"
D2bnetHelp12c, strD2bnetHelp12c, "When using advanced commands, you must use battle.net account names; referencing Diablo II character names will not work." 

D2bnetHelp12b, strD2bnetHelp12b, "To find the account name associated with a character, hold your mouse over that character or access the Character Profile by right clicking the character portrait."

D2bnetHelp12a, strD2bnetHelp12a, "You can access any of these advanced features by entering the following commands in the Text Box where you normally type messages:"

D2bnetHelp13, strD2bnetHelp13, "/whisper <accountname>, /w <accountname>" 
D2bnetHelp13b, strD2bnetHelp13b, "/msg <accountname>, /m <accountname>"
D2bnetHelp13a, strD2bnetHelp13a, "Sends a private message to another user on battle.net"

D2bnetHelp14, strD2bnetHelp14, "/me, /emote"
D2bnetHelp14a, strD2bnetHelp14a, "Allows you to perform an action in the chat room." 

D2bnetHelp15, strD2bnetHelp15, "/squelch <accountname>"
D2bnetHelp15b, strD2bnetHelp15b, "/ignore <accountname>"
D2bnetHelp15a, strD2bnetHelp15a, "Allows you to ignore messages from the indicated user." 

D2bnetHelp16, strD2bnetHelp16, "/unsquelch <accountname>"
D2bnetHelp16b, strD2bnetHelp16b, "/unignore <accountname>"
D2bnetHelp16a, strD2bnetHelp16a, "Allows you to again receive messages from this user." 

D2bnetHelp17, strD2bnetHelp17, "/away <reason>"
D2bnetHelp17a, strD2bnetHelp17a, "Lets other people who send you messages know that you are away from your keyboard and cannot respond. You may provide a reason for your absence, by typing it after the /away command. To turn off this auto message when you return to your keyboard, enter just /away by itself."

D2bnetHelp18, strD2bnetHelp18, "/dnd" 
D2bnetHelp18a, strD2bnetHelp18a, "Lets other people who send you messages know that you do not wish to be disturbed. You may provide a reason for your absence, by typing it after the /dnd command. To turn off this auto message when you return to your keyboard, enter just /dnd by itself."

D2bnetHelp19, strD2bnetHelp19, "/channel <channelname>, /join <channelname>"
D2bnetHelp19a, strD2bnetHelp19a, "Takes you to the battle.net Channel of your choice. If you wanted to enter the technical support Channel, you would simply type /channel technical support. If you attempt to join a Channel that does not exist, you will automatically create that Channel."

D2bnetHelp20, strD2bnetHelp20, "/who <channelname>"
D2bnetHelp20a, strD2bnetHelp20a, "Provides you with a list of the battle.net account names of the players that are currently in the requested battle.net Channel."

D2bnetHelp21, strD2bnetHelp21, "/ban <accountname>" 
D2bnetHelp21a, strD2bnetHelp21a, "Bans an account from entering a private Channel and can only be issued by the Channel operator. Use /unban <accountname> to allow accounts banned from a private Channel back into that Channel."

D2bnetHelp22, strD2bnetHelp22, "ctrl+c, ctrl+x ctrl+v"
D2bnetHelp22a, strD2bnetHelp22a, "Use these commands to copy, cut, and paste highlighted text. Use ctrl+a to select all text in the text field. Use ctrl+m to toggle music off/on. Use ctrl+n to paste the account name of a selected character." 

D2bnetHelp23, strD2bnetHelp23, "/designate <accountname>"
D2bnetHelp23a, strD2bnetHelp23a, "Designates the player of your choice to become the next Channel operator, which will take effect after the current Channel operator leaves the Channel and can only be issued by the current Channel operator." 

D2bnetHelp24, strD2bnetHelp24, "/kick <accountname>"
D2bnetHelp24a, strD2bnetHelp24a, "Kicks an account from a private Channel and can only be issued by the Channel operator. The kicked player, however, can immediately rejoin the channel." 

D2bnetHelp25, strD2bnetHelp25, "/rejoin, resign"
D2bnetHelp25a, strD2bnetHelp25a, "Causes a Channel operator to rejoin the Channel, appearing at the end/bottom of the list instead of the front/top of the list. Only the Channel operator can issue this command." 

D2bnetHelp26, strD2bnetHelp26, "/whois <accountname>, /where <accountname>"
D2bnetHelp26b, strD2bnetHelp26b, "/whereis <accountname>"
D2bnetHelp26a, strD2bnetHelp26a, "Searches for another player in all battle.net Public Chat channels and all Blizzard games, telling you their account name, account number and current location." 

D2bnetHelp27, strD2bnetHelp27, "/whoami"
D2bnetHelp27a, strD2bnetHelp27a, "Provides you with your current account number and location on battle.net." 

D2bnetHelp28, strD2bnetHelp28, "/d2notify"
D2bnetHelp28a, strD2bnetHelp28a, "Toggles battle.net Join/Leave notifications in the Chat Channel."

//This command is English only
D2bnetHelp29, strD2bnetHelp29, "/help, /?" 
D2bnetHelp29a, strD2bnetHelp29a, "Accesses the general battle.net help text." 
//battle.net and not client handles the response on this command.

D2bnetHelp30, strD2bnetHelp30, "/time"
D2bnetHelp30a, strD2bnetHelp30a, "Provides you with the current battle.net time and your current Local time."

D2bnetHelp31, strD2bnetHelp31, "/users"
D2bnetHelp31a, strD2bnetHelp31a, "Provides the number of users, games, and channels that are currently active across all of battle.net."

D2bnetHelp32, strD2bnetHelp32, "/stats <accountname> <programID>"
D2bnetHelp32a, strD2bnetHelp32a, "Provides you with the Ladder statistics for other Blizzard games supported over battle.net. The program ID for each game is as follows; StarCraft < STAR>, Brood War <STARX>, and Warcraft II: battle.net Edition <W2BN>."

D2bnetHelp33, strD2bnetHelp33, "Right-clicking on your own character allows you to edit your own profile."

D2bnetHelp34, strD2bnetHelp34, "Using the 'Tab' key in the battle.net chat room cycles through the last 10 commands you have issued."

D2bnetHelp35, strD2bnetHelp35, "If you need further help, please go to the TECHNICAL SUPPORT Channel on battle.net, consult the Diablo II manual or go to the Blizzard technical support page at http://www.blizzard.com/support/"

D2bnetHelp51, strD2bnetHelp51, "BATTLE.NET COMMANDS"
D2bnetHelp52, strD2bnetHelp52, "/whisper"
D2bnetHelp53, strD2bnetHelp53, "/me"
D2bnetHelp54, strD2bnetHelp54, "/away"
D2bnetHelp55, strD2bnetHelp55, "/squelch, /unsquelch"
D2bnetHelp56, strD2bnetHelp56, "/ban, /unban, /kick"
D2bnetHelp57, strD2bnetHelp57, "/channel"
D2bnetHelp58, strD2bnetHelp58, "/whois, /where, /whoami"
D2bnetHelp59, strD2bnetHelp59, "/d2notify"
D2bnetHelp60, strD2bnetHelp60, "/designate, /rejoin"
D2bnetHelp61, strD2bnetHelp61, "/time"
D2bnetHelp62, strD2bnetHelp62, "/who, /users" 
D2bnetHelp63, strD2bnetHelp63, "/stats"
