//DIABLO II
//ACT I: The Sightless Eye
//SECTION:GREETINGS
//Kashya Greetings
//act1\kashya\kas_hello.wav
//"Hello."
//act1\kashya\kas_greetings.wav
//"Greetings."
//act1\kashya\kas_yes.wav
//"Yes?"
//act1\kashya\kas_goodmorning.wav
//"Good morning."
//act1\kashya\kas_goodday.wav
//"Good day."
//act1\kashya\kas_goodevening.wav
//"Good evening."
//act1\kashya\kas_havenews.wav
//"I have news for you."
//act1\kashya\kas_havequest.wav
//"I have a quest for you."
//act1\kashya\kas_havereward.wav
//"I have a reward for you!"
//act1\kashya\kas_sisterhoodwelcomesyou.wav
//"The Sisterhood welcomes you."
//act1\kashya\kas_helloagainoutlander.wav
//"Hello again, outlander. Word of your great exploits in the east has reached us, even here."
//Akara Greetings
//act1\akara\aka_hello.wav
//"Hello."
//act1\akara\aka_greetings.wav
//"Greetings."
//act1\akara\aka_yes.wav
//"Yes?"
//act1\akara\aka_goodmorning.wav
//"Good morning."
//act1\akara\aka_goodday.wav
//"Good day."
//act1\akara\aka_goodevening.wav
//"Good evening."
//act1\akara\aka_havenews.wav
//"I have news for you."
//act1\akara\aka_havequest.wav
//"I have a quest for you."
//act1\akara\aka_havereward.wav
//"I have a reward for you!"
//act1\akara\aka_orderwelcomes.wav
//"The Order welcomes you."
//act1\akara\aka_welcomeback.wav
//"Welcome back, my friend. We are still clearing the monastery, but you're welcome to stay here as long as you need."
//Charsi Greetings
//act1\charsi\cha_hello.wav
//"Hello."
//act1\charsi\cha_greetings.wav
//"Greetings."
//act1\charsi\cha_yes.wav
//"Yes?"
//act1\charsi\cha_goodmorning.wav
//"Good morning."
//act1\charsi\cha_goodday.wav
//"Good day."
//act1\charsi\cha_goodevening.wav
//"Good evening."
//act1\charsi\cha_havenews.wav
//"I have news for you."
//act1\charsi\cha_havequest.wav
//"I have a quest for you."
//act1\charsi\cha_havereward.wav
//"I have a reward for you!"
//act1\charsi\cha_goodtoseeyou.wav
//"Good to see you!"
//act1\charsi\cha_whatchaneed.wav
//"What'cha need?"
//act1\charsi\cha_whatcanidoforyou.wav
//"What can I do for ya?"
//act1\charsi\cha_heythere.wav
//"Oh, hi there. It's good to see you again. Hey, nice armor!"
//Warriv Greetings
//common\warriv\war_hello.wav
//"Hello."
//common\warriv\war_greetings.wav
//"Greetings."
//common\warriv\war_yes.wav
//"Yes?"
//common\warriv\war_goodmorning.wav
//"Good morning."
//common\warriv\war_goodday.wav
//"Good day."
//common\warriv\war_goodevening.wav
//"Good evening."
//common\warriv\war_havenews.wav
//"I have news for you."
//common\warriv\war_havequest.wav
//"I have a quest for you."
//common\warriv\war_havereward.wav
//"I have a reward for you!"
//common\warriv\war_presencehonorsme.wav
//"Your presence honors me."
//common\warriv\war_wherecanitakeyou.wav
//"Where can I take you?"
//Gheed Greetings
//act1\gheed\ghe_hello.wav
//"Hello."
//act1\gheed\ghe_greetings.wav
//"Greetings."
//act1\gheed\ghe_yes.wav
//"Yes?"
//act1\gheed\ghe_goodmorning.wav
//"Good morning."
//act1\gheed\ghe_goodday.wav
//"Good day."
//act1\gheed\ghe_goodevening.wav
//"Good evening."
//act1\gheed\ghe_havenews.wav
//"I have news for you."
//act1\gheed\ghe_havequest.wav
//"I have a quest for you."
//act1\gheed\ghe_havereward.wav
//"I have a reward for you!"
//act1\gheed\ghe_whatchaneed.wav
//"What do you need?"
//act1\gheed\ghe_mayihelpyou.wav
//"May I help you?"
//act1\gheed\ghe_letsdeal.wav
//"Let's deal, my friend."
//act1\gheed\ghe_goodtoseeyou.wav
//"Good to see you again. Since the Rogues have been moving back into their monastery, they haven't been buying anything from me!"
//Cain Greetings
//common\cain\cain_hello.wav
//"Hello."
//common\cain\cain_greetings.wav
//"Greetings."
//common\cain\cain_yes.wav
//"Yes?"
//common\cain\cain_goodmorning.wav
//"Good morning."
//common\cain\cain_goodday.wav
//"Good day."
//common\cain\cain_goodevening.wav
//"Good evening."
//common\cain\cain_havenews.wav
//"I have news for you."
//common\cain\cain_havequest.wav
//"I have a quest for you."
//common\cain\cain_havereward.wav
//"I have a reward for you!"
//common\cain\cain_goodtoseeyou.wav
//"Good to see you!"
//common\cain\cain_stayandlisten.wav
//"Stay a while and listen."
//common\cain\cain_youreturned.wav
//"You have returned!"
//Rogue Hireable Acknowledgements
//act1\rogue\rog_asyoucommand1.wav
//act1\rogue\rog_asyoucommand2.wav
//"As you command!"
//act1\rogue\rog_immediately1.wav
//act1\rogue\rog_immediately2.wav
//"Immediately."
//act1\rogue\rog_yes1.wav
//act1\rogue\rog_yes2.wav
//"Yes!"
//act1\rogue\rog_done1.wav
//act1\rogue\rog_done2.wav
//"Done."
//Rogue Hireable Get Hits and Death sfx
//"Uhnn!"
//"Arrrghh.."

//Blood Raven's taunts (said as player approaches in range)
//act1\monster\bloodraventaunt3.wav
//"Matron Andariel commands your death."
//act1\monster\bloodraventaunt2.wav
//"Join my army of the dead."
//act1\monster\bloodraventaunt1.wav
//"My army will destroy you!"

//Attacks, Get hits, Death

//Countess' taunts (Forgotten Tower) (said as player enters her chamber)
//act1\monster\countesstaunt1.wav
//"Here for a bloodbath? Hahaha…"
//act1\monster\countesstaunt2.wav
//"Your blood will boil!"

//Attacks, Get Hits, Death

//Smith's taunts (Horadric Malus) (said as player approaches)
//act1\monster\smithtaunt2.wav
//"Your soul shall fuel the Hell Forge."
//act1\monster\smithtaunt5.wav
//"I shall make weapons from your bones."

//Attacks, Get Hits, Death

//Andariel's Taunts
//act1\monster\andarieltaunt3.wav
//"The East is beyond your grasp."
//act1\monster\andarieltaunt1.wav
//"Die, maggot."
//act1\monster\andarieltaunt2.wav
//"Fear me!"

//Attacks, Get hits, Death

//Cain's Tristram sfx
//act1/Cain/Cain_help1.wav
//act1/Cain/Cain_help2.wav
//act1/Cain/Cain_help3.wav
//Various "Help!"  (hanging in midair)

SECTION:GOSSIP

//Warriv Intro Speech (players start new games near him... he is in Active Mode.)
NAME:WarrivAct1Intro
SPEED:45
wave:act1\warriv\war_act1_intro.wav
"Greetings, stranger. I'm not surprised to see your kind here. Many adventurers have traveled this way since the recent troubles began.
 
No doubt you've heard about the tragedy that befell the town of Tristram. Some say that Diablo, the Lord of Terror, walks the world again.
 
I don't know if I believe that, but a Dark Wanderer did travel this route a few weeks ago. He was headed east to the mountain pass guarded by the Rogue Monastery.
 
Maybe it's nothing, but evil seems to have trailed in his wake. You see, shortly after the Wanderer went through, the Monastery's Gates to the pass were closed and strange creatures began ravaging the countryside.
 
Until it's safer outside the camp and the gates are re-opened, I'll remain here with my caravan. I hope to leave for Lut Gholein before the shadow that fell over Tristram consumes us all.  If you're still alive then, I'll take you along.
 
You should talk to Akara, too. She seems to be the leader of this camp. Maybe she can tell you more."
NAME:WarrivAct1IntroPal
SPEED:45
wave:act1\warriv\war_act1_intro_pal.wav
"Well met, noble Paladin. It's been a while since I've seen any of your kind in the west. It would be an honor to aid you in any way that I can.
 
No doubt you've heard about the tragedy that befell the town of Tristram. Some say that Diablo, the Lord of Terror, walks the world again.
 
I don't know if I believe that, but a Dark Wanderer did travel this route a few weeks ago. He was headed east to the mountain pass guarded by the Rogue Monastery.
 
Maybe it's nothing, but evil seems to have trailed in his wake. You see, shortly after the Wanderer went through, the Monastery's Gates to the pass were closed and strange creatures began ravaging the countryside.
 
Until it's safer outside the camp and the gates are re-opened, I'll remain here with my caravan. I hope to leave for Lut Gholein before the shadow that fell over Tristram consumes us all.  If you're still alive then, I'll take you along.
 
You should talk to Akara, too. She seems to be the leader of this camp. Maybe she can tell you more."
NAME:Warriv
SPEED:51
//The next gossip is only for a Paladin.
wave:act1\warriv\war_act1_gossip_pal.wav
"I've been leading my trade caravan across the eastern deserts for more than twenty years now. I've been attacked by bandits and outlaws more times than I can remember. But never when a Paladin accompanied me. 
 
Indeed, your Order has saved me from losing a small fortune over the years. I just hope you can discover what's going on around here and get the Gates to the East opened up!"

//The following gossips are for any player class.
SPEED:85
wave:act1\warriv\war_act1_gossip_01.wav
"Cain seems to have great wisdom regarding the supernatural. I hope I never live to be that wise…"

SPEED:58
wave:act1\warriv\war_act1_gossip_02.wav
"Akara is the Rogues' High Priestess. She sells the few magic items in her possession and can even heal your wounds. She is very wise and will help you if she can."

SPEED:66
wave:act1\warriv\war_act1_gossip_03.wav
"The fiery Kashya commands the Rogue archers in battle. I've only spoken to her a few times, though. I get the feeling that she doesn't like outsiders very much."

SPEED:88
wave:act1\warriv\war_act1_gossip_04.wav
"Charsi seems to be a very sweet girl. She's the smith around here and can help you by trading weapons and armor."

SPEED:55
wave:act1\warriv\war_act1_gossip_05.wav
"Gheed is a wandering merchant of questionable character who is traveling along with my caravan to the East. He will buy and sell most anything.
 
He's greedy, but his wares are beyond reproach. I would suggest keeping both eyes open when you deal with him."

SPEED:71
wave:act1\warriv\war_act1_gossip_06.wav
"To the east are lands of great mystery... and the Jewel City of the Desert, Lut Gholein."

SPEED:68
wave:act1\warriv\war_act1_gossip_07.wav
"I'll gladly take you eastward, if you can drive the Evil from the Monastery.  Then, the Rogues may re-open the pass through the mountains."

SPEED:70
wave:act1\warriv\war_act1_gossip_08.wav
"It's easy to become lost in the wilderness on the way to the Citadel. After you have come to the Cairn Stones, you must remember that the path continues through the caves."
NAME:AkaraIntro
SPEED:35
wave:act1\akara\aka_act1_intro.wav
"I am Akara, High Priestess of the Sisterhood of the Sightless Eye. I welcome you, traveler, to our camp, but I'm afraid I can offer you but poor shelter within these rickety walls.
 
You see, our ancient Sisterhood has fallen under a strange curse. The mighty Citadel from which we have guarded the gates to the East for generations, has been corrupted by the evil Demoness, Andariel.
 
I still can't believe it… but she turned many of our sister Rogues against us and drove us from our ancestral home. Now the last defenders of the Sisterhood are either dead or scattered throughout the wilderness.
 
I implore you, stranger. Please help us. Find a way to lift this terrible curse and we will pledge our loyalty to you for all time."
NAME:AkaraIntroSor
SPEED:34
wave:act1\akara\aka_act1_intro_sor.wav
"Greetings, young Sorceress. It is good to see more of your kind at work in the world these dark days. In my opinion, the world needs more women to fight against the great shadow. But I am forgetting my manners… 
 
I am Akara, High Priestess of the Sisterhood of the Sightless Eye. I welcome you, traveler, to our camp, but I'm afraid I can offer you but poor shelter within these rickety walls.
 
You see, our ancient Sisterhood has fallen under a strange curse. The mighty Citadel from which we have guarded the gates to the East for generations, has been corrupted by the evil Demoness, Andariel.
 
I still can't believe it… but she turned many of our sister Rogues against us and drove us from our ancestral home. Now the last defenders of the Sisterhood are either dead or scattered throughout the wilderness.
 
I implore you, stranger: please help us. Find a way to lift this terrible curse and we will pledge our loyalty to you for all time."
NAME:Akara
SPEED:42
//This gossip is given only to a Sorceress.
wave:act1\akara\aka_act1_gossip_sor.wav 
"The Sisterhood of the Sightless Eye has a long and distinguished history. Over the generations our Order has become a deadly fighting force as well as a bastion for women who sought to forge their own destiny.
 
Yet beware, young one, the lure of power and knowledge can lead to disaster. I have seen ambition foul the bravest of hearts and recklessness dull hard-won wisdom.
 
You would do well to tread lightly upon the dark path you have chosen to explore."

//The following gossips are for any player class.
SPEED:49
wave:act1\akara\aka_act1_gossip_01.wav
"I understand that Cain is the last descendant of the ancient Horadrim and that his knowledge of their lore is vast. He could prove to be very useful in discerning the nature of our current crisis."

SPEED:49
wave:act1\akara\aka_act1_gossip_02.wav
"Kashya has always been fiercely loyal, but I fear her anger and frustration over these recent events will lead her into harm's way. She is highly protective of the few Rogues remaining under her command and will not send them into combat unless there is dire need."

SPEED:46
wave:act1\akara\aka_act1_gossip_03.wav
"Charsi is young and innocent. However, I believe her Barbarian blood thrills to the prospect of adventure and danger. She takes great pride in her work and finds comfort in the fact that her weapons and armor are helping to end this evil plague."

SPEED:48
wave:act1\akara\aka_act1_gossip_04.wav
"Though he has only been our guest for a short time, I sense that Warriv has faced many harrowing trials. Though he knows, as I do, that a terrible evil has blanketed the land, his only real concern is to reach the eastern trading ports with his caravan."

SPEED:53
wave:act1\akara\aka_act1_gossip_05.wav
"To be honest, I have done my best to stay clear of Gheed. He wears dishonesty about himself like a cloak and seeks only to better his situation by preying on the misfortunes of others."

SPEED:55
wave:act1\akara\aka_act1_gossip_06.wav
"The wilderness is overrun with Evil and the minions of Hell have taken our rightful home. We must purge all Evil from the Monastery and restore order to the world."

SPEED:53
wave:act1\akara\aka_act1_gossip_07.wav
"I often dream of the day we reclaim our own. The Sightless Eye sees through the mist of time a great glory ahead, but how far ahead the Eye cannot discern."

SPEED:67
wave:act1\akara\aka_act1_gossip_08.wav
"Our mental discipline is matched only by our skill in archery... I only hope these are enough to withstand this awful trial."

SPEED:59
wave:act1\akara\aka_act1_gossip_09.wav
"Beware that you do not suffer the fate of the corrupted Rogues. To lose one's life is a tragedy, but to lose one's soul is even worse."

SPEED:41
wave:act1\akara\aka_act1_gossip_10.wav
"Even though the corrupted ones were once of our Order, you need not shy from slaying them, for they stand between you and Andariel.
 
Perhaps, when the Demon Queen is dead, our Sisters will return to life, but more likely they will be forever bound to their unholy pact."
NAME:KashyaIntro
SPEED:56
wave:act1\kashya\kas_act1_intro.wav
"Welcome, outlander, to our glorious hovel. I know you're here to challenge the evil that's driven us from our ancestral home.
 
But, know this. Akara may be our spiritual leader, but I command the Rogues in battle. It will take more than just killing a few beasts in the wilderness to earn my trust."
NAME:KashyaIntroAma
SPEED:55
wave:act1\kashya\kas_act1_intro_ama.wav
"Well, well, I never expected to see an Amazon in these lands. You're very brave to have come here. Many of my fellow Sisters have fallen under some dark spell, and if you're not careful you may fall prey to it as well."
NAME:Kashya
SPEED:60
//The next gossip is only for an Amazon.
wave:act1\kashya\kas_act1_gossip_ama.wav
"When I was very young, Akara told me tales of the Amazons' fearlessness in battle and of their skills with spears and bows. I like to think we Rogues have much in common with you Amazons."

//The following gossips are for any player class.
SPEED:64
wave:act1\kashya\kas_act1_gossip_01.wav
"Some of my Rogues told me of Deckard Cain. They said that he is a man of great wisdom. Personally, I don't know how wise he could possibly be if he never learned how to wage battle himself."

SPEED:57
wave:act1\kashya\kas_act1_gossip_02.wav
"Akara has been like a mother to me for as long as I can remember. She is wise and good, but I don't think she has the steel to retake our Monastery by force."

SPEED:89
wave:act1\kashya\kas_act1_gossip_03.wav
"I don't trust many outlanders, but Warriv seems fine. He never says much to me, though."

SPEED:66
wave:act1\kashya\kas_act1_gossip_04.wav
"Before our exile, Charsi, our blacksmith, could fashion any implement of war.
 
Here in the camp, she merely makes do. Her best tools remain within the Monastery." 

SPEED:58
wave:act1\kashya\kas_act1_gossip_05.wav
"Gheed is a pig. I've been tempted to throw him out of the camp many times, but Charsi seems to think that he's good company. I don't trust the man, but if she's comforted by him, then I'll desist."

SPEED:76
wave:act1\kashya\kas_act1_gossip_06.wav
"If we could only find out how Andariel has managed to corrupt our Sisters, then, perhaps, we could drive out the evil clouding their minds."

SPEED:68
wave:act1\kashya\kas_act1_gossip_07.wav
"In this camp, those of us who have remained true to our Order are forced to live among common traders and farm animals.
 
Welcome to our circle of suffering."

SPEED:67
wave:act1\kashya\kas_act1_gossip_08.wav
"Perhaps Tristram deserved its fate... for letting Evil loose upon the land. I only hope we don't suffer the same."

SPEED:71
wave:act1\kashya\kas_act1_gossip_09.wav
"Some evenings we gather at the bonfire to retell epic tales... and try to forget about the terrible events that led to losing the Monastery."
NAME:CharsiIntro
SPEED:47
wave:act1\charsi\cha_act1_intro.wav
"Hi there. I'm Charsi, the blacksmith here in camp. It's good to see some strong adventurers around here.
 
Many of our Sisters fought bravely against Diablo when he first attacked the town of Tristram. They came back to us true veterans, bearing some really powerful items. Seems like their victory was short-lived, though… Most of them are now corrupted by Andariel."
NAME:CharsiIntroBar
SPEED:54
wave:act1\charsi\cha_act1_intro_bar.wav
"Wow. You're a Barbarian, huh? It's really great to meet you. I've seen a few of your kind around here lately. I'm a little jealous… I wish I could go off adventuring with you.
 
Oh, by the way… I'm Charsi, the blacksmith here in camp."
NAME:Charsi
SPEED:57
//The next gossip is only for a Barbarian.
wave:act1\charsi\cha_act1_gossip_bar.wav
"You know, I've been with the Sisters for as long as I can remember. But Akara told me that my real parents were Barbarians from the northern tribes and that they were killed when I was very young.
 
Sometimes I wonder what my life would have been like if I had been raised as a Barbarian.
 
I don't know. I love being a blacksmith… but sometimes I just want to get out and explore the world, you know?"

//The following gossips are for any player class.
SPEED:86
wave:act1\charsi\cha_act1_gossip_01.wav
"I don't really know anything about Cain. He seems to have a lot of secrets… That makes me nervous."

SPEED:51
wave:act1\charsi\cha_act1_gossip_02.wav
"Oh, Kashya's fantastic. Sure, she's a little hard on outsiders, but who can blame her? All she wants is to protect our Order. But now that our Sisters have turned against us… I think this whole mess has hardened her heart."

SPEED:64
wave:act1\charsi\cha_act1_gossip_03.wav
"Akara, our priestess and seer, is most upset by the corruption of our Sisters. I fear that she blames herself."

SPEED:80
wave:act1\charsi\cha_act1_gossip_04.wav
"Warriv's all right, I guess. He seems too serious most of the time. I haven't really talked to him all that much."

SPEED:60
wave:act1\charsi\cha_act1_gossip_05.wav
"Oh, I like Gheed. He's very funny. He has all sorts of interesting stories from the places he's been. I wish I could see the sights he has."

SPEED:84
wave:act1\charsi\cha_act1_gossip_06.wav
"I don't know why some of my Sisters chose to follow Andariel. Those who strayed were among our finest warriors."
NAME:GheedIntro
SPEED:48
wave:act1\gheed\ghe_act1_intro.wav
"Good day to you partner! I'm Gheed and I can already tell that I'll be your best friend in this forsaken camp.
 
A spare weapon, some gold, a small gem is all I want in exchange for the equipment you'll need on whatever quests you might undertake.
 
Now, now, now… Don't be shy, all of my items are guaranteed for life and come with a two-day warranty!"
NAME:GheedIntroNec
//Gheed fears and mistrusts Necromancers. He doesn't want to become involved either.
SPEED:46
wave:act1\gheed\ghe_act1_intro_nec.wav
"A Necromancer! I hoped I'd never have to lay my eyes on one of your kind again. … The recent troubles in this area have brought out all kinds, I see. Nevertheless, your money's good...
 
A spare weapon, some gold, a small gem is all I want in exchange for the equipment you'll need on whatever quests you might undertake!
 
Now, now, now… Don't be shy, all of my items are guaranteed for life and come with a two-day warranty!"
NAME:Gheed
//The next gossip is only for a Necromancer.
SPEED:74
wave:act1\gheed\ghe_act1_gossip_nec.wav 
"Don't think you can fool me, Necromancer. I've seen what your kind can do. If you're involved in any of the evil out there, I don't even want to know. Trade quickly and be about your business!"

//The following gossips are for any player class.
SPEED:57
wave:act1\gheed\ghe_act1_gossip_01.wav
"That old coot, Cain, is as crazy as a wet Quill Rat. I hear he survived whatever happened in Tristram. Personally, I wouldn't trust a thing he has to say."

SPEED:55
wave:act1\gheed\ghe_act1_gossip_02.wav
"Akara and Kashya are Sisters in the Order of the Sightless Eye, but they are worlds apart. Akara is a slow river of magic, and Kashya, a viper of war. They're both deeply devoted to their religious order, yet the corruption of their Sisters pains them both to no end."

SPEED:52
wave:act1\gheed\ghe_act1_gossip_03.wav
"Charsi is a fine girl…, but she has no business savvy! I know she means well, but the prices she charges for weapons and armor will never earn her a profit.
 
As long as I keep filling her mind with stories of adventure, she'll never catch on to the fact that I'm raking in gold hand over fist!"

SPEED:55
wave:act1\gheed\ghe_act1_gossip_04.wav
"Warriv was kind enough to let me travel with his caravan, but don't let him drag you into a search for a new Eastern trade route.
 
I'm making a fortune right here… from the Rogues, of course! You, on the other hand, always get my best prices!"

SPEED:61
wave:act1\gheed\ghe_act1_gossip_05.wav
"Andariel's demonic forces have taken up residence in the forests as well as the Monastery. Uh-uh. I won't be venturing out of the camp. So, if you need anything, I'll be right here."

SPEED:58
wave:act1\gheed\ghe_act1_gossip_06.wav
"When - or if - I get to Lut Gholein, I'm going to find the largest bowl of Narlant weed and smoke 'til all earthly sense has left my body."
NAME:Cain
SPEED:43
wave:act1\cain\cain_act1_gossip_01.wav
"Long ago, the Soulstones were given to the Horadrim by the Archangel Tyrael. They were used to bind the three Prime Evils. I now know that even these holy artifacts were no match for Diablo's power.
 
I hope that his two brothers are more securely held... but I fear the worst."

SPEED:54
wave:act1\cain\cain_act1_gossip_02.wav
"It takes time to master your skills... and use will hone your technique. But take care to choose your new skills wisely."

SPEED:52
wave:act1\cain\cain_act1_gossip_03.wav
"You may recover some mysterious things from the demons you kill. Some of great use to you... some of great peril! Bring them to me and I'll reveal their secrets."

SPEED:46
wave:act1\cain\cain_act1_gossip_04.wav
"Have I told you about the Horadrim? They were an ancient confederation of mage-clans who sought to bind the three Prime Evils for eternity. The Horadrim are now nearly forgotten... and it appears that the bonds they wove are unravelling!
 
As the last of the Horadrim, I pray that I can help you remedy their failure."
//Only active after A1Q6 has been given. (>=Q6)
SPEED:43
wave:act1\cain\cain_act1_gossip_aftera1q6init.wav
"Long ago, Diablo and his brothers were cast out of Hell by the Lesser Evils. It seems that Hell's balance has shifted, as Andariel is now aligned with the Lord of Terror. Her presence here in the mortal realm does not bode well for us."

//Rogue Signpost Warnings (aka forestfairy)
//Called 'Geldel' in game
NAME: RogueSignpost
//If Den of Evil has not been completed…
SPEED:90
wave:act1\rogue\rog_turnback.wav
"Turn back! I can tell that you need more experience to fight safely in the next wilderness."
SPEED:46
wave:act1\rogue\rog_completeakaraquest.wav
"Halt! You should complete Akara's quest before venturing further. Search for the Den in the wilderness closer to camp."

//If Den of Evil has been completed…
SPEED:116
wave:act1\rogue\rog_evilstrong.wav
"Beware! The evil is strong ahead."
SPEED:92
wave:act1\rogue\rog_mortaldanger.wav
"Beware! Beyond lies mortal danger for the likes of you!"
SPEED:88
wave:act1\rogue\rog_wildernessahead.wav
"Take care! The Corrupted Rogues in the wilderness ahead are not to be trifled with."

SECTION:QUEST
//Quest 1.1: Den of Evil
QUEST:A1Q1
STATE:Init

NAME:Akara
SPEED:43
wave:act1\akara\aka_act1_q1_init.wav
"There is a place of great evil in the wilderness. Kashya's Rogue scouts have informed me that a cave nearby is filled with shadowy creatures and horrors from beyond the grave.
 
I fear that these creatures are massing for an attack against our encampment. If you are sincere about helping us, find the dark labyrinth and destroy the foul beasts.
 
May the Great Eye watch over you."
STATE:AfterInit 

NAME:Akara 
SPEED:46
wave:act1\akara\aka_act1_q1_after.wav
"I should add that many Rogue scouts have died in that horrible place. We cannot afford to lose any more. If you choose to enter that Den of Evil, you must do so alone."

NAME:Kashya 
SPEED:87
wave:act1\kashya\kas_act1_q1_after.wav
"The demons in that cave have claimed many of my finest archers. I wonder how you will fare!"

NAME:CharsiMain 
SPEED:95
wave:act1\charsi\cha_act1_q1_after_main.wav
"The beasts from the cave have begun to roam throughout the countryside. You'd better be careful out there."

NAME:CharsiAlt 
//unused
"You seem like a noble warrior. I hope you can help us."

NAME:Gheed 
SPEED:67
wave:act1\gheed\ghe_act1_q1_after.wav
"You're a brave soul! I'd sooner thrust my sacred scepter into the foulest, carbuncular trull than set one boot into that cave."

NAME:Warriv 
SPEED:122
wave:act1\warriv\war_act1_q1_after.wav
"One who seeks that cave, seeks death."
STATE:EarlyReturn

NAME:Akara 
SPEED:85
wave:act1\akara\aka_act1_q1_early.wav
"Your task is not complete until you have killed all the demons in that cave."

NAME:Kashya
SPEED:111
wave:act1\kashya\kas_act1_q1_early.wav
"You'd better come through on this. Your reputation depends on it."

NAME:Charsi 
SPEED:148
wave:act1\charsi\cha_act1_q1_early.wav
"You haven't cleared the cave, yet? Do you need anything?"

NAME:Gheed 
SPEED:73
wave:act1\gheed\ghe_act1_q1_early.wav
"Demons still befouling that cave, huh? I think you might need a new weapon."

NAME:Warriv 
SPEED:124
wave:act1\warriv\war_act1_q1_early.wav
"One who hesitates... does so with good reason."
STATE:Successful

NAME:Akara 
SPEED:65
wave:act1\akara\aka_act1_q1_successful.wav
"You have cleansed the Den of Evil. You've earned my trust and may yet restore my faith in humanity.
 
Your reward is training in the skill of your choice."

NAME:Kashya 
SPEED:74
wave:act1\kashya\kas_act1_q1_successful.wav
"Hmm. I'm surprised you survived that test, outlander. Go see Akara. She may reward you."

NAME:Charsi 
SPEED:94
wave:act1\charsi\cha_act1_q1_successful.wav
"You are truly brave and skillful...  Akara was worried about you."

NAME:Gheed 
SPEED:87
wave:act1\gheed\ghe_act1_q1_successful.wav
"The only good demon is a dead one, I say.
 
By the way, did you happen to find anything in that cave you'd like to sell?"

NAME:Warriv 
SPEED:120
wave:act1\warriv\war_act1_q1_successful.wav
"…That which does not kill you makes you stronger."

//Quest 1.2: The Sisters' Burial Grounds
QUEST:A1Q2
STATE:Init

NAME:Kashya 
SPEED:56
wave:act1\kashya\kas_act1_q2_init.wav
"My Rogue scouts have just reported an abomination in the Monastery graveyard!
 
Apparently, Andariel is not content to take only our living. Blood Raven, one of our finest captains in the battle against Diablo at Tristram, was also one of the first to be corrupted by Andariel.
 
Now, you'll find her in the Monastery graveyard raising our dead as zombies!
 
We cannot abide this defilement! If you are truly our ally, you will help us destroy her."
STATE:AfterInit

NAME:Kashya 
SPEED:80
wave:act1\kashya\kas_act1_q2_after.wav
"Death has done nothing to weaken Blood Raven's combat skills. If anything, she's more deadly than ever."

NAME:Charsi 
SPEED:99
wave:act1\charsi\cha_act1_q2_after.wav
"Blood Raven was the leader of a Rogue band that once fought Diablo at Tristram."

NAME:Gheed 
SPEED:94
wave:act1\gheed\ghe_act1_q2_after.wav
"I'm sorry… The undead are bad for trade. I have a strict no-return policy."

NAME:Akara 
SPEED:51
wave:act1\akara\aka_act1_q2_after.wav
"Blood Raven fought valiantly against Diablo in the catacombs beneath Tristram… She was never quite the same afterwards. It is now obvious she brought an evil influence back with her."

NAME:Warriv 
SPEED:140
wave:act1\warriv\war_act1_q2_after.wav
"Hmmm…
 
How can one kill what is already dead?"
STATE:EarlyReturn

NAME:Kashya 
SPEED:99
wave:act1\kashya\kas_act1_q2_early.wav
"Each moment you delay adds another undead Sister to Blood Raven's army."

NAME:Akara 
SPEED:70
wave:act1\akara\aka_act1_q2_early.wav
"If you fail to destroy Blood Raven, I fear that our Order will perish forever."

NAME:Charsi 
SPEED:68
wave:act1\charsi\cha_act1_q2_early.wav 
"Akara felt something was wrong even before Andariel descended upon us. She feared that Blood Raven had stumbled upon some evil force beneath Tristram.
 
I wish we had acted then..."

NAME:Gheed
SPEED:77
wave:act1\gheed\ghe_act1_q2_early.wav
"I wonder if that old gossip, Melra, is among the undead? Oh, she had dirt on everybody."

NAME:Warriv
SPEED:86
wave:act1\warriv\war_act1_q2_early.wav
"When the dead return to prey upon the living, it is a terror beyond understanding."
STATE:Successful

NAME:Kashya
SPEED:55
wave:act1\kashya\kas_act1_q2_successful.wav
"I can hardly believe that you've defeated Blood Raven!
 
Though she was once my closest friend, I pray that her tortured spirit remains banished forever.
 
You have earned my respect, stranger... and the allegiance of the Rogues. I have placed several of my best warriors at your disposal."

//changed 4/1/00
NAME:Akara
SPEED:122
wave:act1\akara\aka_act1_q2_successful.wav
"Andariel must be made to pay for her sacrilege!"

NAME:Charsi
SPEED:77
wave:act1\charsi\cha_act1_q2_successful.wav
"Kashya wishes to reward you for your defeat of Blood Raven. I thank you, too, even though Blood Raven was once my friend."

NAME:Gheed
SPEED:148
wave:act1\gheed\ghe_act1_q2_successful.wav
"Some of those gals weren't so nice the first time around."

NAME:Warriv 
SPEED:104
wave:act1\warriv\war_act1_q2_successful.wav
"You've done well, stranger. I hope all your efforts are worth it."

//Quest 1.4 The Cairn Stones
QUEST:A1Q4
STATE:Init

NAME:Akara 
SPEED:50
wave:act1\akara\aka_act1_q4_init.wav
"It is clear that we are facing an Evil difficult to comprehend, let alone combat.
 
There is only one Horadrim sage, schooled in the most arcane history and lore, who could advise us... His name is Deckard Cain.
 
You must go to Tristram and find him, my friend. I pray that he still lives."
STATE:AfterInitScroll

NAME:Kashya 
SPEED:90
wave:act1\kashya\kas_act1_q4_after_scroll.wav
"The bark of Inifuss holds mystical runes.
 
Akara can translate them... into our revenge!"

NAME:Akara 
SPEED:42
wave:act1\akara\aka_act1_q4_after_scroll.wav
"Tristram is too far to journey by foot...  Cain would likely be dead, when you arrived. However, there is a magical portal that will take you there instantly.
 
To open it, one must stand within the circle of Cairn Stones and touch them in a certain order. The proper order can be found in the runes written on the bark of the Tree of Inifuss.
 
You must find the sacred Tree of Inifuss and bring back its bark. I will translate the runes to unlock the Stones' mystic pattern."

NAME:Charsi 
SPEED:117
wave:act1\charsi\cha_act1_q4_after_scroll.wav
"If you bring back the bark of Inifuss, Akara will tell you how to get to Tristram."

NAME:Warriv 
SPEED:68
wave:act1\warriv\war_act1_q4_after_scroll.wav
"Months ago, I came across a few survivors from Tristram. They said that Cain had gone half-mad and could no longer distinguish fact from fantasy."

NAME:Gheed 
SPEED:98
wave:act1\gheed\ghe_act1_q4_after_scroll.wav
"I would sooner micturate in a tankard of my own ale than journey to Tristram!"
STATE:Instructions

NAME:Charsi 
SPEED:150
wave:act1\charsi\cha_act1_q4_instructions.wav
"Without the bark of Inifuss you can't find Cain."
STATE:EarlyReturnS

NAME:Akara 
SPEED:76
wave:act1\akara\aka_act1_q4_early_scroll.wav
"How will you find Cain without going to Tristram? Finding the Tree of Inifuss is the first step on your journey."

NAME:Kashya 
SPEED:96
wave:act1\kashya\kas_act1_q4_early_scroll.wav
"The Tree of Inifuss is hard to find, but you'll know it when you see it."

NAME:Gheed 
SPEED:99
wave:act1\gheed\ghe_act1_q4_early_scroll.wav
"Barking up the wrong tree, huh? You'll find it, just keep looking."

NAME:Warriv 
SPEED:70
wave:act1\warriv\war_act1_q4_early_scroll.wav 
"He who seeks that which cannot be found must look inside himself for further guidance… or look harder!"
STATE:SuccessfulScroll

NAME:Kashya 
SPEED:82
wave:act1\kashya\kas_act1_q4_successful_scroll.wav
"With this scroll you may open a portal back to Tristram. Only Akara can decipher its logic."

NAME:Charsi 
SPEED:168
wave:act1\charsi\cha_act1_q4_successful_scroll.wav
"Get this to Akara.
 
Only she can understand it."

NAME:Gheed 
SPEED:72
wave:act1\gheed\ghe_act1_q4_successful_scroll.wav
"Look, friend… I trade a lot of strange items, but I'm not going to start dealing in bark. Okay?"

NAME:Warriv 
SPEED:86
wave:act1\warriv\war_act1_q4_successful_scroll.wav
"This looks like gibberish to me. Akara may know what to make of it."
STATE:Instructions

NAME:Akara 
SPEED:64
wave:act1\akara\aka_act1_q4_instructions.wav
"Ah, very good. I have translated the runes on this scroll. You must find the Cairn Stones and touch them in the order that I have written."
STATE:EarlyReturn

NAME:Kashya 
SPEED:103
wave:act1\kashya\kas_act1_q4_early.wav
"Deckard Cain has crucial knowledge about the Evils we face. You must find him!"

NAME:Charsi 
SPEED:92
wave:act1\charsi\cha_act1_q4_early.wav
"I have heard that Tristram is now in ruins! Without Cain I fear for the ruin of all of us."

NAME:Gheed 
SPEED:68
wave:act1\gheed\ghe_act1_q4_early.wav
"I'm told that Tristram now resembles a mead hall… after a Barbarian wedding! I will wait here for your most glorious return."

NAME:Warriv 
SPEED:82
wave:act1\warriv\war_act1_q4_early.wav
"It is too dangerous to travel to Tristram. I won't be leaving here until the way is clear!"

NAME:Akara 
SPEED:64
wave:act1\akara\aka_act1_q4_early.wav
"If he still lives, Deckard Cain may be in grave peril! You must hurry to Tristram before all is lost!"
STATE:QuestSuccessful

NAME:Akara 
SPEED:82
wave:act1\akara\aka_act1_q4_successful.wav
"You have risked your life to rescue Cain. For that we thank you.
 
We must seek his counsel immediately."


NAME:Kashya 
SPEED:78
wave:act1\kashya\kas_act1_q4_successful.wav
"Again, you amaze me, outlander.
 
The Sisterhood is grateful to you for delivering Cain to us. I believe Akara has something to tell you."

NAME:Gheed 
SPEED:53
wave:act1\gheed\ghe_act1_q4_successful.wav
"Ah, Cain is here... another customer. I haven't been this pleased since a love-starved maiden let down a bit more than her hair."

NAME:Charsi 
SPEED:102
wave:act1\charsi\cha_act1_q4_successful.wav
"Akara wishes to reward you for your bravery in returning Deckard Cain."

NAME:Warriv 
SPEED:80
wave:act1\warriv\war_act1_q4_successful.wav
"Only a brave adventurer could return with Deckard Cain. Akara has a reward for your valor."

NAME:Cain 
SPEED:74
wave:act1\cain\cain_act1_q4_successful.wav
"As a token of my gratitude, I will identify items for you at no charge."
STATE:RescuedByHero

NAME:Cain 
SPEED:82
wave:act1\cain\cain_act1_q4_rescuedbyhero.wav
"…I thank you, friend, for coming to my aid." 
STATE:RescuedByRogues

NAME:Cain 
SPEED:75
wave:act1\cain\cain_act1_q4_rescuedbyrogues.wav
"Oh… Blessings on the Rogues! They finally rescued me from that cursed place!"
STATE:TragedyOfTristram

NAME:Cain
SPEED:33
wave:act1\cain\cain_act1_q4_tragedyoftristram.wav
"Regrettably, I could do nothing to prevent the disaster which devastated Tristram. It would appear that our greatest fears have come to pass. Diablo, the Lord of Terror, has once again been set loose upon the world!
 
As you know, some time ago Diablo was slain beneath Tristram.  And when our hero emerged triumphant from the labyrinth beneath town, we held a grand celebration that lasted several days.
 
Yet, as the weeks passed, our hero became increasingly aloof. He kept his distance from the rest of the townsfolk and seemed to lapse into a dark, brooding depression. I thought that perhaps his ordeal had been so disturbing that he simply could not put it out of his mind.
 
The hero seemed more tormented every passing day. I remember he awoke many times -- screaming in the night -- always something about 'the East'.
 
One day, he simply left. And shortly thereafter Tristram was attacked by legions of foul demons. Many were slain, and the demons left me to die in that cursed cage.
 
I believe now that Tristram's hero was that Dark Wanderer who passed this way before the Monastery fell.
 
I fear even worse, my friend... I fear that Diablo has taken possession of the hero who sought to slay him. If true, Diablo will become more powerful than ever before.
 
You must stop him or all will be lost."

//Quest 1.5 The Forgotten Tower
QUEST:A1Q5
STATE:Init

//spoken by a narrator
NAME:QuestTome
SPEED:36
"...And so it came to pass that the Countess, who once bathed in the rejuvenating blood of a hundred virgins, was buried alive… And her castle in which so many cruel deeds took place fell rapidly into ruin. Rising over the buried dungeons in that god-forsaken wilderness, a solitary tower, like some monument to Evil, is all that remains.
 
The Countess' fortune was believed to be divided among the clergy, although some say that more remains unfound, still buried alongside the rotting skulls that bear mute witness to the inhumanity of the human creature."
STATE:AfterInit

NAME:Gheed 
SPEED:110
wave:act1\gheed\ghe_act1_q5_after.wav
"The only wealth you're likely to find there is a wealth of vermin."

NAME:Charsi 
SPEED:70
wave:act1\charsi\cha_act1_q5_after.wav
"That old tower is as rotten on the inside as it appears on the outside. I heard that several Sisters came to a gruesome end when a stairwell collapsed on them."

NAME:Akara 
SPEED:67
wave:act1\akara\aka_act1_q5_after.wav
"The dangers there are not solely architectural. Once inside that wretched place, many succumb to a vile miasma."

NAME:Cain 
SPEED:60
wave:act1\cain\cain_act1_q5_after.wav
"That tower marks a place of danger. There is an epic poem about it...  How much sorrow one can stand was tested there."

NAME:Warriv 
SPEED:81
wave:act1\warriv\war_act1_q5_after.wav
"Rumors of treasure are no different from rumors of any other kind. They hold false promise to those who should know better."


NAME:Kashya 
SPEED:78
wave:act1\kashya\kas_act1_q5_after.wav
"The tome speaks of treasure. Yet, all we have found are death, delirium, and disappointment."
STATE:EarlyReturn

NAME:Kashya 
SPEED:151
wave:act1\kashya\kas_act1_q5_early.wav
"Have you suddenly lost your taste for wealth?"

NAME:Cain 
wave:act1\cain\cain_act1_q5_early.wav
SPEED:94
"Quickly in and quickly out is all the advice I can give you."

NAME:Warriv 
SPEED:118
wave:act1\warriv\war_act1_q5_early.wav
"Better an empty pocket than a full grave."

NAME:Charsi 
SPEED:170
wave:act1\charsi\cha_act1_q5_early.wav
"You're not ready to give up, are you?"

NAME:Akara 
SPEED:140
wave:act1\akara\aka_act1_q5_early.wav
"There is no more I can tell you about that ancient tower."

NAME:Gheed 
SPEED:79
wave:act1\gheed\ghe_act1_q5_early.wav
"Guess what! I've named a boil on my ass after you. It, too, bothers me every time I sit down."
STATE:Successful

NAME:Kashya 
SPEED:79
wave:act1\kashya\kas_act1_q5_successful.wav
"Your rewards are well-earned. To us, the tower was nothing more than a headstone looming over a long forgotten grave."

NAME:Warriv 
SPEED:62
wave:act1\warriv\war_act1_q5_successful.wav
"Remember. Wealth is as insubstantial as a cloud and passes as quickly. Ignore Gheed. All that twitters is not bold."

NAME:Gheed 
SPEED:68
wave:act1\gheed\ghe_act1_q5_successful.wav
"Warriv's advice is like corpse gas; it befouls the air for a moment and then it disappears."

NAME:Akara 
SPEED:58
wave:act1\akara\aka_act1_q5_successful.wav
"I thought the stories of treasure in the tower were nothing but lies. I am glad you found something of value in that death-trap. Would that our Sisters had been so fortunate."

NAME:Charsi 
SPEED:126
wave:act1\charsi\cha_act1_q5_successful.wav
"Those riches will serve you well on the long road ahead."

NAME:Cain 
SPEED:69
wave:act1\cain\cain_act1_q5_successful.wav
"Well done, my friend. Courage and opportunity together have created in you a kind of alchemy."

//Quest 1.3 Tools of the Trade
QUEST:A1Q3
STATE:Init

NAME:Charsi 
SPEED:66
wave:act1\charsi\cha_act1_q3_init.wav
"When I fled the Monastery, I left behind the Horadric Malus, my enchanted smithing hammer. If you can retrieve it for me, I'll use its magic to strengthen your equipment."
STATE:AfterInit

NAME:Cain 
SPEED:51
wave:act1\cain\cain_act1_q3_after.wav
"The Malus was forged and enchanted by the ancient Horadric Mages during the Sin Wars. When their union dissolved, the Malus was entrusted to the Sisterhood guarding the pass into the East."

NAME:Akara 
SPEED:59
wave:act1\akara\aka_act1_q3_after.wav
"The retrieval of the Horadric Malus is not without risk. Our Monastery is filled with voracious hellspawn. You'd best be careful, my friend."

NAME:Kashya 
SPEED:61
wave:act1\kashya\kas_act1_q3_after.wav
"Charsi is wasting her time and talents using an inferior hammer! Had she the Horadric Malus, she could make the steel sing and craft you a suit of armor as impenetrable as the Great Eye." 

NAME:Charsi 
SPEED:87
wave:act1\charsi\cha_act1_q3_after.wav
"The Monastery can confuse even those who know it well. Stay alert in there."

NAME:Gheed 
SPEED:74
wave:act1\gheed\ghe_act1_q3_after.wav
"Charsi talks of nothing anymore, but this Horadric Malus. Between you and her my ears need a rest.
 
Just find it and bring it back quickly."

NAME:GheedAlt
//unused
"I have offered my nomadic phallus, but to no avail."

NAME:Warriv 
SPEED:68
wave:act1\warriv\war_act1_q3_after.wav
"Just as an archer needs bow and arrow, or a draughtsman pen and paper, so Charsi needs the Horadric Malus with which to ply her trade."
STATE:EarlyReturn

NAME:Cain 
SPEED:57
wave:act1\cain\cain_act1_q3_early.wav
"The Malus has eluded you so far. Well, search thoroughly in the Barracks… That is where the Rogues kept their forge."

NAME:Akara 
SPEED:98
wave:act1\akara\aka_act1_q3_early.wav
"If you can't carry out this quest, how will you face the greater evils ahead?"

NAME:Kashya 
SPEED:71
wave:act1\kashya\kas_act1_q3_early.wav
"To do battle with Andariel requires more than thick skin and a strong will. You'll want armor and weaponry forged with the hammer's enchantments."

NAME:Charsi 
SPEED:89
wave:act1\charsi\cha_act1_q3_early.wav
"The Malus is a Horadric artifact of great power. Please bring it back."

NAME:Gheed 
SPEED:90
wave:act1\gheed\ghe_act1_q3_early.wav
"I have heard that you bear us no Malus."

NAME:Warriv 
SPEED:120
wave:act1\warriv\war_act1_q3_early.wav
"What better opportunity to show your mettle?"
STATE:Successful

NAME:Cain 
SPEED:59
wave:act1\cain\cain_act1_q3_successful.wav
"The magical effects imbued by the Malus are impossible to predict, but are always to the good."

NAME:Akara 
SPEED:57
wave:act1\akara\aka_act1_q3_successful.wav
"Well done, my friend. But remember, the return of the Horadric Malus is but one step in reclaiming the Monastery."

NAME:Kashya 
SPEED:74
wave:act1\kashya\kas_act1_q3_successful.wav
"Now that the Horadric Malus is back in our possession, we shall use it to deliver a great blow against the Evil which torments this land."

NAME:Charsi 
SPEED:72
wave:act1\charsi\cha_act1_q3_successful.wav
"Oh! Thanks so much for returning the Horadric Malus! I will now imbue one of your items with magical powers."

NAME:Gheed 
SPEED:120
wave:act1\gheed\ghe_act1_q3_successful.wav
"I guess it's too late to take back some of the names I called you."

NAME:Warriv 
SPEED:118
wave:act1\warriv\war_act1_q3_successful.wav
"I am glad the hammer has returned and you with it."

//Quest 1.6 Sisters to the slaughter
QUEST:A1Q6
STATE:Init

NAME:Cain 
SPEED:34
wave:act1\cain\cain_act1_q6_init.wav
"It is certain that we face the demon queen, Andariel, who has corrupted the Rogue Sisterhood and defiled their ancestral Monastery. This does not bode well for us, my friend.
 
Ancient Horadric texts record that Andariel and the other Lesser Evils once overthrew the three Prime Evils -- Diablo, Mephisto and Baal -- banishing them from Hell to our world. Here, they caused mankind untold anguish and suffering before they were finally bound within the Soulstones.
 
Andariel's presence here could mean that the forces of Hell are once again aligned behind Diablo and his Brothers. If this is true, then I fear for us all.
 
You must kill her before the Monastery becomes a permanent outpost of Hell and the way east lost forever."
STATE:AfterInit

NAME:Cain
SPEED:45
wave:act1\cain\cain_act1_q6_after.wav
"Diablo is heading east for some foul purpose. And the only passage east is through the Monastery gate. Obviously, Diablo summoned Andariel to block any pursuit.
 
For her part Andariel hopes to win Diablo's favor… the lesser demons are always vying for positions of power within the unholy hierarchy!"

NAME:Akara
SPEED:63
wave:act1\akara\aka_act1_q6_after.wav
"Andariel has desecrated all we hold dear. She must not be permitted to serve Diablo.
 
Destroy her! Her corruption of our Order must be undone!"

NAME:Charsi 
SPEED:132
wave:act1\charsi\cha_act1_q6_after.wav
"Send Andariel back to the Hell she came from!"

NAME:Gheed 
SPEED:71
wave:act1\gheed\ghe_act1_q6_after.wav
"You're going after Andariel?
 
... One of my wagon wheels is in need of repair. I'll be under the wagon, if I'm needed."

NAME:Warriv 
SPEED:72
wave:act1\warriv\war_act1_q6_after.wav
"The mapmakers tell us the shortest distance between two points is a straight line.
 
Our way east is a line that runs through Andariel's stronghold, the Monastery."

NAME:Kashya 
SPEED:81
wave:act1\kashya\kas_act1_q6_after.wav
"I can imagine a thousand different ways to kill Andariel. You need only choose one."
STATE:EarlyReturn

NAME:Cain 
SPEED:48
wave:act1\cain\cain_act1_q6_early.wav
"It is clear that Andariel is acting on behalf of Diablo to prevent anyone from following him eastward. Her defeat would allow you to continue the pursuit.
 
Ancient lore has it that while Andariel was spawned in the Burning Hells, she is not fond of fire."

NAME:Akara 
SPEED:57
wave:act1\akara\aka_act1_q6_early.wav
"You have done much to help us, but I sense that this has only fueled Andariel's fury. She will not stop until we are all dead.
 
You must kill Andariel before her army can gain the upper hand."

NAME:Gheed 
SPEED:72
wave:act1\gheed\ghe_act1_q6_early.wav
"Have you stumbled upon that Demon Queen, yet? I hear she's quite the beauty... as far as Maidens of Anguish go, that is."

NAME:Charsi 
SPEED:108
wave:act1\charsi\cha_act1_q6_early.wav
"If you are the hero that you seem to be, now is the time to prove it."

NAME:Warriv 
SPEED:90
wave:act1\warriv\war_act1_q6_early.wav
"May I remind you that my caravan can only go east, if the Monastery is cleansed?"
STATE:EarlyReturn2

NAME:Kashya 
SPEED:126
wave:act1\kashya\kas_act1_q6_early2.wav
"Deckard Cain has important information about Andariel."
STATE:Successful

NAME:Akara 
SPEED:64
wave:act1\akara\aka_act1_q6_successful.wav
"Finally, we may rejoice!
 
We owe you a debt we can never repay. I only hope that in time we will be able to rebuild our Order.
 
All our thanks go with you, my friend."

NAME:Charsi 
SPEED:86
wave:act1\charsi\cha_act1_q6_successful.wav
"You'll probably go east now… It was good to know you. I hope you'll come back if you ever need anything."

NAME:Kashya 
SPEED:44
wave:act1\kashya\kas_act1_q6_successful.wav
"Andariel's death brings about renewed life for us all. We mourn the loss of our dear Sisters, but at least now we can get on with our lives.
 
I… may have misjudged you, outlander. You are a true hero and testament to the noble spirit which has inspired our Order for generations.
 
Fare well… my friend."

NAME:Gheed 
SPEED:100
wave:act1\gheed\ghe_act1_q6_successful.wav
"I'm going to party like it's 999!"

NAME:Warriv 
SPEED:82
wave:act1\warriv\war_act1_q6_successful.wav
"The caravan is prepared. We may now journey eastward to Lut Gholein."

NAME:Cain 
SPEED:38
wave:act1\cain\cain_act1_q6_successful.wav
"This is a great victory indeed, but many more battles await. I will accompany you on your journey, lending what assistance I can... 
 
Remember… Diablo is still out there, seeking something in the desert. I'm afraid that this nightmare will not end until you find what it is that he seeks."
//end
