//DIABLO II

//ACT II: The Secret of the Vizjerei

//SECTION:GREETINGS

//Griez Greetings
//"Hello."
//act2\griez\gre_greetings.wav
//"Greetings."
//act2\griez\gre_goodmorning.wav
//"Good morning."
//act2\griez\gre_goodday.wav
//"Good day."
//act2\griez\gre_goodevening.wav
//"Good evening."
//act2\griez\gre_whogoesthere.wav
//"Who goes there?"
//act2\griez\gre_needsomehelp.wav
//"Need some help?"
//act2\griez\gre_yescitizen.wav
//"Yes, citizen?"
//act2\griez\gre_comebackthisway.wav
//"Come back this way, have you? What, didn't you see enough action here the first
//time?"

//Elzix Greetings
//act2\elzix\elz_hello.wav
//"Hello."
//act2\elzix\elz_greetings.wav
//"Greetings."
//act2\elzix\elz_hithere.wav
//"Hi, there."
//act2\elzix\elz_goodmorning.wav
//"Good morning."
//act2\elzix\elz_goodday.wav
//"Good day."
//act2\elzix\elz_goodevening.wav
//"Good evening."
//"How do you like desert life?"
//act2\elzix\elz_whatchaneed.wav
//"What'cha need?"
//act2\elzix\elz_welcometodesertrain.wav
//"Welcome to the Desert Rain."

//Warriv Greetings
//same as in Act 1

//Atma Greetings
//act2\atma\atm_hello.wav
//"Hello."
//act2\atma\atm_greetings.wav
//"Greetings."
//act2\atma\atm_goodmorning.wav
//"Good morning."
//act2\atma\atm_goodday.wav
//"Good day."
//act2\atma\atm_goodevening.wav
//"Good evening."
//act2\atma\atm_tellmetroubles.wav
//"Tell me your troubles."
//act2\atma\atm_mugcantcure.wav
//"There's no trouble a mug can't cure."
//act2\atma\atm_helloagain.wav
//"Hello again. Things have been very quiet around here since you left."

//Geglash Greetings
//act2\geglash\geg_hey.wav
//"Heyyyy."
//act2\geglash\geg_heythere.wav
//"Hey there."
//act2\geglash\geg_yes.wav
//"Yes?"
//act2\geglash\geg_huh.wav
//"Huh?"
//act2\geglash\geg_goodmorning.wav
//"Good morning."
//act2\geglash\geg_goodday.wav
//"Good day."
//act2\geglash\geg_goodevening.wav
//"Good evening."
//act2\geglash\geg_buyyouadrink.wav
//"Let me buy you a drink."
//act2\geglash\geg_youbeentokurast.wav
//"So you've been to Kurast, huh? Did you happen to bring back any Skatsimi
//ale-potions?"

//Meshif Greetings
//common\meshif\mes_hello.wav
//"Hello."
//common\meshif\mes_goodtoseeyou.wav
//"Good to see you."
//common\meshif\mes_goodmorning.wav
//"Good morning."
//common\meshif\mes_goodday.wav
//"Good day."
//common\meshif\mes_goodevening.wav
//"Good evening."
//common\meshif\mes_ahoymate.wav
//"Ahoy, mate.
//common\meshif\mes_myshipyourship.wav
//"My ship is your ship."
//common\meshif\mes_thankfuldontcharge.wav
//"You should be thankful that I don't charge you for ferrying you across the sea."

//Jerhyn Greetings
//act2\jerhyn\jer_hello.wav
//"Hello."
//act2\jerhyn\jer_greetings.wav
//"Greetings."
//act2\jerhyn\jer_yes.wav
//"Yes?"
//act2\jerhyn\jer_goodmorning.wav
//"Good morning."
//act2\jerhyn\jer_goodday.wav
//"Good day."
//act2\jerhyn\jer_goodevening.wav
//"Good evening."
//act2\jerhyn\jer_stateyourbusiness.wav
//"Please state your business."
//"I grant you audience."
//"Welcome, hero."
//act2\jerhyn\jer_ourheroreturns.wav
//"Ahh... Our hero returns."

//Fara Greetings
//act2\fara\far_hello.wav
//"Hello."
//act2\fara\far_greetings.wav
//"Greetings."
//act2\fara\far_blessingstoyou.wav
//"Blessings to you."
//act2\fara\far_goodmorning.wav
//"Good morning."
//act2\fara\far_goodday.wav
//"Good day."
//act2\fara\far_goodevening.wav
//"Good evening."
//act2\fara\far_howmayihelpyou.wav
//"How may I help you?"
//"What can I do for you?"
//act2\fara\far_anhonortoserveyou.wav
//"It is my honor to serve you."
//act2\fara\far_thankallthatsholy.wav
//"Thank all that's Holy, you're still alive. I can see in your eyes that glorious Kurast
//has been despoiled by evil. I don't think I can bear to hear about it. I wish you luck."

//Lysander Greetings
//act2\lysander\lys_hello.wav
//"Hello."
//act2\lysander\lys_greetings.wav
//"Greetings."
//act2\lysander\lys_goodmorning.wav
//"Good morning."
//act2\lysander\lys_goodday.wav
//"Good day."
//act2\lysander\lys_goodevening.wav
//"Good evening."
//"Huh? Did you say something?"
//act2\lysander\lys_rightpotioncantcure.wav
//"There's nothing the right potion can't cure."
//"Back again, uh?"
//act2\lysander\lys_welcometomyshop.wav
//"Welcome to my shop."
//act2\lysander\lys_whatthehelldoyouwant.wav
//"Well, what the hell do you want? Oh, it's you. Uh, hi there."

//Drognan Greetings
//act2\drognan\dro_hello.wav
//"Hello."
//act2\drognan\dro_greetings.wav
//"Greetings."
//act2\drognan\dro_goodmorning.wav
//"Good morning."
//act2\drognan\dro_goodday.wav
//"Good day."
//act2\drognan\dro_goodevening.wav
//"Good evening."
//act2\drognan\dro_askandlearn.wav
//"Ask and learn."
//act2\drognan\dro_approachandtrade.wav
//"Approach and let's trade."
//act2\drognan\dro_allowtoadvise.wav
//"Allow me to advise you."
//act2\drognan\dro_welcomeback.wav
//"Welcome back, stranger. I hope the battle goes well in the east."

//Radament's taunts (said as player enters his lair)
//act2\monster\radamenttaunt1.wav
//"We live again!"
//act2\monster\radamenttaunt2.wav
//Evil laughter
// Attacks, Get hits, and death.

//changed 3/1/00
//No need to localize the Summoner laughs
//Summoner's taunts (insane laughter as player approaches within range)
//act2\monster\summonertaunt1.wav
//"Heha… hahahehehaha…hehehaha…"
//act2\monster\summonertaunt2.wav 
//"Heha… hahahehehaha…" 
// Attacks, Get hits, and death.

//Duriel's taunts (said as the player enters his lair)
//act2\monster\durieltaunt1.wav
//"Looking for Baal?"
//unused
//"I am your doom!"
// Attacks, Get hits, and death.

SECTION:GOSSIP

NAME:PalaceGuard
//Guards Greetings (at beginning of Act)

SPEED:600
wave:act2\guard\gua_halt.wav
"Halt."

SPEED:290
wave:act2\guard\gua_youmaynotpass.wav
"You may not pass."

//Guards Greetings (after player has earned right to enter palace)

SPEED:255
wave:act2\guard\gua_welcome.wav 
"Welcome to the palace."

SPEED:255
wave:act2\guard\gua_youmayenter.wav
"You may enter the palace."

SPEED:290
wave:act2\guard\gua_stayoutoftrouble.wav
"Stay out of trouble."


NAME:GriezIntro
SPEED:58
wave:act2\griez\gre_act2_intro.wav
"I'll bet you wonder how this town manages to stay safe with all the trouble going on out in the desert. Well, I can tell you that it's got nothing to do with the local town guards... they're all in the palace for some reason.
 
Jerhyn hired me and my mercenaries to help keep the peace around here. We're not cheap, but we're the best this wasteland has to offer."

NAME:Griez
SPEED:85
wave:act2\griez\gre_act2_gossip_01.wav
"We do a good job in town, but beyond the city gates, you'll find all manner of demons."

//<Q4
SPEED:52
wave:act2\griez\gre_act2_gossip_02.wav
"The local guards were all relocated to the palace after the troubles began. No one really knows why. Actually, all of the town's brothel girls have been hiding out in the palace's cellar lately, so I assume that the guards have been assigned to 'protect them' with their lives." 

SPEED:75
wave:act2\griez\gre_act2_gossip_03.wav
"I might spare you a few of my men. Why, enough gold can muster an army."

SPEED:61
wave:act2\griez\gre_act2_gossip_04.wav
"Jerhyn's got a nice little trading post going here. Despite his youth, he is a clever businessman. As you can see by that palace, he's done quite well for himself."

SPEED:99
wave:act2\griez\gre_act2_gossip_05.wav
"We're keeping the town safe and tight, but I've got a hunch there's something Jerhyn's not telling us."

SPEED:44
wave:act2\griez\gre_act2_gossip_06.wav
"Ah, Elzix is quite a character. I had a few run-ins with his band of outlaws in my younger years. Now, he's as settled as the dunes out there. The Desert Rain Inn is his pride and joy these days."
 
SPEED:53
wave:act2\griez\gre_act2_gossip_07.wav
"Atma seems to be a fine woman. But I'm sure the loss of her family has made her lonely. Perhaps I should go over and console her when I get off duty tonight…"

//<Q6
SPEED:72
wave:act2\griez\gre_act2_gossip_08.wav
"Geglash is an imposing warrior, but he's never been able to back down from a fight. One of these days, his pride will be the death of him."

SPEED:67
wave:act2\griez\gre_act2_gossip_09.wav
"Meshif has sailed all around the southern seas and visited many strange lands. 
It must be driving him mad, having to stay anchored here." 

SPEED:70
wave:act2\griez\gre_act2_gossip_10.wav 
"I haven't talked much to Fara. She keeps to herself most of the time. I get the feeling that she doesn't like us mercenary types much."

SPEED:73
wave:act2\griez\gre_act2_gossip_11.wav 
"I'd stay clear of Lysander, if I were you. He's always mixing his damned potions and chemicals. I wouldn't be surprised if he winds up blowing himself to smithereens!"

SPEED:85
wave:act2\griez\gre_act2_gossip_12.wav 
"Drognan's a mystery to me. Then again, I never did trust mages much."

NAME:ElzixIntro
SPEED:61
wave:act2\elzix\elz_act2_intro.wav
"Hmm... You look like a sturdy adventurer.
 
You know, I used to be quite the scoundrel in my day. I led the fiercest group of bandits who ever terrorized these sands!
 
Nowadays, I run this here Inn and pretty much stay out of trouble.
 
My days of adventuring are behind me."

NAME:ElzixIntroNec
SPEED:48
wave:act2\elzix\elz_act2_intro_nec.wav
"Ah… You must be one of the new heroes who've come to rid our city of evil. Under any other circumstances, I'd be surprised to see one of your kind in the city. But lately… Oh, never mind all that…
 
You know, I used to be quite the scoundrel in my day. I led the fiercest group of bandits who ever terrorized these sands!
 
Nowadays, I run this here Inn and pretty much stay out of trouble.
 
My days of adventuring are behind me."

NAME:Elzix
//The next gossip is only for a Necromancer.
SPEED:52
wave:act2\elzix\elz_act2_gossip_nec.wav
"You know, I've lost a number of body parts over the years. An eye here, a leg there…
 
Say, do you know any spells that'd grow them back for me? Hmm… On second thought, I'll leave well enough alone."

SPEED:90
wave:act2\elzix\elz_act2_gossip_01.wav 
"What tales Drognan can tell... You would do well to listen carefully to that wizened wizard."

SPEED:80
wave:act2\elzix\elz_act2_gossip_02.wav 
"There are many ancient tombs in the desert. Most of them are already plundered, but I imagine that some have remained hidden."

SPEED:67
//<Q4
wave:act2\elzix\elz_act2_gossip_03_q4.wav
"I miss the brothels that used to do business here.
 
You know, all of the ladies fled to the palace as soon as the trouble in the desert started. You'd think that they could at least come out once in a while now that Greiz and his men have things relatively under control."

SPEED:71
//<Q2
wave:act2\elzix\elz_act2_gossip_04_q2.wav
"Atma... Now, there's a fine woman. Lately, though, she's only thinking about revenge. She has reason enough..."

SPEED:71
//<Q4
wave:act2\elzix\elz_act2_gossip_05.wav
"We've all fared well under Jerhyn's leadership. The town has remained safe throughout this whole mess; and yet the lad still seems very upset about something." 

SPEED:88
wave:act2\elzix\elz_act2_gossip_06.wav 
"Geglash is a fool who would fight his own shadow if he could. Fighting's all he ever thinks about!"

SPEED:74
wave:act2\elzix\elz_act2_gossip_07.wav 
"Meshif is a wise Captain, I think. Wise enough to know silver from tin and truth from dung, that's for sure."

SPEED:65
wave:act2\elzix\elz_act2_gossip_08.wav 
"Fara is a good woman. She seems very sad, but seldom speaks of her past. She's good to the poor and helps people when she can. That makes her all right in my book." 

SPEED:70
wave:act2\elzix\elz_act2_gossip_09.wav 
"That Lysander's a grumpy old cuss. You'd better not disturb him while he's working on his potions, or… BOOM! You could get blasted to the moon."

Name:WarrivAct2Intro
SPEED:62
wave:act2\warriv\war_act2_intro.wav
"Now that Andariel is dead, I can return and outfit the Rogues properly. Once I've made some trades here, I'll be free to head back to their Monastery. Let me know if you want to travel along."

Name:WarrivAct2
SPEED:106
wave:act2\warriv\war_act2_gossip_01.wav
"Caravans take people where they want to go - until they get there."

SPEED:80
wave:act2\warriv\war_act2_gossip_02.wav 
"By ship is the only way eastward from here. I believe Captain Meshif has a small trading vessel moored at the docks."

SPEED:70
//<Q4
wave:act2\warriv\war_act2_gossip_03.wav 
"There used to be a lot of brothels here... I guess the troubles scared all the women away, or maybe they're 'safe' in Jerhyn's palace."

SPEED:53
wave:act2\warriv\war_act2_gossip_04.wav 
"That old desert fox, Elzix, is as crafty as they come. Years back, he made off with a small fortune of my caravan's wares. I certainly never expected to see him so… domesticated."
 
SPEED:57
wave:act2\warriv\war_act2_gossip_05.wav
"Jerhyn has his father's strength and wits. He's young, but he rules this place with wisdom and care. I think he'll grow into a fine Sultan… Provided we all survive this crisis." 

//removed
wave:act2\warriv\war_act2_gossip_06.wav
//"I've met Meshif many times on my travels here. I've always enjoyed trading stories with him //about the exotic lands of the East. I'd wager he's sailed to many strange lands."

NAME:AtmaIntro
SPEED:59
wave:act2\atma\atm_act2_intro.wav
"You'll forgive me if I seem upset. I've suffered a loss recently, but that's not your problem.
 
It's a relief to see some proper warriors come through here. My name is Atma. I run the tavern here in Lut Gholein."

NAME:Atma
SPEED:86
wave:act2\atma\atm_act2_gossip_01.wav
"Evil has laid siege to Lut Gholein and you may be our last hope..."

SPEED:56
wave:act2\atma\atm_act2_gossip_02.wav 
"This public house used to be quite lively, until this plague of evil. Luckily, I've managed to save away a tidy nest egg. Unfortunately, I couldn't save everything I cared for..."

SPEED:57
//<Q4
wave:act2\atma\atm_act2_gossip_03.wav
"In addition to my public house, there used to be several brothels doing business here. When the troubles first started in the desert, the harem guilds sought sanctuary within the palace.
 
Of course, Jerhyn was glad to oblige. I'll bet they're finding many ways to repay him for his protection."

SPEED:70
wave:act2\atma\atm_act2_gossip_04.wav 
"Geglash may seem like a sot, but he's a brave man. All this trouble has driven him to drinking more than his usual."

SPEED:64
wave:act2\atma\atm_act2_gossip_05.wav 
"Elzix and I have reached an understanding over the years. He sends travelers to me for drink and entertainment, and I send them back to him for a soft bed. The travelers often trade their wares for lodging."

SPEED:89
wave:act2\atma\atm_act2_gossip_06.wav 
"Meshif seldom patronizes my establishment. I think he prefers to stay out there on his leaky ship." 

SPEED:71
wave:act2\atma\atm_act2_gossip_08.wav 
"Oh, Lysander is cranky, but he's a good old man. He used to give me medicines when… my son was ill." 

SPEED:78
wave:act2\atma\atm_act2_gossip_09.wav 
"Drognan is a very private person. He's always studying ancient scrolls and such. He may be a mystery to me forever."

NAME:GeglashIntro
SPEED:57
wave:act2\geglash\geg_act2_intro.wav 
"Bah! I don't know why you people keep pestering me.
 
Greiz seems to have this place locked down nice and tight. Not that I couldn't have done the same! I've proven my valor in combat plenty of times."

NAME:GeglashIntroBar
SPEED:43
wave:act2\geglash\geg_act2_intro_bar.wav 
"Hey, you're a Barbarian, aren't ya? Ferocious as the wild beasts of the north, that's what they say. I suppose you've come to help save this city. You needn't bother.
 
Greiz seems to have this place locked down nice and tight. Not that I couldn't have done the same! I've proven my valor in combat plenty of times."

NAME:Geglash
//The next gossip is only for a Barbarian.
SPEED:46
wave:act2\geglash\geg_act2_gossip_bar.wav
"Hey, I heard that you Barbarians can wield multiple weapons at once. I never learned to fight two-handed. Carrying a sword and a wineskin at the same time is all I can ever handle."

//<Q4
SPEED:53
wave:act2\geglash\geg_act2_gossip_01.wav 
"Sure, I hear lots of what goes on. Did you hear about the harem guilds? They were the only ones allowed to hide out in the palace when the raids started!
 
Ah… It figures."

SPEED:64
wave:act2\geglash\geg_act2_gossip_02.wav 
"I've killed plenty of those demons out in the desert. It doesn't seem to slow them down any, though... they just keep coming back for more."

SPEED:55
wave:act2\geglash\geg_act2_gossip_03.wav 
"Have you found those big sand maggots yet? Arrows and all that don't work so well against them. Best thing is to hack 'em with a sword or such."

SPEED:58
wave:act2\geglash\geg_act2_gossip_04.wav 
"There are some ancient tombs out there in the desert. You have to go pretty far to find them, though. Rumor has it that they're crawling with walking corpses now.
 
As if the Saber Cats and Claw Vipers weren't bad enough."
 
SPEED:67
wave:act2\geglash\geg_act2_gossip_05.wav 
"Yeah. Meshif's okay, I guess. But I'll be damned if I ever get on his ship. I don't even like to drink water."

//<Q4
SPEED:52
wave:act2\geglash\geg_act2_gossip_06.wav 
"Jerhyn's been acting strange lately. I can't imagine why he recalled the town guards into the palace. If there is something wrong in there, I hope he doesn't expect me to handle it." 

SPEED:57
wave:act2\geglash\geg_act2_gossip_07.wav 
"I've seen Fara defend herself against a few drunken ruffians. She's got moves I've never even seen before. Wherever she's from, she sure learned how to fight there." 
 
SPEED:83
wave:act2\geglash\geg_act2_gossip_08.wav 
"I've got no time for old alchemists. Lysander would be completely useless in a real fight."

NAME:MeshifIntro
SPEED:63
wave:act2\meshif\mes_act2_intro.wav 
"Greetings. I'm Meshif, captain of this ship here. I make port runs around the Twin Seas and occasionally out to Kingsport in Westmarch.
 
I haven't sailed anywhere lately, though... Jerhyn has ordered me to stay docked here in case of emergency."

NAME:MeshifIntroAma
SPEED:54
wave:act2\meshif\mes_act2_intro_ama.wav 
"Greetings, Amazon. I haven't seen one of your kind in many years…. It's good to know that warriors of your caliber are protecting this city.
 
I'm Meshif, captain of this ship here. I make port runs around the Twin Seas and occasionally out to Kingsport in Westmarch.
 
I haven't sailed anywhere lately, though... Jerhyn has ordered me to stay docked here in case of emergency."

NAME:Meshif
//The next gossip is only for an Amazon.
SPEED:62
wave:act2\meshif\mes_act2_gossip_ama.wav 
"I was wondering if you've heard any news from Kurast? I know you Amazons travel extensively. Have you been there recently?
 
Hmm… Well, I hope the port opens soon. I need to get home to Kurast and find out what's been happening there."

//<Q4
SPEED:72
wave:act2\meshif\mes_act2_gossip_01_q4.wav 
"There's something Jerhyn's not telling me, I just don't know what. To my eye, things here in town don't look that bad, especially since Warriv's caravan route opened up."

SPEED:65
wave:act2\meshif\mes_act2_gossip_02.wav 
"I've been all around the seas in these parts. It's dangerous sailing west this time of year, though. Until the season changes, the caravan through the desert is the main trade route to Westmarch."

SPEED:75
wave:act2\meshif\mes_act2_gossip_03.wav 
"My ship is the only way East from here. Still, Lord Jerhyn tells me that I may not leave until the current crisis is over."

SPEED:65
wave:act2\meshif\mes_act2_gossip_04.wav 
"Oh, I've known Elzix for years. He always offers me a free room at his Inn when I dock here, but I prefer the comforts of my own cabin."

SPEED:61
wave:act2\meshif\mes_act2_gossip_05.wav 
"Warriv is a good friend. We've shared many tales, he and I. If we had it all to do over again, I believe we'd both be explorers of some renown." 

SPEED:69
wave:act2\meshif\mes_act2_gossip_06.wav 
"Greiz seems to be a dependable fellow. I hope he can handle it if those things in the desert decide to attack this town."

SPEED:130
wave:act2\meshif\mes_act2_gossip_07.wav 
"Atma serves a fine ale in her establishment." 

SPEED:70
wave:act2\meshif\mes_act2_gossip_08.wav 
"Hah! That braggart Geglash says he fears neither man nor beast. Yet, when I offer to take him out to sea, he quakes with fear." 

SPEED:130
wave:act2\meshif\mes_act2_gossip_09.wav 
"The lady Fara has a proud, noble air about her."

NAME:JerhynActIntro
SPEED:41
wave:act2\jerhyn\jer_act2_intro.wav 
"Greetings, honored traveler. I am Jerhyn, Lord of Lut Gholein, and I bid you welcome to my fair port-city. I'm glad to know that once again caravans are free to travel through the Western Pass.
 
For some time now, we have been under siege by an evil power that I cannot identify. Strange… It all began when a Dark Wanderer came this way, looking for the Tomb of Tal Rasha. No one knows exactly where Tal Rasha, Keeper of Baal, is entombed, but it is certain to be far out in the desert.
 
Now, my people whisper tales of the dead rising from their tombs and horrible creatures lurking amongst the moonlit dunes. Even I have witnessed things which I cannot explain. I've ordered the port closed and all trade ships moored until I am sure that my city is safe.
 
Atma, the tavernkeeper, has an important mission for you. Go see her immediately. You'll find her on the other side of town.
 
Now, I must return to the palace. I apologize, but I can't invite you in. Things are… rather a mess right now."

//Script note: He is hiding knowledge that the demons have already invaded the
//palace cellar, and he's just barely holding them off. If they break through, the
//whole town will be lost. The harem guilds, who were hiding in the cellar, are
//already dead!

NAME:JerhynActIntroMore
SPEED:51
wave:act2\jerhyn\jer_act2_intro_more.wav 
"For trade in magic and the like, see Drognan or Lysander. Drognan is the wisest man I know - without equal in magic and ancient lore. Poor Lysander is nearly deaf, but he's a reliable potion chemist.
 
For travel back west, see Warriv, whom you already know.
 
Our own Fara is a fine and honest armorer, and she can heal wounds as well.
 
Elzix is the Innkeeper and may also have some items to trade.
 
Greiz, the mercenary captain I hired to secure the gates of Lut Gholein, keeps order in town, as well.
 
There are others here, too. I'm sure you'll meet most of them. Just look around…"
 
NAME:JerhynIntro
SPEED:117
//<Q1
wave:act2\jerhyn\jer_act2_gossip_01.wav 
"Things are getting worse by the hour. I know everything looks fine, but trust me, it isn't!"
 
NAME:Jerhyn
SPEED:117
//<Q1 
wave:act2\jerhyn\jer_act2_gossip_01.wav 
"Things are getting worse by the hour. I know everything looks fine, but trust me, it isn't!"

SPEED:63
wave:act2\jerhyn\jer_act2_gossip_02.wav 
"To any who aid me in the defense of Lut Gholein, I pledge my support. Passage East, wealth, honor - all are due to those who help my city."

SPEED:71
wave:act2\jerhyn\jer_act2_gossip_03.wav 
"You seem very capable, but no offense is intended when I say that I must choose my confidants carefully. It wouldn't do to have rumors sending everyone into a panic."

SPEED:87
wave:act2\jerhyn\jer_act2_gossip_04.wav 
"Even though he was once a bandit, I permitted Elzix to take over the Desert Rain Inn. He has been quite civilized ever since." 

SPEED:76
wave:act2\jerhyn\jer_act2_gossip_05.wav 
"When you arrived, Warriv's caravan had been long overdue. With all of the evil that's arisen in the land, I'm surprised he got through at all." 

SPEED:77
//<Q4
wave:act2\jerhyn\jer_act2_gossip_06.wav 
"Meshif is an honorable man, but I fear that he is growing impatient with me about impounding his ship. I dare not tell him what's really happening in this city." 

SPEED:98
wave:act2\jerhyn\jer_act2_gossip_07.wav 
"The woman, Atma, may have some useful gossip for you. She can always be found near her public house."

NAME:FaraIntro
SPEED:81
wave:act2\fara\far_act2_intro.wav 
"I know much about the ancient religions. I was trained as a Paladin of Zakarum in the Eastern Kurast temple many years ago."

NAME:FaraIntroPal
SPEED:103
wave:act2\fara\far_act2_intro_pal.wav 
"Welcome, brother Paladin.
 
I am Fara. I was once a devout champion of Zakarum."

NAME:Fara
SPEED:67
//The next gossip is only for a Paladin.
wave:act2\fara\far_act2_gossip_pal.wav
"Perhaps, in time, you will play a part in reclaiming our Order's honor and spirit. You are an inspiration to me, brother Paladin."

SPEED:60
wave:act2\fara\far_act2_gossip_01.wav 
"The shrines in the desert are leftover artifacts from the great Sin War that ravaged these lands almost a thousand years ago. They still function, but most travelers believe them only to be remnants of the distant past."

//<Q4
SPEED:54
wave:act2\fara\far_act2_gossip_02.wav 
"I've no love for brothels, as they can lead honorable men to do dishonorable things. Since the local harems took up hiding in the palace, however, there seems to be a rise in foul tempers."

SPEED:66
wave:act2\fara\far_act2_gossip_04.wav 
"When the Three Evils were bound ages ago, Mephisto, the Lord of Hatred, was moved to Kurast and bound by the holiest of magics."

SPEED:79
wave:act2\fara\far_act2_gossip_07.wav 
"Warriv may not remember me, but I helped him out when I was a young Paladin. There's no need for me to remind him. The rewards for honor will not come in this life." 

SPEED:68
wave:act2\fara\far_act2_gossip_08.wav 
"Greiz is a fine warrior and leader, but in his heart, he will always be a mercenary for hire. I cannot be loyal to those who have no loyalty to themselves." 

SPEED:90
wave:act2\fara\far_act2_gossip_09.wav 
"Atma is a good, loving woman. But I fear she will succumb to her despair and hatred."

SPEED:95
wave:act2\fara\far_act2_gossip_11.wav 
"Geglash is too confident in his abilities. A warrior's true strength is in his heart."

SPEED:94
wave:act2\fara\far_act2_gossip_12.wav 
"Meshif is an honest man as far as I can tell. He has never pestered me about my past." 

NAME:LysanderIntro
SPEED:61
wave:act2\lysander\lys_act2_intro.wav 
"How do I know I can trust you? Hmm?
 
You may be as shifty as that pack rat, Elzix, who runs the Inn. But, if you need a potion, though, I suppose I can make you one... for a price, of course."

NAME:Lysander
SPEED:109
wave:act2\lysander\lys_act2_gossip_01.wav 
"Potions are delicate mixtures. They're just as liable to go off in your face as anything."

SPEED:65
wave:act2\lysander\lys_act2_gossip_02.wav 
"Ah… The sweetest desert flower - that's Atma. Even my strongest brew can't bring back her family, though."

SPEED:86
wave:act2\lysander\lys_act2_gossip_03.wav 
"There are some ancient enchanted fountains in the desert that can heal your wounds - if you drink enough from them."

SPEED:71
wave:act2\lysander\lys_act2_gossip_04.wav 
"Oh. Deafness has its advantages, you know. I'm no longer forced to overhear the tedious gossip of others."

SPEED:54
wave:act2\lysander\lys_act2_gossip_05.wav 
"I never patronized the brothels, mind you. But since those ladies took up hiding in the palace, there certainly has been less scenery to feast my eyes on."

SPEED:95
wave:act2\lysander\lys_act2_gossip_06.wav 
"Oh… I have great faith in Greiz. He seems to have things well in hand."

SPEED:90
wave:act2\lysander\lys_act2_gossip_07.wav 
"I've traded my potions to Warriv many times. Yes. They seem to fetch a good price in the western lands." 

SPEED:71
wave:act2\lysander\lys_act2_gossip_09.wav 
"I've sold many sea-sickness potions to Meshif over the years. It seems that many of his passengers don't take well to the rocking of his ship on the open seas." 

SPEED:58
wave:act2\lysander\lys_act2_gossip_10.wav 
"Oh… Young Jerhyn used to purchase minor love potions from me, hoping to win the favors of the harem girls.
 
But now that the girls have taken up residence in the palace, he doesn't come around here anymore. Well, well… I've always said, 'alchemy is no substitute for experience'."

SPEED:57
wave:act2\lysander\lys_act2_gossip_11.wav 
"Drognan? Oh.. He's a good friend of mine. I help him find exotic spell components and alchemical books from time to time. I think he used to be a sorcerer of great renown, but he doesn't like to talk about his past."

NAME:DrognanIntro
SPEED:61
wave:act2\drognan\dro_act2_intro.wav 
"I've heard that you are responsible for banishing Andariel back to the Burning Hells. I'm impressed, stranger. That couldn't have been easy.
 
My name is Drognan and I know what you're up against, my friend.
 
You ought to look over my inventory of items for trade."

NAME:DrognanIntroSor
SPEED:50
wave:act2\drognan\dro_act2_intro_sor.wav 
"Welcome, young Sorceress, to Lut Gholein. I hope your skills are a match for the horrors that lie beyond the city's walls. A mage of your limited experience may find the evil too great to withstand alone.
 
My name is Drognan and I know what you're up against, my friend.
 
You ought to look over my inventory of items for trade."

NAME:Drognan
//The next gossip is only for a Sorceress.
SPEED:74
wave:act2\drognan\dro_act2_gossip_sor.wav 
"Many of the Mage Clans feel that women shouldn't practice magic openly. But since you've made it this far, I must say that you have proven your right to do so."

SPEED:57
wave:act2\drognan\dro_act2_gossip_01.wav 
"The Horadrim were a powerful Order, although maybe too prideful. Tal Rasha was one of their Order. And that should tell you something.
 
Any man who believes himself strong enough to contain one of the Prime Evils is in for a rude awakening, I should think."

SPEED:78
wave:act2\drognan\dro_act2_gossip_02.wav 
"I have heard of your friend, Cain. He is the last of the Horadrim. You would do well to heed whatever advice he has to give you."

//<Q5
SPEED:53
wave:act2\drognan\dro_act2_gossip_03.wav 
"Not long ago, one of my Vizjerei comrades, who I believed had died in Tristram, came to this city. He seemed quite insane, so I dismissed much of what he said.
 
However, he was able to talk his way into Jerhyn's palace. No one has seen him since. I fear that fool may have found something in the palace that led to his doom."

SPEED:68
wave:act2\drognan\dro_act2_gossip_04.wav 
"I've been practicing magic for more years than you could know. I'm older than I look, though not so old that I can't conjure up a few sparks."

SPEED:67
wave:act2\drognan\dro_act2_gossip_05.wav 
"Elzix is a sly one, I'll give him that. Of course, he never tries to cheat me. He knows what my magic skills can do."

SPEED:86
wave:act2\drognan\dro_act2_gossip_06.wav 
"Demons have spread throughout the desert wasteland and threaten to engulf our quiet port-city." 
 
//<Q6
SPEED:88
wave:act2\drognan\dro_act2_gossip_07.wav 
"Meshif and his vessel should remain here, lest we risk taking demonic stowaways to other lands."

//<Q4
SPEED:58
wave:act2\drognan\dro_act2_gossip_08.wav 
"When the recent troubles began, Lord Jerhyn came seeking my council. I advised him to close the port and put the town under strict watch.
 
Lately, though, he's been occupied within the palace. I doubt his whores could divert him from his civic duties for this long, though."

SPEED:68
wave:act2\drognan\dro_act2_gossip_09.wav 
"Lysander is harmless enough. We keep each other company with our mutual interests, yet I don't think he could handle the enormity of our present situation." 

NAME:CainAct2
SPEED:48
wave:act2\cain\cain_act2_gossip01.wav 
"Greetings, my friend. Have you spoken to Jerhyn yet? He's quite a remarkable leader for being such a young man. Then again, the old blood has always run strong in this land."

SPEED:71
wave:act2\cain\cain_act2_gossip02.wav 
"There is something about Fara that troubles me. Her manner is strange for a lonely desert-maid." 

SPEED:70
wave:act2\cain\cain_act2_gossip03.wav 
"Elzix is quite a scoundrel, but I like him all the same."

SPEED:59
wave:act2\cain\cain_act2_gossip04.wav 
"I talked at length with Warriv as we crossed the desert from Khanduras. He has many fascinating tales of the dangers in the desert. His experience may be useful to you."

SPEED:57
wave:act2\cain\cain_act2_gossip05.wav 
"Meshif is an interesting man. Part of him longs for the freedom of the open seas… Yet his heart belongs in his homeland."

NAME:Tyrael
SPEED:42
wave:act2\tyreal\tyr_act2_intro.wav
"I thank you, mortal, for my freedom. But I did expect you earlier.
 
I am the Archangel Tyrael. I came here to prevent Diablo from freeing his brother, Baal. But I have failed. Now, Terror and Destruction roam free throughout your world.
 
Even now, they head towards the Eastern capital of Kurast - to the very heart of the Zakarum Temple. There they hope to find their eldest brother, Mephisto, the Lord of Hatred who was imprisoned there ages ago.
 
If the three Prime Evils unite, they will be invincible. Though it is unclear as to what their aims are, it is certain that they must be stopped at all costs.
 
I am broken and the energies that tie me to this world are diminishing rapidly.
 
You must take up this quest and prevent the Three Brothers from reuniting. You must cross the sea and search for Diablo and Baal in Kurast.
 
Now hurry, mortal… Time is running out for all of us!"

NAME:Desert2Guard
SPEED:50
wave:act2\guard\gua_heyhero.wav
"Hey, hero! You're asking for trouble, if you leave town now."

SECTION:QUEST

//QUEST 2.1 Radament's Lair
QUEST:A2Q1
STATE:Init

NAME:Atma
SPEED:50
wave:act2\atma\atm_act2_q1_init.wav 
"I don't expect this of you, but if you want to help me, I would be grateful.
 
In the sewers below our city, there lurks a horrid creature that hungers for human flesh. The creature has killed many, including my son and my husband.
 
If you destroy it, I will reward you. Please be careful though, that beast has taken enough from us already.
 
The sewer entrance is through the trap door just up the street."

STATE:AfterInit

NAME:Greiz
SPEED:52
wave:act2\griez\gre_act2_q1_after.wav 
"I've personally found some of that devil's victims washed up out of the sewer. Often, they are missing limbs or a head, and their bodies have always been skinned.
 
At first the creature raided the town at night... That's how Atma lost her family. Now we've got him barricaded in the sewers.
 
You're safe up here on the surface, but every now and again some fool wants to be a hero and heads down to the waste tunnels with a pig-sticker."

NAME:Elzix
SPEED:68
wave:act2\elzix\elz_act2_q1_after.wav
"I hear that the creature kills his victims in order to hack off their limbs! I guess that makes me a less likely candidate, eh?"

Name:WarrivAct2
SPEED:84
wave:act2\warriv\war_act2_q1_after.wav 
"I've heard tales of walking corpses out in the desert at night, though I've never actually seen one."

NAME:Geglash
SPEED:77
wave:act2\geglash\geg_act2_q1_after.wav 
"Hey… Don't touch my drink or I'll bore a hole into your skull with my thumb."

NAME:Fara
SPEED:54
wave:act2\fara\far_act2_q1_after.wav 
"I believe that the creature you refer to is one of the ancient Horadric mummies from the tombs that lie buried beneath the desert sands. It is unusual for one of his kind to be so far away from his resting place. I sense in this entity a restless and malevolent spirit."

NAME:Atma
SPEED:62
wave:act2\atma\atm_act2_q1_after.wav 
"The creature makes its lair in the tunnels beneath this city. He butchered my husband and son... I simply cannot bear to talk about it..."

NAME:Meshif
SPEED:63
wave:act2\meshif\mes_act2_q1_after.wav 
"There are two entrances to the sewers, I believe. One of them is right near here, down by the water beneath the docks. I can see it from my ship, and you can bet I keep an eye on it every night."

NAME:Drognan
SPEED:53
wave:act2\drognan\dro_act2_q1_after.wav 
"Fara and I have been talking about the creature recently. From my studies, I have deduced that it is Radament the Fallen, an ancient Horadric mummy that has for some reason left his tomb to prey on mortals.
 
I'm doing some more research now. If you check back later, I may have some more insight as to his nature."

NAME:Lysander
SPEED:94
wave:act2\lysander\lys_act2_q1_after.wav
"I hear that beast is after body parts. Does he eat them? Oooh… Ghastly!"

NAME:Cain
SPEED:48
wave:act2\cain\cain_act2_q1_after.wav
"The Horadrim used to mummify their highest mages, and infuse them with spells that would allow them to protect their tombs, even after death.
 
I have no idea why one of them would be acting so malevolently. Perhaps Drognan or Fara would know more about this."

STATE:EarlyReturn

Name:WarrivAct2
SPEED:90
wave:act2\warriv\war_act2_q1_early.wav 
"Death is not afraid of the living, but the living abhor death."

NAME:Meshif
SPEED:55
wave:act2\meshif\mes_act2_q1_early.wav 
"I noticed a rotting, human arm floating in the harbor this morning. I suspected foul play, so I told Greiz. He didn't seem too concerned since there haven't been any folk reported missing lately."

NAME:Atma
SPEED:83
wave:act2\atma\atm_act2_q1_early.wav 
"I am starting to have second thoughts about my request... I couldn't bear the thought of you losing your life on my behalf.
 
Please be careful."

NAME:Greiz
SPEED:69
wave:act2\griez\gre_act2_q1_early.wav 
"We've been meaning to send an organized group down there to kill that thing, but it would be dangerous. We just can't afford the chance of losing any men with all the trouble that's going on in the desert."

NAME:Geglash
SPEED:65
wave:act2\geglash\geg_act2_q1_early.wav 
"Ah-hah! Back for a small shot of courage… Believe me, it doesn't help for long.
 
Drinks, barkeep!"

NAME:Elzix
SPEED:69
wave:act2\elzix\elz_act2_q1_early.wav 
"If you're going to fight that thing, use some common sense. Be knowledgeable about what harms the undead. Poison, for instance, will have little effect."

NAME:Lysander
SPEED:64
wave:act2\lysander\lys_act2_q1_early.wav 
"Huh? Peppermint? Oh, Radament! Yes, yes. Ooh, a foul creature...
 
Some of my exploding potions should do quite nicely against him. They usually work well against the undead."

NAME:Drognan
SPEED:49
wave:act2\drognan\dro_act2_q1_early.wav 
"I've just been reading something interesting about this sort of undead. Apparently, certain Horadric funereal priests altered the bodies of their dead mages with magical and surgical techniques -- often replacing body parts with those of animals.
 
This was thought to augment their powers, and raise their status in the afterlife."

NAME:Fara
SPEED:68
wave:act2\fara\far_act2_q1_early.wav 
"Drognan told me something interesting earlier today. It might explain why Radament is so restless, and it might have something to do with why he is stealing human body parts."

NAME:Cain
SPEED:41
wave:act2\cain\cain_act2_q1_early.wav 
"The Horadric mummies were created to protect the tombs, but Radament is far from his burial chamber. Given the aberrations that have been witnessed lately, it comes as no surprise that even the ancient guardian spells have begun to unravel. Be wary of this as you venture farther into the desert."

STATE:Successful

NAME:Greiz
SPEED:76
wave:act2\griez\gre_act2_q1_successful.wav 
"You've killed Radament, eh? That's quite a nice piece of work! If you ever need a job as a mercenary, I'd be happy to sign ya' up."

NAME:Drognan
SPEED:52
wave:act2\drognan\dro_act2_q1_successful.wav 
"From what you tell me, it would seem that Radament was bent on the task of reviving his own mummified corpse with the flesh of the living.
 
This is very unusual indeed. It takes an incredible magic power to alter the singular purpose of an undead mind.
 
Perhaps there is a power at work here which is beyond my ken."

NAME:Lysander
SPEED:61
wave:act2\lysander\lys_act2_q1_successful.wav
"Uh… Little of what I am able to hear is of any value. Radament's death, however, is news worth hearing. I'm sure Atma will be glad to hear of this."

NAME:Meshif
SPEED:62
wave:act2\meshif\mes_act2_q1_successful.wav 
"Good job mate! At night out on my ship, I was often awakened by that fiend's awful moaning. I bet I rest easier now."
 
NAME:Geglash
SPEED:41
wave:act2\geglash\geg_act2_q1_successful.wav 
"Whoah oh… 'Radament the Fallen', is it?
 
I've fallen off many a barstool and no one calls me 'Geglash the Fallen'. They might go so far as to say, 'Geglash, you've fallen!'"

NAME:Elzix
SPEED:70
wave:act2\elzix\elz_act2_q1_successful.wav 
"We ran into one of those old tomb guardians when I ran with my bandits. I know they aren't easy foes to face, so you sure have my respect. Have you told Atma yet?"

Name:WarrivAct2
SPEED:142
wave:act2\warriv\war_act2_q1_successful.wav 
"Atma's been telling everyone what you've done for her."

NAME:Fara
SPEED:102
wave:act2\fara\far_act2_q1_successful.wav 
"As you have helped Atma and all of us, so shall I help you."

NAME:Cain
SPEED:57
wave:act2\cain\cain_act2_q1_successful.wav 
"If you haven't already, tell Atma that Radament is dead. It may help to ease the weight of her mourning."

//changed 3/2/00
NAME:Atma
SPEED:50
wave:act2\atma\atm_act2_q1_successful.wav 
"They say that the taste of vengeance is bittersweet, but I find it to my liking. 
 
In addition to my undying gratitude, I have spoken on your behalf with the rest of the townspeople. The merchants have agreed to show their gratitude by offering their wares and services at lower rates.
 
Oh… Jerhyn wants to see you, too. You'll find him in front of the palace."


//QUEST 2.2 The Horadric Staff
QUEST:A2Q2
//STATE:Init 
//Initialized by picking up the Horadric Scroll in Radament's lair or either of the 2 parts (Viper Amulet or Staff of the Kings) or the Horadric Cube.

//STATE:AfterInit

STATE:EarlyReturnScroll
NAME:Cain
SPEED:37
wave:act2\cain\cain_act2_q2_earlyscroll.wav 
"Ahh… The lost Horadric Scroll! What a fortunate turn of events…
 
As the last living Horadrim, I alone have knowledge of its meaning. Now, to read the Horadric runes it bears. Hmmm…
 
The Horadric Mages, after binding Baal within Tal Rasha, magically sealed off his Burial Chamber from the mortal realm. Those same Mages also crafted fearsome Horadric Staves and imbued them with the special power to open the Chamber's hidden door.
 
After nearly losing one to the thievery of a rogue sorcerer, they divided all the Horadric Staves into two parts - wooden shaft and metal headpiece - hiding them separately to safeguard them.
 
The Horadrim foresaw our current plight and designed the hiding places to reveal themselves to worthy heroes like you.
 
Collect both parts of a Horadric Staff and unite them using a Horadric Cube. Then, you may enter Tal Rasha's Burial Chamber."


STATE:EarlyReturnCap
wave:act2\cain\cain_act2_q2_earlycap.wav 
NAME:Cain
SPEED:50
"The Viper Amulet you bear is actually the headpiece of a Horadric Staff!
 
Yes… You have an uncanny knack for finding rare and valuable artifacts. Of course, you'll have to use a Horadric Cube to combine the headpiece with the shaft."


STATE:EarlyReturnStave
NAME:Cain
SPEED:56
wave:act2\cain\cain_act2_q2_earlystave.wav 
"The Staff of Kings! You astound me, my friend. You have discovered the shaft portion of a Horadric Staff.
 
I trust you know how to use a Horadric Cube to unite the shaft with its headpiece."


//changed 4/25/00
STATE:EarlyReturnCube
NAME:Cain
SPEED:40
wave:act2\cain\cain_act2_q2_earlycube.wav 
"You have quite a treasure there in that Horadric Cube. According to Horadric lore, the Cube can restore a Horadric Staff.
 
To do it - use the Cube as you would a scroll. When the Cube opens, place both pieces of the Staff into it and use the Cube's transmute power.
 
You'll be pleased to know that the Cube has other alchemical uses as well…
 
Six gems plus one sword transmute into a socketed long sword.
 
You may also transmute two quivers of crossbow bolts into one quiver of arrows, while two quivers of arrows yield one quiver of bolts.
 
I must leave it to you to discover other formulae."


STATE:SuccessfulStaff
NAME:Cain
SPEED:46
wave:act2\cain\cain_act2_q2_successfulstaff.wav 
"Excellent! You have a Horadric Staff.
 
Carry it with you into Tal Rasha's Tomb. Find within the Tomb the chamber whose floor is inset with the Circle of Seven Symbols.
 
Place the Staff into the receptacle you find there. That will open the secret passage into Tal Rasha's Burial Chamber.
 
But, be prepared for a fight - you'll likely have to kill Tal Rasha to destroy Baal."


//QUEST 2.3 The Tainted Sun
QUEST:A2Q3
//STATE:Init 
//Initialized by random timer... after meeting level minimum or finishing Q1.
//Lighting drops to midnight level.

STATE:AfterInit

NAME:Jerhyn
SPEED:110
wave:act2\jerhyn\jer_act2_q3_after.wav 
"My astrologers failed to predict this eclipse. You should seek Drognan's advice."

NAME:Greiz
SPEED:71
wave:act2\griez\gre_act2_q3_after.wav 
"This midday darkness reeks of foul magic! My men and I are trying to keep the peace, but this kind of thing really scares people."

NAME:Elzix
SPEED:65
wave:act2\elzix\elz_act2_q3_after.wav 
"Two men arrived late last night bearing a story about evil magic. They said they saw a gathering of giant snake creatures performing some arcane ritual. They sound like the Serpent Men of the desert."

Name:WarrivAct2
SPEED:72
wave:act2\warriv\war_act2_q3_after.wav 
"The sun has grown disgusted with the terrible deeds it must shine upon each day. Damnation is upon us all."

NAME:Atma
SPEED:121
wave:act2\atma\atm_act2_q3_after.wav 
"Drognan, the wizard, will have some idea as to what is happening."

NAME:Geglash
SPEED:100
wave:act2\geglash\geg_act2_q3_after.wav 
"This whole place is one big ale fog."

NAME:Fara
SPEED:70
wave:act2\fara\far_act2_q3_after.wav 
"This unnatural nightfall is no doubt caused by evil sorcery. Drognan might know what we are dealing with."

NAME:Lysander
SPEED:65
wave:act2\lysander\lys_act2_q3_after.wav
"Claw Vipers! This outer darkness mirrors the inner blackness of their souls. It is they who have eclipsed the sun, I'll wager. They are a venomous band."

NAME:Drognan
SPEED:77
wave:act2\drognan\dro_act2_q3_after.wav 
"I've been researching this lengthy eclipse and I believe it to be the work of Claw Vipers.
 
Find their temple beneath the desert sands and you may find the source of this curse."

NAME:Meshif
SPEED:76
wave:act2\meshif\mes_act2_q3_after.wav 
"This permanent darkness is very unsettling. Hmmm… It would make navigation by stars easier for me, though."

NAME:Cain
SPEED:62
wave:act2\cain\cain_act2_q3_after.wav 
"Drognan may have some advice on this matter. Hmm… I think I'll speak with him myself."

STATE:EarlyReturn

NAME:Jerhyn
SPEED:130
wave:act2\jerhyn\jer_act2_q3_early.wav 
"This eclipse is a definite manifestation of evil."

NAME:Greiz
SPEED:73
wave:act2\griez\gre_act2_q3_early.wav
"Don't worry! My men and I have an iron grip on this town. If those cursed Claw Vipers are plotting anything against us, we'll be prepared for 'em."

Name:WarrivAct2
SPEED:73
wave:act2\warriv\war_act2_q3_early.wav 
"The calculated coldness of the reptilian brain makes the Claw Vipers uncanny adversaries."

NAME:Geglash
SPEED:49
wave:act2\geglash\geg_act2_q3_early.wav 
"It's strange when the morning after the night before… is still the same night."

NAME:Meshif
SPEED:105
wave:act2\meshif\mes_act2_q3_early.wav 
"I've had about enough of this darkness. I don't even know what day it is anymore."

NAME:Fara
SPEED:77
wave:act2\fara\far_act2_q3_early.wav 
"The Claw Vipers practice evil magic. They have also been known to kidnap travelers and sacrifice them to their dark gods."

NAME:Lysander
SPEED:82
wave:act2\lysander\lys_act2_q3_early.wav 
"Well… I don't know much about the habits of Claw Vipers, to be honest. Drognan will probably know something about the nature of the magic at work."

NAME:Drognan
SPEED:51
wave:act2\drognan\dro_act2_q3_early.wav 
"I've discovered a reference to a similar eclipse several hundred years ago. It says that some desert-dwelling snake demons had erected an evil altar, which caused the sun to go black.
 
Perhaps we are dealing with something similar here. Look for an altar in the Claw Viper temple."

NAME:Elzix
SPEED:94
wave:act2\elzix\elz_act2_q3_early.wav
"I usually charge for rooms by the night.
 
But I may have to soon change that."

NAME:Cain
SPEED:57
wave:act2\cain\cain_act2_q3_early.wav 
"The source of this spell is probably a magical altar. It will not be enough to kill the Claw Vipers. To reverse the spell you must destroy the altar."

NAME:Atma
SPEED:80
wave:act2\atma\atm_act2_q3_early.wav 
"I was going to go to bed, but then I realized that I have no idea what time it is. It could be the crack of dawn, for all I know."

STATE:Successful

NAME:Jerhyn
SPEED:96
wave:act2\jerhyn\jer_act2_q3_successful.wav 
"The sun again shines on Lut Gholein! I'm beginning to like you, traveler."

NAME:Greiz
SPEED:219
wave:act2\griez\gre_act2_q3_successful.wav 
"I'm glad that's over with!"

NAME:Elzix
SPEED:74
wave:act2\elzix\elz_act2_q3_successful.wav 
"Ahh… It takes but one eye to revel in the beauty of our restored sun."

NAME:Geglash
SPEED:60
wave:act2\geglash\geg_act2_q3_successful.wav 
"So, this is daylight… It's over-rated."

Name:WarrivAct2
SPEED:80
wave:act2\warriv\war_act2_q3_successful.wav 
"With renewed daylight, one may gather the wits that were scattered about like restrictive undergarments in the darkness."

NAME:Meshif
SPEED:130
wave:act2\meshif\mes_act2_q3_successful.wav 
"So... Did you plunder any booty?"

NAME:Atma
SPEED:132
wave:act2\atma\atm_act2_q3_successful.wav
"You have done well to restore light to our world."

NAME:Fara
SPEED:87
wave:act2\fara\far_act2_q3_successful.wav 
"Drognan seems to have taken you into his confidence. This is good, for you will benefit from his wisdom."

NAME:Lysander
SPEED:69
wave:act2\lysander\lys_act2_q3_successful.wav
"Ahhh… Claw Vipers are fond of magical artifacts. Did you happen to find one in their temple?"

NAME:Drognan
SPEED:69
wave:act2\drognan\dro_act2_q3_successful.wav 
"You did well in destroying the Claw Vipers. We are all glad to see the sun returned to its former glory."

NAME:Cain
SPEED:48
wave:act2\cain\cain_act2_q3_successful.wav 
"I've been speaking with Lord Jerhyn, and I sense that he is becoming more and more agitated by something. You should try to talk to him again.
 
If he still won't take you into his confidence, seek to prove yourself a bit more. I gather that his respect for you is growing."

//QUEST 2.4 The Arcane Sanctuary
QUEST:A2Q4
STATE:Init

NAME:Drognan
SPEED:41
wave:act2\drognan\dro_act2_q4_init.wav
"I've been researching the old records, trying to find the location of Tal Rasha's Tomb. Though I haven't found the Tomb, itself, I may have a good lead for you.
 
The great Vizjerei Summoner, Horazon, built his Arcane Sanctuary somewhere around here. He was a powerful spellcaster and kept demons as slaves within the Sanctuary. He kept a close eye on great events, too -- such as the imprisonment of Baal within Tal Rasha's Tomb.
 
If you could find Horazon's Sanctuary, I'm sure that it would hold some clue as to the Tomb's location. Though I doubt Horazon is still alive, you must proceed with caution. There's no telling what could be waiting inside.
 
When I spoke of this with Lord Jerhyn, he asked that I send you to him. Perhaps he knows of a secret entrance or the like."

STATE:AfterInit
 
NAME:Fara
SPEED:46
wave:act2\fara\far_act2_q4_after.wav 
"Ah, the ancient mage Horazon! He believed that he could bend Evil forces to his will. What he didn't know was that Evil uses man, not the reverse.
 
The Vizjerei still revere him as a symbol of man's ability to triumph over other worldly forces. The Church of Light, however, cites him as an example of man's folly."

NAME:Greiz
SPEED:89
wave:act2\griez\gre_act2_q4_after.wav 
"The only thing in Jerhyn's cellar are the harem girls that have been hiding there since the troubles began."

NAME:Elzix
SPEED:62
wave:act2\elzix\elz_act2_q4_after.wav 
"An 'Arcane Sanctuary' under the palace? I'd heard that there were some underground cellar levels that Jerhyn used as chambers for his treasure and such, but no Arcane Sanctuary."
 
NAME:Jerhyn
SPEED:44
wave:act2\jerhyn\jer_act2_q4_after.wav 
"When the troubles began here, I allowed the terrified Harem guilds to join me within the safety of the palace. All was fine, until one night…
 
Screams echoed up the stairwells from the harem. My guards arrived to find the poor girls being slaughtered by a merciless band of hell-spawned demons. My brave guardsmen tried to push the demons back into the mysterious rift from which they came.
 
Ever since, my men have fought a losing battle. Demons have continued to pour through the rift into the palace. Ultimately, I hired Greiz and his mercenaries to help protect the rest of my fair city.
 
Drognan believes that the Arcane Sanctuary lies buried underneath this palace, since Lut Gholein occupies the site of an ancient Vizjerei fortress.
 
My palace is open to you now… Take care."

NAME:Cain
SPEED:45
wave:act2\cain\cain_act2_q4_after.wav 
"I very much doubt that Horazon still lives in his Sanctuary. He possessed great power and influence over demons, but even that may not have been enough in the end. One of his notoriety cannot easily remove himself from the vengeful reach of Hell."

NAME:Geglash
SPEED:60
wave:act2\geglash\geg_act2_q4_after.wav 
"Look, look… I'm just about as tough and arrogant as they come, but you'd never catch me trying to tame a demon for a pet. That's just asking for a lot of trouble."

NAME:Atma
SPEED:75
wave:act2\atma\atm_act2_q4_after.wav
"Arcane Sanctuary? That place sounds awful! Even if you find a way into it, what makes you think you'll be able to leave again?"

Name:WarrivAct2
SPEED:73
wave:act2\warriv\war_act2_q4_after.wav 
"A careful caravan gives wide berth to sleeping bandits. If Horazon is gone, let him remain so."

NAME:Lysander
SPEED:49
wave:act2\lysander\lys_act2_q4_after.wav
"Horazon found it necessary to lock himself up for all time, just to protect himself from those angry demons. Such is the fate of one who practices the summoning arts... that, or eternal damnation. There's old summoners and bold summoners, but no old, bold summoners."

NAME:Drognan
SPEED:42
wave:act2\drognan\dro_act2_q4_after.wav 
"Nearly a thousand years ago, Horazon rose to the fore of the Vizjerei mage clan. Horazon used the knowledge of the Vizjerei to summon and control demons from Hell.
 
Though a powerful Summoner, Horazon feared that the Lords of Hell would punish him for enslaving their brethren. Thus, the Summoner created for himself an Arcane Sanctuary.
 
He believed that his Sanctuary would not only protect him from Hell's vengeance, but also allow him to continue his studies free from the ravages of time and disease.
 
Horazon had crafted many wondrous scrying devices through which he observed the events of the world outside. It is certain that he took careful study of Tal Rasha's imprisonment and recorded the location of his forgotten Tomb.
 
The Arcane Sanctuary was believed to have been constructed here in Lut Gholein. An entrance may be hidden somewhere in the palace, as that building is very old, and was once a Vizjerei fortress." 

NAME:Meshif
SPEED:57
wave:act2\meshif\mes_act2_q4_after.wav 
"Ahh… The legend of Horazon is an old one, especially around these parts. You wouldn't believe the feats and strange events that are attributed to him."

STATE:EarlyReturn

NAME:Elzix
SPEED:63
wave:act2\elzix\elz_act2_q4_early.wav 
"I understand that you've been talking to Jerhyn. Well, if so, then you're the first in a long while... since the trouble began, actually.
 
Do us a favor and try to find out what's got Jerhyn so edgy all the time. OK?"

NAME:Jerhyn
SPEED:48
wave:act2\jerhyn\jer_act2_q4_early.wav
"There was an eastern mage... a Vizjerei, I believe... who visited me almost a year ago. He was very interested in the history of this site, and he seemed particularly fascinated with the palace architecture.
 
I gave him a tour. When he found the ancient seals over a passageway in the cellar, he became very agitated. He asked for some time alone to study them, and I granted it.
 
Shortly after, he left with no further word and I never saw him again. Odd… Don't you think?"

NAME:Greiz
SPEED:61
wave:act2\griez\gre_act2_q4_early.wav 
"What's got you so occupied in the palace? Don't tell me you're finding the Harems more compelling than killing demons? That would be out of character for one such as yourself."

NAME:Drognan
SPEED:63
wave:act2\drognan\dro_act2_q4_early.wav 
"I am certain that you will find the information you need when you find Horazon's Journal. I suggest you find it quickly, for Diablo may be getting closer to freeing his brother as we speak."

NAME:Lysander
SPEED:68
wave:act2\lysander\lys_act2_q4_after.wav 
"Huh? The horizon is always out of reach, you should know that. Oh, Horazon! Oh, I see. Uh.
 
Yes. Well. He was insane. Brilliant, yes, but… total lunatic."

NAME:Fara
SPEED:57
wave:act2\fara\far_act2_q4_early.wav 
"Even a sanctuary such as Horazon's can be breached by the tentacles of Evil. Such a haven could have become a chamber of unspeakable horrors. Be wary of what you may unleash!"

NAME:Geglash
SPEED:49
wave:act2\geglash\geg_act2_q4_early.wav 
"All my years of brawling, of pummeling both the unsuspecting and the deserving, have yielded two insights. You can either fight or you can run. All other strategies are variations of these."

NAME:Meshif
SPEED:77
wave:act2\meshif\mes_act2_q4_early.wav 
"So… Now that you're such a pal of Jerhyn, why don't you ask him if I can set sail one of these days? I'm running out of patience."

NAME:Atma
SPEED:87
wave:act2\atma\atm_act2_q4_early.wav 
"So you've been in the palace, have you? Tell me, why does Jerhyn keep that place locked up so tight?"

NAME:WarrivAct2
SPEED:87
wave:act2\warriv\war_act2_q4_early.wav 
"Fate is like a caged gorilla. It will pelt you with dung if you mock it."

NAME:Cain
SPEED:51
wave:act2\cain\cain_act2_q4_early.wav 
"I've been thinking about the problems in Jerhyn's palace. Perhaps this has occurred to you as well...
 
If those cellar passageways lead to the Arcane Sanctuary, then that is where the demons came from. Horazon's haven must have been breached!"

STATE:Successful

// Excerpt from the Journal of Horazón: (played when the player opens the journal)
//Note: "great Tyrael's" below to be read with sarcasm

NAME:Narrator
SPEED:37
wave:act2\narrator\nar_act2_q4_successful_journal.wav
"Seekers of the Tomb of Tal Rasha will find it through the Portal. But know that the glowing glyphs recorded here in my Arcane Sanctuary are the signs of the six False Tombs.
 
The missing Seventh Sign marks the Tomb of Tal Rasha… Of the Horadrim he might be called the foremost.
 
It was a shining - but brief - moment for the Mage Clans when they set aside their differences and worked together against the common enemy.
 
The Horadrim relentlessly pursued the Three across the desolate Empires of the East, and even into the uncharted lands of the West, leaving the Archangel Tyrael's hands unblemished.
 
Presuming the Three to be vanquished, the Horadrim's unstable fellowship began to dissipate. Abandoning their sacred charge to safeguard the three Soulstones, the disparate Mage Clans began to squabble amongst each other over petty differences.
 
Their conflicts not only dissolved their brotherhood, but strengthened the Evils which they had buried beneath the cold earth."

NAME:Griez
SPEED:59
wave:act2\griez\gre_act2_q4_successful.wav
"Unbelievable! The Harem girls are dead! The palace guards have been fighting off demons from the cellar. How could that happen without my knowledge?"

NAME:Jerhyn
SPEED:62
wave:act2\jerhyn\jer_act2_q4_successful.wav 
"I thank you for your heroic aid! I'm also glad that you found something you were looking for. The journal should help you find the True Tomb of Tal Rasha. Hopefully, there is still time to get there before Diablo.
 
Go now. And good luck."

NAME:Drognan
SPEED:55
wave:act2\drognan\dro_act2_q4_successful.wav 
"You have found Horazon's Journal. Excellent… But, I must caution you.
 
The mark of the True Tomb of Tal Rasha, is sought, if not already known, by Diablo. I needn't elaborate on the implications of that."

NAME:Elzix
SPEED:71
wave:act2\elzix\elz_act2_q4_successful.wav 
"News of the tragedy in the palace is spreading fast. How awful! And to think, this whole time I thought Jerhyn and his guards were in there playing with the harem girls."

NAME:Geglash
SPEED:60
wave:act2\geglash\geg_act2_q4_successful.wav 
"Hah! I wish Jerhyn would've let me in the palace. I would've saved those girls and kicked demon ass back to the fire-pits o' Hell!"

NAME:Meshif
SPEED:52
wave:act2\meshif\mes_act2_q4_successful.wav 
"So… Now we know Jerhyn's little secret. Well… I guess I can see why he wanted me to stay, though... I'm just glad it didn't come to that. Now he tells me to wait some more, in case you need to get out of here.
 
Well, for you I'll do it. Maybe they'll mention me in the epic ballads, eh?"

NAME:WarrivAct2
SPEED:67
wave:act2\warriv\war_act2_q4_successful.wav 
"Well, the news going around town is very unsettling. Apparently, we were in more danger than anyone thought.
 
Good work friend... you may have saved all our skins."

NAME:Fara
SPEED:64
wave:act2\fara\far_act2_q4_successful.wav 
"Faith is stronger than any armor. The shield will protect the body, but Faith will strengthen the courageous heart."
 
NAME:Lysander
SPEED:55
wave:act2\lysander\lys_act2_q4_successful.wav 
"Horazon's urinal? Oh, journal! Yes, well... Glad you found it. Such a shame about those poor harem girls, huh? I shall miss them deeply... I mean their conversations, of course."

NAME:Atma
SPEED:62
wave:act2\atma\atm_act2_q4_successful.wav 
"Oh, those poor women! Will the slaughter never end? Thank you once again for protecting our city."

NAME:Cain
SPEED:57
wave:act2\cain\cain_act2_q4_successful.wav 
"You must move quickly now, friend, for Diablo is undoubtedly close to finding what he seeks. Find the Tomb of Tal Rasha before he frees the Lord of Destruction."

//QUEST 2.5 The Summoner
QUEST:A2Q5
//STATE:Init
//Encountering the Summoner. The player hears his raving taunts from a distance.

//STATE:AfterInit

STATE:EarlyReturn

NAME:Greiz
SPEED:89
wave:act2\griez\gre_act2_q5_early.wav 
"That guy really talks like that? Sounds like either Horazon has gone stir-crazy or that's some impostor."

NAME:Jerhyn
SPEED:57
wave:act2\jerhyn\jer_act2_q5_early.wav 
"The man you describe is probably not Horazon.
 
He sounds like the very mage who came around here a while ago. He was very curious about this palace and seemed especially interested in the seal on the passageway in the cellar. He left shortly after that. I wonder how he got down there? The seal was never broken...
 
That mage spoke a great deal to Drognan. Why don't you ask him about it?"

NAME:Drognan
SPEED:47
wave:act2\drognan\dro_act2_q5_early.wav 
"Yes… The man you speak of sounds like the mage who came here many months ago. He claimed to have fought Diablo in the passages beneath Tristram.
 
No doubt the fool wandered into Horazon's Sanctuary and lost whatever was left of his ravaged mind. He is beyond salvation. 
 
It is possible that the fool has been possessed by the spirit of Horazon. If that's true, then you'd better put an end to his tortured existence.
 
Once done, I believe the demons who were summoned and imprisoned within the Sanctuary will cease to exist as well."

NAME:Lysander
SPEED:57
wave:act2\lysander\lys_act2_q5_early.wav 
"Ah, yes. I remember. There was a… fellow around here many months ago who asked almost as many questions about Horazon as you.
 
So… He discovered enough to assume Horazon's place in the Arcane Sanctuary, huh? What a fool!"

NAME:Meshif
SPEED:72
wave:act2\meshif\mes_act2_q5_early.wav 
"Ah, yes. As a ship captain I am well aware of the phenomenon of a false Horazon.
 
Sorry, just a little joke."

Name:WarrivAct2
SPEED:99
wave:act2\warriv\war_act2_q5_early.wav 
"There's nothing more dreadful than a powerful being driven by a frayed mind."

NAME:Atma
SPEED:105
wave:act2\atma\atm_act2_q5_early.wav 
"You always seem to find the worst trouble. I don't know how you handle it."

NAME:Geglash
SPEED:38
wave:act2\geglash\geg_act2_q5_early.wav 
"So! Horazon's crazy, eh? I'd be surprised if he wasn't. All those centuries without ale would drive anyone to drink... but then you couldn't drink. And that would drive you to drink... Hah?... What was the question?"

NAME:Fara
SPEED:63
wave:act2\fara\far_act2_q5_early.wav 
"Hmmm... That doesn't sound like Horazon. I'll agree that he may have gone mad, but from what you tell me, I don't think that's the case. Talk to Drognan... he may know more than I."

NAME:Elzix
SPEED:106
wave:act2\elzix\elz_act2_q5_early.wav 
"Ugh… Crazy mages give me the creeps.
 
Just kill him and get on with your business."

NAME:Cain
SPEED:45
wave:act2\cain\cain_act2_q5_early.wav 
"The appearance of the mage you describe sounds like one I met back in Tristram. Many Vizjerei came to fight against Diablo, the Lord of Terror. Perhaps, this is one of them.
 
You know, fate seems to have frowned upon all of the heroes who confronted that terrible Evil. Take care or the same may happen to you."

STATE:Successful

NAME:Greiz
SPEED:76
wave:act2\griez\gre_act2_q5_successful.wav 
"So, Horazon's been dead for some time. I take it you at least found what you were looking for."

NAME:Geglash
SPEED:60
wave:act2\geglash\geg_act2_q5_successful.wav 
"The way I see it... Well, it's all pretty blurry."

NAME:Jerhyn
SPEED:63
wave:act2\jerhyn\jer_act2_q5_successful.wav 
"The demonic force that was emanating from the corrupted Sanctuary has dissipated. I thank you greatly for your help. Now, we can look to rebuilding our lives.
 
All will be for nothing, though, if you do not stop the greater Evil which is rapidly gaining ground."

NAME:Drognan
SPEED:83
wave:act2\drognan\dro_act2_q5_successful.wav
"Larger forces are moving inexorably towards us. You must now make haste to the Tombs."

NAME:Elzix
SPEED:65
wave:act2\elzix\elz_act2_q5_successful.wav 
"You make me long for the days of glory. When I had both hands, both eyes and more of a foot..."

Name:WarrivAct2
SPEED:84
wave:act2\warriv\war_act2_q5_successful.wav 
"I guess you'll be heading to the Tombs now? I hear that they're in the deepest desert regions."

NAME:Meshif
SPEED:100
wave:act2\meshif\mes_act2_q5_successful.wav 
"Well! You've got what you're after. Now get a move on before it's too late."

NAME:Lysander
SPEED:103
wave:act2\lysander\lys_act2_q5_successful.wav 
"Huhhh… Such is always the fate of those who meddle with evil."

NAME:Atma
SPEED:89
wave:act2\atma\atm_act2_q5_successful.wav 
"You're more the hero than I could have dreamed. Perhaps, there is hope for us after all."

NAME:Fara
SPEED:74
wave:act2\fara\far_act2_q5_successful.wav 
"I feel no pity for that would-be Summoner. His terrible ambition for demonic power was his undoing. You merely hastened the inevitable."

NAME:Cain
SPEED:48
wave:act2\cain\cain_act2_q5_successful.wav 
"I hope that this false Summoner found peace in death. Unfortunately, it is more likely that he will be dragged down into Hell by the demons he was bound to.
 
Let this be a lesson to you... Demonic magic is a quick path, but its powers are seductive and deadly."


//QUEST 2.6 The Seven Tombs
QUEST:A2Q6
STATE:Init

NAME:Jerhyn
SPEED:45
wave:act2\jerhyn\jer_act2_q6_init.wav 
"I have heard of your many deeds of skill and bravery. I feel I can trust you with something I have been hesitant to speak of…
 
Drognan and I have concluded that the Dark Wanderer who passed through here recently was Diablo, himself! Drognan believes that Diablo is searching the desert for the secret tomb where the great Horadric mage, Tal Rasha, keeps Baal imprisoned.
 
You must find Diablo and put an end to the terrible evil that has fallen upon our city. Drognan is wise and is sure to have some helpful advice for you as to how Tal Rasha's tomb may be found.
 
It may take you quite some time to find The Tomb. May you be ready when you do."

STATE:AfterInit

NAME:Jerhyn
SPEED:53
wave:act2\jerhyn\jer_act2_q6_after.wav
"It is well-known that there are seven great Horadric tombs hidden beneath the sands in the furthest reaches of the desert. One of them surely must be Tal Rasha's prison. You must explore each of the tombs to find Tal Rasha's exact location.
 
Of course, Diablo is searching for the Tomb as well… No one can guess as to what terrors he has unleashed in his search."

NAME:Elzix
SPEED:59
wave:act2\elzix\elz_act2_q6_after.wav 
"So… You're going to search for the Seven Tombs, huh? Don't you know that they're just desert legends passed between merchants and travelers? No one really believes that they exist." 

Name:WarrivAct2
SPEED:61
wave:act2\warriv\war_act2_q6_after.wav 
"Be very careful, my friend. I think I've seen enough recently not to doubt that these Tombs exist. And if they do, they're most certainly guarded by terrible creatures."

NAME:Atma
SPEED:67
wave:act2\atma\atm_act2_q6_after.wav 
"I've heard legends of the Tomb of Tal Rasha, but I thought they were just old tales meant to scare young children."

NAME:Geglash
SPEED:59
wave:act2\geglash\geg_act2_q6_after.wav 
"Ohh… I'd go with ya' to those tombs... But… umm… I don't like all that living dead stuff."

NAME:Meshif
SPEED:84
wave:act2\meshif\mes_act2_q6_after.wav 
"I'm sorry, I can't help you much here. Now, if the tombs were across the ocean, then I'd be the guy to talk to."

NAME:Fara
SPEED:57
wave:act2\fara\far_act2_q6_after.wav 
"Legend has it that Tal Rasha lies imprisoned within his tomb, forever struggling to keep the Lord of Destruction bound. His was a selfless act, although perhaps foolhardy."

NAME:Lysander
SPEED:56
wave:act2\lysander\lys_act2_q6_after.wav 
"When Tal Rasha chose to embody the spirit of Baal, he knew his doom was to wrestle eternally against the will of the greater Evil. Look around you and ask yourself, 'Has the battle been won or lost?'"

NAME:Drognan
SPEED:55
wave:act2\drognan\dro_act2_q6_after.wav 
"Tal Rasha's tomb is hidden deep in the desert among six others. Tal Rasha's symbol marks the True Tomb. If you want to know what that symbol is, you should be able to find it within the legendary Arcane Sanctuary."

NAME:Cain
SPEED:57
wave:act2\cain\cain_act2_q6_after.wav 
"Diablo nears his goal. We have little time to lose.
 
Remember, my friend, that Andariel gave herself willingly to Diablo's cause. It would be prudent to assume that the other Evils will attempt to aid their master as well."

NAME:Greiz
SPEED:106
wave:act2\griez\gre_act2_q6_after.wav
"If you're going into the deep desert, why not hire a few of my men to watch your back?"

//STATE:EarlyReturn

STATE:Successful

NAME:Jerhyn
SPEED:47
wave:act2\jerhyn\jer_act2_q6_successful.wav 
"You have done very well. Few could have come this far, let alone discover the True Tomb of Tal Rasha. Unfortunately, I hear that Diablo and Baal have eluded your grasp. This is most unfortunate...
 
If you wish to travel East, I have authorized Meshif to give you passage by sea. I imagine he should be very anxious to leave by now.
 
Good luck on your quest, and thank you again for saving my beloved city. You will always be welcome in Lut Gholein, my friend."

NAME:Elzix
SPEED:71
wave:act2\elzix\elz_act2_q6_successful.wav
"I heard that Diablo has managed to best you, at least for the time being. I hope you catch up with him soon, and send him back to Hell for good!"

NAME:Lysander
SPEED:70
wave:act2\lysander\lys_act2_q6_successful.wav 
"I'm sorry things didn't turn out as you had hoped. Go and remember us fondly. You know, you bothered me far less than most."

NAME:Atma
SPEED:64
wave:act2\atma\atm_act2_q6_successful.wav
"You have proven to be the greatest of heroes, and I am honored to call you friend. Thank you for bringing peace to our lives again."

Name:WarrivAct2
SPEED:68
wave:act2\warriv\war_act2_q6_successful.wav 
"Never fear, my friend. You did the best you could.
 
I suspect that Diablo and Baal are now heading east, towards Kurast. You'll find them… I know you will."

NAME:Fara
SPEED:46
wave:act2\fara\far_act2_q6_successful.wav 
"This is terrible news! Baal is in possession of one of mankind's most powerful mages, and the Lord of Terror guides his path. They must be stopped, for I am sure they mean to free their elder brother Mephisto, the Lord of Hatred, who lies imprisoned under the corrupted city of Kurast.
 
I fear you are walking into a great evil, but your faith can save you. May you walk in the light always."

NAME:Geglash
SPEED:54
wave:act2\geglash\geg_act2_q6_successful.wav 
"You're an inspiration! And such a hero that it makes me look twice as bad…
 
Ahh, you're OK... Hey! Just save some glory for us little guys, huh?"

NAME:Drognan
SPEED:51
wave:act2\drognan\dro_act2_q6_successful.wav 
"This is a serious setback... It is most unfortunate that Tal Rasha has been consumed by Baal's destructive influence. There are many secrets known to the Horadrim, which could be used by Baal against us.
 
You must travel east by sea to Kurast and stop Diablo and Baal before they free their eldest brother, Mephisto.
 
Hahh… The lands of the eastern Empire are not the same as they used to be. There has been little word for some time.
 
Speed is of the essence. Go quickly, my friend. May the fates smile on you."

NAME:Meshif
SPEED:82
wave:act2\meshif\mes_act2_q6_successful.wav 
"Jerhyn tells me I should take you east to Kurast. I haven't been there for several years, but rumor has it that things are pretty grim."

NAME:Greiz
SPEED:51
wave:act2\griez\gre_act2_q6_successful.wav 
"I've heard that your foe got away from you this time. Well, look at it this way... you've got the demons on the run. If you're going to be leaving, then… Well, thanks for your help."

NAME:Cain
SPEED:39
wave:act2\cain\cain_act2_q6_successful.wav 
"The Archangel Tyrael was the one who gave the Soulstones to the Horadrim two hundred and sixty years ago.
 
It is highly unusual for the forces of Heaven to so directly interfere with man's destiny, but Tyrael was said to act of his own volition. We have never been able to discern why.
 
Perhaps, he goes against the consensus of Heaven because he doubts our ability to defend ourselves, or perhaps, he sees more threat than his peers.
 
Where the actions of Hell often seem straightforwardly bent on destruction, the motives of Heaven are unfathomable.
 
Now make haste... Both Diablo and Baal must be stopped before they join with their brother, Mephisto. If the three Prime Evils unite once again, the world as we know it will be no more."
//end
1


23


