"Your connection has been interrupted", gamefailserverdrop.dc6
"The Host of this game has left", selfresurrect.dc6
"Unable to enter game. A dead hardcore character cannot join or create any games.", gamefailillegaljoinA.dc6
"Unable to enter game. A hardcore character cannot join a game created by a normal character.", gamefailillegaljoinB.dc6
"Unable to enter game. A normal character cannot join a game created by a hardcore character.", gamefailillegaljoinC.dc6
"Unable to enter game. Your character must kill Diablo to play in a Nightmare game.", gamefailillegaljoinD.dc6
"Unable to enter game. Your character must kill Diablo in Nightmare difficulty to play in a Hell game.", gamefailillegaljoinE.dc6 
"Versions do not match. Please log onto battle.net or go to http://www.blizzard.com/support/Diablo2/ to download a patch", gameversionmismatch.dc6
